<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mental-Health on Yuvi</title>
    <link>https://words.yuvi.in/tags/mental-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mental-Health on Yuvi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 20:56:40 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://words.yuvi.in/tags/mental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ADHD and Me</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/adhd-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 20:56:40 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/adhd-and-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-write-this&#34;&gt;Why write this?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This August / September, I had a lot of life changes in one go:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Moving from an apartment i disliked to one I absolutely love, and maybe even feel at home in, for the first time in my life&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Officially switch jobs, becoming an employee of a non-profit I had co-founded&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Catch COVID for the first time and recover from it, with appropriate MH breakdowns from the isolation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Get on &lt;a href=&#34;https://medlineplus.gov/druginfo/meds/a601059.html&#34;&gt;Guanfacine&lt;/a&gt; as a non-stimulant medication for ADHD&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I can not fully separate the effects of these changes, the overall effect has been very good for me. The ADHD meds form an important and specific component, and I think I am primarily writing this to understand what that is. Many years ago, I had started on bipolar 2 meds and anti anxiety meds at the same time, and attributed some positive changes to the bipolar 2 meds that were not true - it was almost exclusively the anti anxiety meds. This contributed to me living with a misdiagnosis for many years, and taking meds I just didn&amp;rsquo;t need. So I don’t want to unconditionally say all the good positives in my life are from this, but recognize that &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; are, especially this time we did not mix it with another pharmacological intervention. Writing it down now should also allow me to come back to it a year or two later to see how that has evolved&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
