<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>personal on Yuvi</title>
    <link>https://words.yuvi.in/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in personal on Yuvi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 10:49:48 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://words.yuvi.in/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Something that seems to drive me: Part I</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 10:49:48 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/drive/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a bit of a slump the last few months, working through what feels like deep mental fog for totally unclear reasons. The lack of clarity on causation is one of the most frustrating parts of this, and one of the most familiar too - this isn&amp;rsquo;t the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve felt like this, and I know (rationally at least, if not emotionally) it won&amp;rsquo;t be the last. Probably a combination of intensely avoiding making some decision that seems too big to be made by me without actually knowing what it is and fun brain chemicals stuff.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2017</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 16:29:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/2017/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t done a &amp;lsquo;year in retrospective&amp;rsquo; publicly for a long time, but after reading Alice Goldfuss&amp;rsquo; 2017 year in review decided to do one for me too!&#xA;This is a very filtered view - there are lots of important people &amp;amp; events in 2017 that are not contained here, and that is ok.&#xA;Professional New Job&#xA;I finished around 6-ish years at the Wikimedia Foundation, and joined UC Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s Data Science Division early in the year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Things”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 00:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/things/</guid>
      <description>I’m writing this post in an attempt to catalog the list of things I own so I can evaluate if I really need them and get rid of them.&#xA;15″ rMBP Kinesis Keyboard Apple Trackpad Moto X Kindle Nexus 7 (To be returned to the WMF) Broken Nexus 4 (To be backed up and then… something) iPod Touch Earphones (Soundmagic E10) Headphones (AudioTechnica ATH M50) Battery Pack #1 Battery Pack #2 MiFi (US Only) Multi USB Charger + 6 USB Cables Bluetooth Speaker (JBL Flip 2) Assorted Medication (in several loose covers, need to consolidate) Toiletries (Emergency Soap, Toothbrush, Toothpaste, Hair Gel, Shampoo, Conditioner) Velcro Rolls Box of Leaves Octopus Letter in Envelope Universal plug convertor Physical paper notebook Nailcolor Glasses + backup glasses Small Green Foldable Bag Pens Wallet with assorted currencies and cards Raspberry PI Assorted USB chargers (accumulated from various devices) Wrist Straps (left and right) Beard Trimmer Clothes:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plugging a keyboard into my Nexus 7</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/plugging-a-keyboard-into-my-nexus-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 18:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/plugging-a-keyboard-into-my-nexus-7/</guid>
      <description>Was a great idea! It just worked (with an OTP cable), and I can now probably find much more uses for this thing than I could before. Yay!&#xA;I wonder if I can use this to write code. However, a 7 inch tablet is very poorly suited for that task – would need at least a 10″ one. But there aren’t many of those going around these days…&#xA;I’ll probably use this for random browsing / commenting, and use my Mac for actual programming.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Scouting for Boys”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/scouting-boys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 19:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/scouting-boys/</guid>
      <description>In Welcome to the Machine there is a line that goes “provided with toys and scouting for boys”. I had initially assumed that it was referring to a young guy who is gay and is ‘scouting for boys’.&#xA;And then a few days later I realized that it is talking about ‘the book‘. That is now doubly funny because of the Boy Scouts’ attitude towards gays</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discworld Series progress</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/discworld-series-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 16:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/discworld-series-progress/</guid>
      <description>Contains a list of Discworld Novels. Am reading them all, and will cross them out here as I finish each. Number of books currently finished: 24 (as of 16 Jan 2014)&#xA;The Colour of Magic (1983) (Rincewind) The Light Fantastic (1986) (Rincewind) Equal Rites (1987) (Witches) Mort (1987) (Death) Sourcery (1988) (Rincewind) Wyrd Sisters (1988) (Witches) Pyramids (1989) (One-off) Guards! Guards! (1989) (City Watch) Eric (1990) (Rincewind) Moving Pictures (1990) (One-off) Reaper Man (1991) (Death) Witches Abroad (1991) (Witches) Small Gods (1992) (One-off) Lords and Ladies (1992) (Witches) Troll Bridge (1992) (Short story) Men at Arms (1993) (City Watch) Theatre of Cruelty (1993) (Short story) Soul Music (1994) (Death) Interesting Times (1994) (Rincewind) The Discworld Companion (1994) (Companion) Maskerade (1995) (Witches) Feet of Clay (1996) (City Watch) Hogfather (1996) (Death) Jingo (1997) (City Watch) The Unseen University Diary (1998) (Diary) The Last Continent (1998) (Rincewind) Carpe Jugulum (1998) (Witches) The Sea and Little Fishes (1998) (Short story) The Ankh-Morpork City Watch Diary (1999) (Diary) The Fifth Elephant (1999) (City Watch) The Science of Discworld (1999) (Science) Nanny Ogg’s Cookbook (1999) (Recipes) The Assassins’ Guild Yearbook and Diary (2000) The Truth (2000) (One-off) The Fools’ Guild Yearbook and Diary (2001) (Diary) Thief of Time (2001) (Death) The Last Hero (2001) (Rincewind, although this is debatable) The Amazing Maurice and his Educated Rodents (2001) (One-off, children’s) The Thieves’ Guild Yearbook and Diary (2002) (Diary) Night Watch (2002) (City Watch) Death and What Comes Next (2002) (Short story) The Science of Discworld II: The Globe (2002)(Science) The Wyrdest Link (2002) (Quizbook) The (Reformed) Vampyre’s Diary (2003) (Diary) The Wee Free Men (2003) (Wee Free Men) The New Discworld Companion (2003) (Companion) Monstrous Regiment (2003) (One-off) A Hat Full of Sky (2004) (Wee Free Men) Going Postal (2004) (Post Office) Once More* *With Footnotes (2004) (Compilation of short works) The Discworld Almanack (2005) (Almanack) Thud!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doing Laundry</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/doing-laundry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 07:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/doing-laundry/</guid>
      <description>At a hotel in SF, doing my laundry. This trip has made me more amenable to taking my time to do things. Feel more happy in general and less restless :)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comments on again</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 22:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/comments/</guid>
      <description>WordPress decided to be a dick and turned off comments without telling me. They’re back on now.&#xA;Why does all software suck?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Entire Night Wasted</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/an-entire-night-wasted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 21:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/an-entire-night-wasted/</guid>
      <description>[Warning: Childish rant ahead]&#xA;My natural sleep cycle seems to be one that tends towards the darker times – sleeping before 3AM feels like an abomination, before midnight unheard of. My best work seems to be done between 2AM and 5AM. My current &amp;lsquo;sleep cycle&amp;rsquo; has me sleeping at about 8AM, and waking up at about 5PM. Plenty of sleep for the day, eh?&#xA;It is probably not healthy. I don&amp;rsquo;t look, or feel healthy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disconnecting, for real</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/disconnecting-for-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 15:56:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/disconnecting-for-real/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the Internet since I was 14. And I don&amp;rsquo;t remember a time when I did not have a computer – I think I got mine when I was 10. Growing up, writing code has always been a major part of me – my identity. I&amp;rsquo;ve never quite managed to separate &amp;lsquo;me&amp;rsquo; from &amp;lsquo;my code&amp;rsquo; – despite mouthing off the soundbite &amp;lsquo;You are not your code!&amp;rsquo; to plenty of people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Streaks</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/github-streaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 22:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/github-streaks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m on my longest GitHub Streak this year – currently 20 days (was previously 18 days). That means I&amp;rsquo;ve had at least one commit (though usually more!) each day for the last 20 days. Sounds much easier than it actually is. Wanting to keep my streak unbroken is also making me write more diverse code – I think those 20 days feature code in Javascript, Python, Java, PHP and Python. It&amp;rsquo;s also distributed across a lot of projects – at least 8-9 different ones on last count.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing Platen Blog Editor</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/testing-platen-blog-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 12:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/testing-platen-blog-editor/</guid>
      <description>Ever since the death of Windows Live Writer, I’ve never managed to find a nice blog editor that I really liked and also worked fine. I had a nice Vim plugin that posted to wordpress for a while, but that seems to have stopped working. The WordPress interface itself is mostly fine, but still a fair bit ‘meh’.&#xA;Platen is a markdown based editor that’s a Chrome Web Store app that looks cool so far.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comedy Central Censored in India</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/comedy-central-censored-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 09:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/comedy-central-censored-india/</guid>
      <description>Comedy Central has been banned in India for the next ten days. Reasons?&#xA;Whereas, the programme showed a man performing an act of stand_up comedy and mouthing vulgar words accompanied by obscene and suggestive gesture and gyration. During his performance, the man was shown uttering dialogues denigrating women, indecently and crudely referred to sex organs of men-and women and the sing-song rendition by the man sought to pornographically describe .the male lust, depicting women as a commodify of sex.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emotional Blackmail</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/emotional-blackmail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 22:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/emotional-blackmail/</guid>
      <description>Potential trigger warning&#xA;I keep trying to tell myself “People are not evil. They are just doing the best they can with what they have”. But then I’ve to read shit like this, and I’m not so sure anymore.&#xA;Growing up to lose respect for people you considered heros is a horrible thing. Friends don’t let friends fall prey to emotional blackmail.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autosuggest for Tamil in Android Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/autosuggest-tamil-android-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 21:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/autosuggest-tamil-android-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Screenshot of Autosuggest working in Tamil on my variant of the Android keyboard. I’ve been working on this on and off for the last few months (this is also my final year project in college). I’ve ported all of the jQuery.IME languages to work on the keyboard natively.&#xA;Now experimenting with Autosuggest. It only needs an appropriate dictionary now and we’ll be good to go. Currently I’m getting Autosuggest working only on Tamil, but the plan is to get it to work for all Indian languages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the dead</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/remembering-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 21:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/remembering-dead/</guid>
      <description>Potential trigger warning&#xA;Like if you ask three separate groups of Canadian households how much they’ll pay to save two thousand, twenty thousand, or two hundred thousand birds from dying in oil ponds, the three groups will respectively state that they’re willing to pay seventy-eight, eighty-eight, and eighty dollars. No difference, in other words. It’s called scope insensitivity. Your brain imagines a single bird struggling in an oil pond, and that image creates some amount of emotion that determines your willingness to pay.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greatest Fear</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/greatest-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 06:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/greatest-fear/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people confuse being physically alone with being lonely. Not even remotely close to being the same thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaving ICICI Bank</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/leaving-icici-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 01:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/leaving-icici-bank/</guid>
      <description>I’m going to be moving all my cash off ICICI and on to… somewhere else (undecided) ASAP.&#xA;They have paste disabled everywhere, by placing onpaste=”return false” on all their text elements. I know that this is easily fixable, so let me open inspector by right cli-oh!&#xA;Well, no matter – I can simply use a short cut. Once getting rid of the frustrating onpaste, I found this in the HTML right below it:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code in Times New Roman</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/code-times-roman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 19:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/code-times-roman/</guid>
      <description>Quoting from Anna University’s guidelines for submitting a ‘project report’&#xA;Appendix 1: Sample Code. Font style: Times New Roman, Font Size:12 and 1.5 line spacing.&#xA;Shoot me now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experiencing ‘Embrace, Extend &amp; Extinguish’</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/experiencing-embrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 19:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/experiencing-embrace/</guid>
      <description>I am too young to remember Microsoft doing anything that could be considered effective ‘Embrace, Extend &amp;amp; Extinguish’ (my first browser when using internet at home was Firefox 0.9), and hence could never appreciate the general suspicion with which everything Microsoft was viewed with. Google’s handling of Reader has remedied that for me, however. I was around to witness all the events that Ed Bott at ZDNet discusses, and hopefully I have learnt my lesson.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Whatsapp</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/511/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 12:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/511/</guid>
      <description>Whatsaapp (and GTalk) has completely replaced SMS for me. The only sore point was that it was not ‘Android’y enough – looked too much like an iOS port, but it worked well enough (and had enough people in it) that my forays into Hike were never long enough. The latest update fixes the design to be a lot more flat and pleasing to the eyes, and I’m quite happy to stick to it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogging more often, bye bye Twitter</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/blogging-more-often-bye-bye-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/blogging-more-often-bye-bye-twitter/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been mostly off Twitter for a while now, interacting with it rarely, and only on my Phone. While I’ve had a vague feeling of uneasiness ever since they unveiled their now business friendly developer policies, it really hit home when my favorite Android twitter app, Falcon Pro, hit Twitter’s arbitrary user token limit (and Twitter declined to care). That, plus the Google Reader saga have jolted me out of complacency a bit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choices</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/choices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 10:24:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/choices/</guid>
      <description>They suck. It’s easy when it is ‘useless test to take’ vs ‘GSoC’. Painful for a lot of other things. Ugh.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open License everything!</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/open-license-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 10:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/open-license-everything/</guid>
      <description>Should have done this a while back. Added a CC BY mark to the blog. Will add a notice to the front page as well, stating that all media I produce (when not bound to someone else’s copyright) is CC BY. I think code is already taken care of, but I’ll add a note here saying that all code I release (unless explicitly licensed otherwise) is CC0 Licensed.&#xA;Now to actually produce something of value…</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immortality of Youth</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/immortality-of-youth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 20:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/immortality-of-youth/</guid>
      <description>Reading this blog post from Wesley CrusherWil Wheaton reminded me first of my visit to the beach a few hours before Cyclone Nilam hit landfall (at the Thiruvanmiyur Beach). The fact that I couldn’t stand in one place (wind) and was constantly being attacked by sand – it was exhilarating.&#xA;The blog post also reminded me of how much I mis-treat my body. I’m surprised I’m not bedridden, immovable and with a host of diseases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Month of Awesome (2012 Edition)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/month-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 19:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/month-awesome/</guid>
      <description>I left Chennai on the 3rd of November. I (will be) leaving Delhi on the 4th of December. That’s a 31 day trip. It taught me to be optimistic. It taught me in very real terms that the world is a large place, and so is life.&#xA;A few highlights:&#xA;Building an app from nothing to workable state in a few days An actual first class train ride in India Running into a bunch of random french people who ended up becoming travel buddies Feeling small, and very temporary being in the ruins of Hampi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happiness #1</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/happiness-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 19:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/happiness-1/</guid>
      <description>Happiness is fixing a bug with no obvious cause with a one liner and pushing it out to five million people with wonderful support from a team sitting halfway across the world :-)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Eye flight</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/red-eye-flight/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 16:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/red-eye-flight/</guid>
      <description>I am not a fan of red eye flights. Nobody is&#xA;I have one tomorrow. Which brings up the question – do I stay up, or go to sleep and risk not waking up in time?&#xA;I am going to stay up. Let’s see how that goes :-)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wretched City</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/wretched-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 06:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/wretched-city/</guid>
      <description>There has been no power here since yesterday night.&#xA;I have a million other reasons to not like Chennai. And scarce few reasons to like it.&#xA;I need to get out of here. As soon as I can.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neglect and Sorrow</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/neglect-sorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 20:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/neglect-sorrow/</guid>
      <description>SumaStorm was my desktop computer. She died a slow, silent and agonizing death over the past few months, which came to light only today. Due to my neglect, she is dead today.&#xA;I built SumStorm with my own hands, bought with my own money (thanks to several amazing people on the web) when I was 16 or so. It felt amazing when I first booted it up. It felt amazing when I maxed out all its cores running distcc with my netbook.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>House painters of Programming</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/house-painters-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 07:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/house-painters-programming/</guid>
      <description>We’re the Michelangelos of the great age of machine intelligence which is yet to come. We’re sketching out how it’s all going to look. We’re at the forefront of solving incredible problems and creating magical devices. – DanielBMarkham&#xA;If there’s a great age of machine intelligence to come, then one in a million of us may be a Michelangelo. The rest of us are house-painters, and the houses we paint are slated for demolition within our own lifetimes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“What still puzzles us?”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/what-puzzles-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 06:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/what-puzzles-us/</guid>
      <description>A screenshot from the etherpad used for last week’s WMF Mobile Team retrospective meeting. I could (and should!) fill in several volumes about how awesome working for (and with) the WMF Mobile team is, but that screenshot is a start in explaining the general fun and silliness of the place :)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I’m not a college drop out</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/college-drop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 09:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/college-drop/</guid>
      <description>I’m just on a one year break from college doing Interesting Things and growing up. Going great on both counts.&#xA;I will go back to college next year and finish. I understand that it will not be easy and that many people would consider it a pointless waste of time. That’s OK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Program</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 21:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/program/</guid>
      <description>Note: These are almost a decade old. Reproduced as close to memory as possible&#xA;My first memories of programming aren’t actually C. They were GW-BASIC, and later on, LOGO. I don’t remember any of my BASIC – but I do remember the look on my computer science teacher’s face in 5th grade when I managed to draw a flower with LOGO when everyone else was doing rectangles and lines. I vividly remember it – you draw an arc for a certain length, then stop, draw another arc in the reverse direction for the same length – and you have a petal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our Greatest Fear – ‘Flash and Fade’</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/greatest-fear-flash-fade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 03:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/greatest-fear-flash-fade/</guid>
      <description>HP:MOR is an awesome fanfic that anyone intent on improving themselves should read. It’s a bit like HHG2G – you don’t read for the storyline (which is jumbled) but for the characters, wit, rationality and humor. Quite a few of those things hit very close to home – if you are a geek, they would perhaps to you too. Highly reccomended.&#xA;Of the many quotable parts of that book, here’s one little nugget I found:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The fridge at InterviewStreet office</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/the-fridge-at-interviewstreet-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 08:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/the-fridge-at-interviewstreet-office/</guid>
      <description>We bought a fridge two days ago, and spent a day stocking it up. Perhaps it needs a bit more non-liquid content in it, but I think the choco fills and Dark Fantasy biscuits (not to mention the litres of Ice Cream we’ve stocked up on) would do just fine for now :)&#xA;And before you start harping on about ‘health’ – the bottom tray has a mysterious cover full of apples shipped from Chennai by mom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temptations</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/temptations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 18:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/temptations/</guid>
      <description>Just came across this beautiful piece of conversation that had me doubled up for quite while:&#xA;Him: The Nexus S tempts me. Only 20k.&#xA;Her: The Galaxy SII tempts me.&#xA;Him: Hehe, that’s way out of my range though.&#xA;Him: You tempt me!&#xA;Her: Hehe, that’s way out of your range too!&#xA;:)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Note from Present Self to Future Self: Pre-Book your Travel Tickets</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/note-present-future-self-pre-book-travel-tickets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 08:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/note-present-future-self-pre-book-travel-tickets/</guid>
      <description>Dear Future Me,&#xA;I know you don’t want to pre-book travel tickets. You tell yourself that you like the sense of adventure and uncertainity that it gives you. You tell yourself that you need these life expriences.&#xA;But I know the truth, ofcourse. You’re just plain ol’ lazy. Too lazy to book your damn tickets. So, get off your ass and book them now. I’ll promise you that I’ll hunt you through time and kill you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So, I broke a law by photographing a clock in a railway station</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/broke-nonexistent-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 15:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/broke-nonexistent-law/</guid>
      <description>(Update 3: Manish (@jimanish) was awesome enough to point me to the official stuff from Railway Ministry (pdf here). It starts off by stating the cause for the rules being strict:&#xA;A case relating to lapses in allowing shooting of a feature film (which resulted inburning/damage of some passenger coaches provided to the party causing a huge loss tothe Railways)&#xA;It then notes that it’s archaic, since you can even shoot from mobile phones, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My New Canon 550D from Flipkart</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/my-new-canon-550d-from-flipkart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 13:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/my-new-canon-550d-from-flipkart/</guid>
      <description>I was finally able to order my Canon 550D from Flipkart. Their customer service was awesome – both on twitter (when the camera was out of stock) and via the phone after it was ordered. I ordered Cash on Delivery, and despite some minor issues with the delivery person (uhm, so I’m supposed to hand over 39k, and then open the box? What if I found a box of bricks?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Years of Blogging and Eleven Years of Coding</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/six-years-of-blogging-and-eleven-years-of-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 09:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/six-years-of-blogging-and-eleven-years-of-coding/</guid>
      <description>It was exactly six years ago that I started blogging. My first blog post ow seems to be rather childish, but considering I was 14 then, maybe it is excusable :)&#xA;I’ve moved across several blogging platforms and urls in the meantime (Blogspot, wordpress and now my own custom engine. I’ve sadly lost a good portion of my blogs thanks to a domain loss and a server crash. Sigh.&#xA;Also, looks like I’ve been writing code for almost eleven years now!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NEN First Dot 2010 – What I learnt</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/nen-first-dot-2010-what-i-learnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 00:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/nen-first-dot-2010-what-i-learnt/</guid>
      <description>I was part of the team that organized NEN First Dot – a student startup showcase. I was involved from day 0, so I was able to see it evolve from a high-in-the-sky concept to something that actually did happen. It was an incredible experience, to say the least.&#xA;What I learnt I was the ‘tech’ guy – working with a few people (Karthik, Arun, Madhu, Dinesh, etc) to take care of most things tech.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serendipity</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/serendipity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 09:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/serendipity/</guid>
      <description>I’m back at home after travelling almost ten days – ACM ICPC at Coimbatore, One day at Ooty, the last FOSS.in at Bangalore, Nonameconf at Bangalore, and finally chilling out losing at XBox 360 Takken at the [Zynga][z] office.&#xA;One thing I’ve realized sharply is that “Life will take you to interesting places and make you do interesting things, if only you let it“&#xA;I realized that my days were being pretty much the same all day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogging From Under The Table During Class</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/blogging-from-under-the-table-during-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 14:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/blogging-from-under-the-table-during-class/</guid>
      <description>One of the major advantages of my netbook is that I can actually use it in class, under the desk – and most staff won’t notice ;) And even if they do, I can easily and neatly close the lid, put it in standby and become innocent good boy :D&#xA;I’ve zoned out from what’s happening in class a long time back. I just looked up, and it’s something I really do like (withheld to protect the name of subject).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ihave a motorbike!</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/ihave-a-motorbike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2010 00:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/ihave-a-motorbike/</guid>
      <description>So, I now have a motorbike!&#xA;It’s a Bajaj Platina, and bought off GSoC money from my cousin Sudar. I’ve been learning to ride for a while, and it’s been good. Had my first accident a while back, and started riding again a few days back.&#xA;I’m still very conscious about riding. I still think before clutching, braking, changing gears, etc. It hasn’t been internalized in the same way typing on a Keyboard has been – with enough practice (and accidents!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The End of GSoC 2010</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/the-end-of-gsoc-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 23:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/the-end-of-gsoc-2010/</guid>
      <description>Google Summer of Code ended a while back. Me (and most on #gsoc) agreed on one thing – WHERE DID THOSE 3 MONTHS GO? Amazing time it was – thanks to _ke (Who is frolicking somewhere in Thailand right now), fargiolas and the rest of the GNOME guys (#clutter, #gstreamer and #gtk+ yay!) for making it awesome. #hackers-india was a great venting place too :)&#xA;Cheese‘s master needs quite a bit of work before it can be included in GNOME 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work Life Balance</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/work-life-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 16:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/work-life-balance/</guid>
      <description>aeoo 221 points222 points223 points 1 day ago* [-]&#xA;recognize that work is something you do to live and isn’t your whole life&#xA;Let’s examine this as objectively as we can manage. Lets assume a 40 hour work week where the employer pays for lunch, as the employer should be doing, which results in a real 8 hour day instead of a 9 hour day. Of course a 9 hour day will work even more in favor of my argument.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Room Full of People Like Me”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/room-full-of-people-like-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 03:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/room-full-of-people-like-me/</guid>
      <description>&#34;I can&amp;#39;t tell you how wonderful it was - I walked into this room, and it was full of people like me&#34; I would give an arm, a leg, an eye and other assorted body parts if I could find such a room. And live there.&#xA;Hackerpace Chennai or The Startup Center better turn up fast :)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My GSoC 2010 Proposal</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/my-gsoc-2010-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 02:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/my-gsoc-2010-proposal/</guid>
      <description>I used gist to publish my GSoC proposal. Diffs, easy to show off, and Markdown support – made gist perfect for me to make modifications and get feedback easily.&#xA;It is the first ‘real’ document I’ve written – it actually had a tangible effect.&#xA;Now that I don’t need to make any modifications, I’ve moved it to my site.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I spent the Day today</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/how-i-spent-the-day-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 02:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/how-i-spent-the-day-today/</guid>
      <description>Wake up at 10. Roll around bed for half an hour. Chase brother away from your computer (on which he was playing GTA (or NFS)). Check mail. Find something to code on, code. Check mail. Check proggit. Check HN. Waste some time on Twitter. Waste some more time on IRC. Check mail. Check proggit. Check HN. Tab around, really fast. Tab around, really fast. Go have breakfast. Or lunch – doesn’t matter what you call it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Binary Dream</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/first-binary-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 13:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/first-binary-dream/</guid>
      <description>I had my first ever dream in binary today.&#xA;The cycle moved like this:&#xA;Borg -&amp;gt; nanoprobes -&amp;gt; a scene in Minority Report when nanobots go around looking for John Anderton (Tom Cruise), who was hiding in a bathtub full of water -&amp;gt; Will Smith and his Dog cuddling in a bathtub in I am Legend -&amp;gt; the climax of I am Legend when Will Smith blows himself up to save the others -&amp;gt; A column of binary numbers came up, showing state of Will Smith as ‘SAD’ AND MSB FLIPPED TO ZERO, and then he has this epiphany (Realization of God Moment) and becomes ‘HAPPY’ and the MSB FLIPS TO ONE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2010 – The Beginning, the bicycle ride and external dependencies</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/2010-the-beginning-the-bicycle-ride-and-external-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 01:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/2010-the-beginning-the-bicycle-ride-and-external-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>I was writing a post on how 2009 ended. Here is the tl;dr version: It was my ‘growing-up’ year in Tech, and ‘roller-coaster’ year in personal stuff. There! I’m certainly significantly wiser at the end of 2009, and that is due more to my state at the beginning of 2009 than at the end :) Good enough&#xA;So how did I celebrate? By joining the KPP competition at Kurukshetra. That’s what I did at around 12 on New Year’s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I lack</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/what-i-lack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 03:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/what-i-lack/</guid>
      <description>Commitment.&#xA;I keep jumping around. My GitHub profile is proof for that. So are the large number of projects I’ve taken up only to leave in the middle. Unless and until I fix my commitment issues, I’ll be just-another-guy-who-learnt-to-code-in-his-teens, not the-guy-who-changed-the-world. Just reading a lot of stuff isn’t going to do me any good unless I actually get off my ass and do something.&#xA;Hopefully, putting this up in public will make it more real.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perfect Day #1</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/perfect-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 00:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/perfect-day-1/</guid>
      <description>So, I wake up at noon.&#xA;And my phone doesn’t work.&#xA;Then I find out my Internet doesn’t work.&#xA;Then I find my TV’s crapped.&#xA;Then I find that I’ve to go to college tomorrow.&#xA;The last thing is good. The others aren’t. Oh well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attraction or Admiration</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/attraction-or-admiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2009 22:28:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/attraction-or-admiration/</guid>
      <description>If you are a college student, especially my college’s student, please go read this. I wish Divya had written this a year and a half back. :D</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I learnt from the Hackfest at IITM</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/what-i-learnt-from-the-hackfest-at-iitm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2009 23:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/what-i-learnt-from-the-hackfest-at-iitm/</guid>
      <description>I was about to just type a list of stuff here, but that doesn’t do the topic justice. So here I am, at 3:30 in the morning, sleep cycle screwed up by the Hackfest, typing out a post on what all I learnt from there. I spent pretty much my entire awake-time at the IIT, so it helped me a lot.&#xA;Your college doesn’t matter much IIT Envy. Every non-IITian has that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code I’ve written so far</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/code-ive-written-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/code-ive-written-so-far/</guid>
      <description>Code I have written so far:&#xA;HiSlain: A static blog publishing system (NOT A DJANGO BLOG!). Runs this blog wtfimb: The code that powers Busroutes.in frailgrey: Markov Chain based page generator (pretty lame, actually) GoodFather: Collection of utils for web data scraping and storing reappy: A Twitter Search Application Framework SadIvy: A pure WSGI URL Shortener Now, I’ve been doing a shit job of documenting them – none exists. Nor of writing tests – none exists.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learnt from working with the Symposium</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/lessons-learnt-from-working-with-the-symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 23:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/lessons-learnt-from-working-with-the-symposium/</guid>
      <description>Document Everything! On paper. Will save you from hell later. There is never enough time. Start earlier than you think is early enough. Sell people things. Make them want it. Think from their point of view. Prioritize. Delegate. Responsibly. And follow up. Know when to stop. Recognize when something is good enough. Printing takes a long time. Very long timeE. And is boring. People often do not mean what they say.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3hours of code &amp; 1 blog post per day</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/3hours-of-code-1-blog-post-per-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 00:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/3hours-of-code-1-blog-post-per-day/</guid>
      <description>Those are my new goals.&#xA;I’ve got a mechanism to track the code accomplishments (will make that public soon), and maybe I’ll write a widget for HiSlain for the blog post/day accomplishment.&#xA;I’m liking it so far – 7 hours of code yesterday, along with 2 blog posts. Couldn’t hit my code target today – but am hitting my blog target. I should figure out more ways to make this work better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Premature Greying</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/premature-greying/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2009 16:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/premature-greying/</guid>
      <description>He liked her. Very much. He had never felt like that before. The butterflies in his stomach were beating up a storm. He had never believed in love at first sight. Till he saw her.&#xA;Her waitress uniform made her look cuter than ever. He knew he had to ask her out. He drummed up enough courage, went to her and said ‘Hi’.&#xA;She turned, gave him a cute smile, and replied ‘Hello uncle, what can I do for you?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New email id</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/new-email-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 00:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/new-email-id/</guid>
      <description>I’ve got a new email id.&#xA;It’s me@yuvisense.net&#xA;Groovy, uh? ;)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alone</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 00:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/alone/</guid>
      <description>He was sitting in class. Bored. He looked around. He saw sixty other people, but felt alone. He stood up, shouted ‘Why am I here?!? This won’t do!’ and walked out of the class, leaving everyone confused and weirded out.&#xA;He moved out of the campus, and saw sixty thousand other people. He still felt alone. He realized the problem is not the world, but him. Within the next few hours, the problem went away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carrier Error</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/carrier-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 20:55:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/carrier-error/</guid>
      <description>The bus lurched to one side, and fell of the bridge. He felt his skull crack. He realized he had just seconds to live. One hand immobilized, he used the other to find the mobile. Two well practiced presses later, he was at the Compose Message screen. Five seconds later, he had the words ‘love ya’ typed out. He hit send, and died peacefully.&#xA;Five second later, an error popped up on the screen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chennai’s Concentration camps (aka Colleges)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/chennais-concentration-camps-aka-colleges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 09:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/chennais-concentration-camps-aka-colleges/</guid>
      <description>As someone with a lot of friends in these concentration camps, I can say that this is SPOT ON.&#xA;(Subtitles by Krish Ashok)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I’m jealous of her</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/im-jealous-of-her/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/im-jealous-of-her/</guid>
      <description>I’m Jealous of Freya. I can’t really seem to figure out why.&#xA;Okay, I think I can. Guess it’s the anonymity. That she can write whatever se wants, without caring a damn.&#xA;I can’t. :(&#xA;Go, get jealous.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treat of a Lifetime</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/treat-of-a-lifetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 23:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/treat-of-a-lifetime/</guid>
      <description>I promise her ‘the Treat of a Lifetime’. I cook up a reason realistic enough for her to buy it. I bribe off everyone else to make sure she is alone. And she is.&#xA;We walk along the sides of a typical city street. She is talking – she always is. When has she ever been quiet? Quiet is an adjective one doesn’t use with the noun ‘girl’. And she’s no ordinary girl.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cute Dress</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/cute-dress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 23:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/cute-dress/</guid>
      <description>Should I tell her?&#xA;I shouldn’t.&#xA;I don’t even know her. She’s new in class. So am I. We’re all new in this class. We are first years, at the first day of college.&#xA;I don’t even know her name! And she obviously doesn’t know my name. We are, for all intents and purposes, complete strangers in the same class.&#xA;What if she takes it seriously? I’ll probably be branded the classholic flirt of the class, and never be taken seriously ever again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 02:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/emacs/</guid>
      <description>He was coding.&#xA;He was on a bus, and coding. He had bought himself a cute little black Netbook just so he could open up Vim on a bus and code Python. He is a geek. A young, 18 year old typical geek. As typical as your usual geek.&#xA;The bus was quite empty. It was late at night, this was proably the last bus for the day, and except the Driver &amp;amp; Conductor, there were probably 4 people on the bus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isoooo want this on a T-Shirt</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/isoooo-want-this-on-a-t-shirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 01:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/isoooo-want-this-on-a-t-shirt/</guid>
      <description>Seirously.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evanescence: Enjoyed best without the Music Vids</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/evanescence-enjoyed-best-without-the-music-vids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 17:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/evanescence-enjoyed-best-without-the-music-vids/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shirts</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/shirts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 15:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/shirts/</guid>
      <description>My shirts went from L to M&#xA;My pants went from 40 to 34&#xA;I’m awesome :)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things I need time to do</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/things-i-need-time-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 11:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/things-i-need-time-to-do/</guid>
      <description>Put on muscle/reduce weight. Master jQuery Learn CSS Process photos and put them up on flickr Put up college’s (awesome) dance videos on Facebook and Youtube Go out more. Fix my glasses. Get ontacts if possible – or change my frames. Write stats posts. Develop goodfather Add a plugin system to HiSlain Publish a paper or two! (yeah, I know) Blog more (duh) Go out more. Learn to bike (of the petrol eating variety, that is) Go out more Photograph more Kick everyone’s ass in studies (I can do that this sem, we have 3 CS papers!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Life</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/optimizing-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 10:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/optimizing-life/</guid>
      <description>Geeks Optimize Life. True that. I do optimize the short route from when I get down from my college bus to my home, and me and Sudar did have an argument about optimization when we took the train together one day. My argument was that the distance you are going to walk is constant anyway (you either walk it at the station you are boarding the train, or where you are getting down), so moving to the extreme end of the train is pointless.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
