<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on Yuvi Panda</title>
    <link>http://words.yuvi.in/categories/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Yuvi Panda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 19:56:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://words.yuvi.in/categories/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Code in Times New Roman</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/code-times-roman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 19:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/code-times-roman/</guid>
      <description>Quoting from Anna University&amp;#8217;s guidelines for submitting a &amp;#8216;project report&amp;#8217;
 Appendix 1: Sample Code. Font style: Times New Roman, Font Size:12 and 1.5 line spacing.
 Shoot me now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vague Sense of Order, No Sense of Purpose</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/vague-sense-order-sense-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 06:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/vague-sense-order-sense-purpose/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this month I spent a couple of days as a &amp;#8216;guest&amp;#8217; at Infosys Mahindra City (district finals for Aspirations 2020 &amp;#8211; a TopCoder style programming competition). Interesting experience.
No laptops allowed. No storage devices either. Cameras are okay, but &amp;#8220;please don&amp;#8217;t take pictures&amp;#8221;. Phones are okay too. The usual complimentary grope as you enter. Random security guards ask &amp;#8220;Where is your ID card?&amp;#8221; at random times. Buses bringing in hordes of people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you do when only 0.3% of School Teachers pass the Eligibility Exam for Teaching?</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/0-3-school-teachers-pass-teachers-recruitment-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 09:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/0-3-school-teachers-pass-teachers-recruitment-exam/</guid>
      <description>You increase the time from 1.5 hours to 3 hours and give them another chance, of course!
 Keeping in mind the welfare of children and the need for teachers to fill vacancies, the government directed TRB to conduct re-examination for candidates who failed to obtain 60 per cent marks.
The government has directed TRB to increase the duration of the test time from one-and-a-half hours to three hours with additional 30 minutes for blind candidates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Story of Average Indian ‘Techie’</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/story-average-indian-techie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 09:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/story-average-indian-techie/</guid>
      <description>Note: I am just reformatting + putting this in one piece rather than have it split across multiple comments on reddit. Am not the original author
Beautifully laid out by someone in the under-trafficked r/india:
 my state has 300+ engineering colleges and my parents decided that i am going to be an engineer. so, i wrote an exam and got into one institute (luckily i can make it into a good institute where there are campus interviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 reasons why people join ‘IT companies’</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/3-reasons-people-join-it-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 08:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/3-reasons-people-join-it-companies/</guid>
      <description>Source: Friend of mine who is sadly &amp;#8216;training&amp;#8217; at a big &amp;#8216;IT company&amp;#8217; now (He wishes to remain anonymous, and I could see why)
 Because everyone else did Because parents told Because it will be very sophisticated and relaxing there, with lots of recreational facilities  I&amp;#8217;m just going to leave this here, and hope that when this boom does bust, it doesn&amp;#8217;t leave too many dead bodies in its wake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why working at “Big Co” is unsatisfying</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/working-big-co-unsatisfying/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 13:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/working-big-co-unsatisfying/</guid>
      <description>Update: As usual, good comments at HN.
I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to put it in words for a while, and failing utterly every time. swombat gets to the crux of it wonderfully:
 At the same time, something really bothered me about my work. It felt pointless. One project I did (whose output was basically a PPT and Word document outlining the successes and failures of a client project), which took two and a half months, had, as its only apparent purpose, the promotion of the person who had led the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Infosys, TCS or Wipro?” “None”</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/infosys-tcs-or-wipro-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 04:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/infosys-tcs-or-wipro-none/</guid>
      <description>Succinctly written post that every engineering college student should read.
Ofcourse, someone should write a post called &amp;#8220;CS, EC or EEE?&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Neither&amp;#8221; for high school students, because for a lot of people the answer to the question &amp;#8220;Should you do Engineering?&amp;#8221; is a huge &amp;#8220;No&amp;#8221;.
The comments section is even more awesome. Choice quotes:
A sympathizer/astroturfer/cognitively dissonant person writes:
 Are you saying that anybody who can browse the internet and knows about the computer can do our jobs?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orwell and Huxley</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/orwell-and-huxley/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 21:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/orwell-and-huxley/</guid>
      <description>I just finished 1984. Had finished Animal Farm and Brave New World a while ago. Orwell is scarier, but Huxley seems to be closer to real life already &amp;#8211; I know several people (perhaps too many) who wouldn&amp;#8217;t flinch at all at the world Huxley created. Scary.
 Sanity is not Statistical
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enthusiastic Teachers and Naive Implementation of Gauss Seidel Approximations</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/enthusiastic-teachers-and-naive-implementation-of-gauss-seidel-approximations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 11:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/enthusiastic-teachers-and-naive-implementation-of-gauss-seidel-approximations/</guid>
      <description>This semester, one of our so called electives (despite the fact that we have no real choice in them) is Numerical Methods. I don&amp;#8217;t quite like the actual way the subject is taught &amp;#8211; mind numbing, error prone calculations with a calculator. However, the methods are pretty awesome.
The staff explained Gauss Seidel yesterday, and it seemed a straightforward recursive solution to me. So in the break, I cooked up a small python script that gave me all the intermediate answers as well &amp;#8211; so for any assignments I could just run them through this and copy it to paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging From Under The Table During Class</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/blogging-from-under-the-table-during-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 14:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/blogging-from-under-the-table-during-class/</guid>
      <description>One of the major advantages of my netbook is that I can actually use it in class, under the desk &amp;#8211; and most staff won&amp;#8217;t notice ;) And even if they do, I can easily and neatly close the lid, put it in standby and become innocent good boy :D
I&amp;#8217;ve zoned out from what&amp;#8217;s happening in class a long time back. I just looked up, and it&amp;#8217;s something I really do like (withheld to protect the name of subject).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reddit University – SICP Reading Group</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/reddit-university-sicp-reading-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2010 17:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/reddit-university-sicp-reading-group/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve joined Reddit University&amp;#8216;s SICP Reading Group class. I&amp;#8217;ve wanted to read through SICP for a long time, and have gotten started many times &amp;#8211; never completed it. Maybe the group effects will help me finish this time :)
If you&amp;#8217;re interested in expanding your horizons beyond mere code-monkey programming, join up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure of Learning: Epiphanies per Session</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/measure-of-learning-epiphanies-per-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 03:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/measure-of-learning-epiphanies-per-session/</guid>
      <description>The measure of code quality is WTFs/minute.
I just realized, after a rather intriguing facebook conversation with Shiva, that the only true measure of learning is Epiphanies per Session.
My latest Epiphany was a couple of days back. And the one before that was a month or so back, when I was &amp;#8216;pairing&amp;#8217; with Sid. I think the one before that was quite some time back &amp;#8211; when I understood the true meaning of closures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learnt from working with the Symposium</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/lessons-learnt-from-working-with-the-symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 23:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/lessons-learnt-from-working-with-the-symposium/</guid>
      <description>Document Everything! On paper. Will save you from hell later.  There is never enough time. Start earlier than you think is early enough. Sell people things. Make them want it. Think from their point of view. Prioritize. Delegate. Responsibly. And follow up. Know when to stop. Recognize when something is good enough. Printing takes a long time. Very long timeE. And is boring. People often do not mean what they say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chennai’s Concentration camps (aka Colleges)</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/chennais-concentration-camps-aka-colleges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 09:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/chennais-concentration-camps-aka-colleges/</guid>
      <description>As someone with a lot of friends in these concentration camps, I can say that this is SPOT ON.
(Subtitles by Krish Ashok)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>