<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rant on Yuvi Panda</title>
    <link>http://words.yuvi.in/tags/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rant on Yuvi Panda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 08:27:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://words.yuvi.in/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Note from Present Self to Future Self: Pre-Book your Travel Tickets</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/note-present-future-self-pre-book-travel-tickets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 08:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/note-present-future-self-pre-book-travel-tickets/</guid>
      <description>Dear Future Me,
I know you don’t want to pre-book travel tickets. You tell yourself that you like the sense of adventure and uncertainity that it gives you. You tell yourself that you need these life expriences.
But I know the truth, ofcourse. You’re just plain ol’ lazy. Too lazy to book your damn tickets. So, get off your ass and book them now. I’ll promise you that I’ll hunt you through time and kill you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So, I broke a law by photographing a clock in a railway station</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/broke-nonexistent-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 15:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/broke-nonexistent-law/</guid>
      <description>(Update 3: Manish (@jimanish) was awesome enough to point me to the official stuff from Railway Ministry (pdf here). It starts off by stating the cause for the rules being strict:
 A case relating to lapses in allowing shooting of a feature film (which resulted inburning/damage of some passenger coaches provided to the party causing a huge loss tothe Railways)
 It then notes that it’s archaic, since you can even shoot from mobile phones, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Infosys, TCS or Wipro?” “None”</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/infosys-tcs-or-wipro-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 04:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/infosys-tcs-or-wipro-none/</guid>
      <description>Succinctly written post that every engineering college student should read.
Ofcourse, someone should write a post called “CS, EC or EEE?” “Neither” for high school students, because for a lot of people the answer to the question “Should you do Engineering?” is a huge “No”.
The comments section is even more awesome. Choice quotes:
A sympathizer/astroturfer/cognitively dissonant person writes:
 Are you saying that anybody who can browse the internet and knows about the computer can do our jobs?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>