<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devlog on Yuvi</title>
    <link>https://words.yuvi.in/categories/devlog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devlog on Yuvi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 10:23:40 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://words.yuvi.in/categories/devlog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Devlog 2018 12 26</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/devlog-2018-12-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 10:23:40 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/devlog-2018-12-26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;physical-activity&#34;&gt;Physical activity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I walked for about 6 miles yesterday evening, after doing 3-4 miles each day for about 2-3 days before. The roads were empty, and it was lovely. I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to maybe 6-10 hours of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deborah_Frances-White&#34;&gt;Deborah Frances-White&lt;/a&gt; in the last week or so, split between &lt;a href=&#34;http://guiltyfeminist.com/&#34;&gt;The Guilty Feminist&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://globalpillage.net/&#34;&gt;Global Pillage&lt;/a&gt;. Next time though, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try listen to podcasts less &amp;amp; observe my surroundings more. I am doing this (plus PT) to rehab my knee mostly. I slept for 12h yesterday night :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devlog 2018 12 24</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/devlog-2018-12-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 10:51:57 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/devlog-2018-12-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;gracefully-exiting-asyncio-application&#34;&gt;Gracefully exiting asyncio application&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Continuing yesterday&amp;rsquo;s work on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yuvipanda/simpervisor&#34;&gt;simple supervisor library&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;I continued trying to propagate signals cleanly to child processes&#xA;before exiting. I remembered that it isn&amp;rsquo;t enough to just propagate&#xA;signals - you also have to actually reap them. This meant waiting&#xA;for &lt;code&gt;wait&lt;/code&gt; calls on them to return.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had a task running concurrently that is waiting on these&#xA;processes. So &amp;lsquo;all&amp;rsquo; I had to do was make sure the application&#xA;does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; exit until these tasks are done. This turned&#xA;out to be harder than I thought! After a bunch of reading, I&#xA;recognized that what I needed to do was make sure I wait&#xA;for all pending tasks before actually exiting the application.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog 2018 December 23</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/devlog-2018-12-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 19:44:53 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/devlog-2018-12-23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have enjoyed keeping running logs of my coding work (devlogs)&#xA;in the past, and am going to start doing those again now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This &amp;lsquo;holiday&amp;rsquo; season, I am spending time teaching myself&#xA;skills I sortof know about but do not have a deep understanding of.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;jupyterlab-extension&#34;&gt;JupyterLab extension&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I spent the first part of the day (before I started devlogging)&#xA;working on finishing up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yuvipanda/jupyterlab-nbmetadata&#34;&gt;jupyterlab extension&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;I started the day before. It lets you &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jupyterlab/jupyterlab/issues/1308&#34;&gt;edit notebook metadata&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;I got started since I wanted to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mwouts/jupytext&#34;&gt;Jupytext&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;for my work on publishing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yuvipanda/mybinder.org-analytics&#34;&gt;mybinder.org-analytics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 21-30 Dec 2015</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-21-30-dec-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 23:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-21-30-dec-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Clearly I missed an entire week. I need to build a better system to make this easier…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Random notes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kicked out NFS from the Tool Labs proxies (with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/260424/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;). Yay! This hopefully explains the lockup of tools-proxy-01 yesterday night, maybe? It’s been restarted since, and I hope to no longer have instances randomly locoking on me. Infrastructure standards of 2009, here we come! :D I’ve also removed NFS from tools-redis, and migrated them to Jessie as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fixed up all the races in how kubernetes workers are setup with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/260501/&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Another instance is ‘stuck’ again. Sigh. AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA. Paravoid helped debug this, tracking it down to NFS client issues in the 4.2 kernel (See &lt;a href=&#34;https://phabricator.wikimedia.org/T121998&#34;&gt;phab&lt;/a&gt;). I moved k8s nodes back to a working 3.19 kernel (after filing &lt;a href=&#34;https://phabricator.wikimedia.org/T122284&#34;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt; about the other 3.19 kernel package I tried that didn’t work).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Moved the tools proxies to 4.2 (lol?) after finding out huge ksoftirqd spikes in them. Let’s see if that improves things&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I split up the individual components of PAWS, and have a working &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yuvipanda/nbserve&#34;&gt;nbserve&lt;/a&gt; in there now! Exciting times. Need to fixup nbserve to use traitlets for config&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Big Tool Labs outage (again!). Some tool accidentally sent about 12million job requests and crashed gridengine’s underlying backing store (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Berkeley_DB&#34;&gt;BerkeleyDB&lt;/a&gt;). Reset to a clean slate after many hours (Thanks Coren!) and mostly things are back up now. I’m reading through the Berkeley DB &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.stanford.edu/class/cs276a/projects/docs/berkeleydb/&#34;&gt;reference manual&lt;/a&gt; now.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Persistance failed for ores’s redises again, mostly because &lt;code&gt;vm_overcommit&lt;/code&gt; was turned off. Fixed in the core redis module so it does not happen again.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 2015 Dec 20</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-2015-dec-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 17:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-2015-dec-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Probably going to take it easy and chill. Already sent a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kjschiroo/WikiChatter/pull/13&#34;&gt;trivial PR&lt;/a&gt; up though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also saw the old &lt;a href=&#34;http://librelist.com/browser/devlog/&#34;&gt;devlog mailing list&lt;/a&gt; and feeling happy memories. Clearly need to bring something back like that, but I don’t know / think mailing lists are the best medium. More thinking!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ended up learning some &lt;a href=&#34;http://tornadoweb.org/&#34;&gt;Tornad&lt;/a&gt; and wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yuvipanda/nbserve&#34;&gt;nbserve&lt;/a&gt; to serve rendered notebooks and static files in a configurable way. I should refactor PAWS to have separate jupyterhub, proxy and nbserve pods tomorrow. Also need to test for path traversal attacks and whatnot. Also coroutine based programming is a lot easier than I had originally thought! woo!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 2015 Dec 19</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-2015-dec-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 09:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-2015-dec-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Today looks like a day of finding, reporting and fixing bugs in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kjschiroo/WikiChatter&#34;&gt;WikiChatter&lt;/a&gt;. I had made a stupid mistake yesterday that meant not all of the Teahouse pages were being parsed, and I immediately started running into bugs. Have reported (and fixed!) two (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kjschiroo/WikiChatter/issues/8&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kjschiroo/WikiChatter/issues/9&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;), and ran into another &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/earwig/mwparserfromhell/issues/55#issuecomment-166033817&#34;&gt;bug&lt;/a&gt; in mediawikiparserfromhell itself. I’m sure I’ll find more.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Another bug in WikiChatter! &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kjschiroo/WikiChatter/issues/12&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Perils of digging through archives – you find Wikipedians giving &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Teahouse/Questions/Archive_105#relationship_help&#34;&gt;relationship advice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Should work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jupyter/jupyterhub/issues/17&#34;&gt;https://github.com/jupyter/jupyterhub/issues/17&lt;/a&gt; in some form over the next few weeks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for Jan 5, 2015</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-for-jan-5-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 21:52:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-for-jan-5-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DevLog for Jan 5, 2015&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Trying out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/byword/id420212497?mt=12&#34;&gt;ByWord&lt;/a&gt; app, since it has MarkDown support and also publishes to WordPress. Paid Rs. 900 for it, let’s hope it is useful. Hate the default font, though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Need to parse View definitions on labsdb public databases and verify that we aren’t leaking any info (&lt;a href=&#34;https://phabricator.wikimedia.org/T85783)&#34;&gt;https://phabricator.wikimedia.org/T85783)&lt;/a&gt;. Was going to use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/python-sqlparse/&#34;&gt;sqlparse&lt;/a&gt; library, but that doesn’t seem very complete or useful. Will attempt to use regexes now. Wish I had learnt how to build parsers properly easily.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ignore lament ^, I spent some time learning to use PyParsing, and ended up with a very simple parser that parsed the small subset of SQL I cared about! Yay :) Still need to set aside some time at some point to fully understand parsers/parsing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fixed wikdidata beta not resolving (&lt;a href=&#34;https://phabricator.wikimedia.org/T85793)&#34;&gt;https://phabricator.wikimedia.org/T85793)&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, problem was caused by me as well, not verifying that DNS changes I was making didn’t have unintended consequences. It’s also somewhat surprising that it was down for 6 days before someone noticed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add labsdb-auditor report that verifies views have appropriately done definitions that do not expose private information (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/182848/)&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/182848/)&lt;/a&gt;. This was fun to write. I should definitely learn more parsing things and seek out other simpel things I can write a parser for. Code quality is getting better, although could still be better if I can remove the regex part entirely – it currently cleans up the SQL via a regex and then parses it with pyparsing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fixed a consistency bug in the perl script that maintians public view replicas (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/182819/)&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/182819/)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reading list: * &lt;a href=&#34;http://joostdevblog.blogspot.in/2015/01/what-most-young-programmers-need-to.html&#34;&gt;What most young programmers need to learn&lt;/a&gt; was nice. I just feel lucky to have been gifted a copy of Code Complete and Pragmatic Programmer when I was 15 (by &lt;a href=&#34;http://colinizer.com/&#34;&gt;Colinizer&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for Jan 3-4 2015</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-jan-3-4-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 19:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-jan-3-4-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing much going on…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Continue reading Real World Haskell. This is indeed expanding my horizons, but I haven’t found any project I could use haskell in yet. Will keep looking.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Helped fix a parsoid outage yesterday. No biggie. I still do not understand fully how parsoid works / how it is set up, should do.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spend most of the rest of the time in ‘weekend mode’, which includes mostly not doing things. That went mostly well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Watched ‘Pink Floyd The Wall’ movie. HOLY FUCK MY MIND IT IS GONE OMG IT IS QUITE REALLY NICE. Recommended.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I should probably write a ‘Year in Review 2014’ post, but so much of that is going to be NSFW and private that there probably is no point… ;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for Jan 2, 2015</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-jan-2-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 21:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-jan-2-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Woohoo, 2015! :) Let’s see if I can keep this going this time :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Have started taking weekends slightly more seriously. My brain feels less overwhelmed after that. Should take weekends even more seriously going forward.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Merged &lt;code&gt;labsdb-auditor&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/182164/&#34;&gt;rewrite patch&lt;/a&gt;. Code clean enough for my tastes now, although not documented enough. Lots of back and forth CR with valhallasw was really nice – it’s something I’ve been missing for the past few months. Debating over style and cleanliness was also interesting. Felt like I had been taking code cleanliness and proper design not as seriously as I should have, and this is now time to change that. Also spent time consciously thinking about the commit message I was writing, and shall continue doing that. I think I’ve taken a few things for granted wrt code quality and design, and should be more careful. And learnt a few more tricks about decorators (haven’t built decorators that are parameterized before).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Read a few chapters of &lt;a href=&#34;http://book.realworldhaskell.org/&#34;&gt;Real World Haskell&lt;/a&gt;. Quite nice, although the syntax feels a bit too dense for my tastes. Still should maybe write things with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.call-cc.org/&#34;&gt;ChickenScheme&lt;/a&gt; instead :)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Continuing re-reading Coders at Work, which continues to be a thought provoking, wonderful book.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog Sep 12-24, 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-sep-12-24-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 15:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-sep-12-24-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That was a long break. Should get into better habits. I’m sure I’d miss some here. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was a very interesting week, culminating in some very interesting things at Trafalgar Square. I feel much better as a person and more calmer/chilled out now :) Should remember to take weekends off.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Helped the &lt;a href=&#34;http://metrics.wmflabs.org/&#34;&gt;WikiMetrics&lt;/a&gt; people with some puppet changes. They were requiring mysql directly instead of using the class we have in ops/puppet, which meant it put data in the /var partition instead of in /srv. This was because they want to be a ‘proper’ independent puppet module, not depending on the other modules in ops/puppet (since the module is used in vagrant as well). Puppet has &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt; support for this kind of thing, and ops/puppet by itself also suffers from an incredible amount of NIH syndrome when it comes to modules. Some of the NIH-so-rewrite is justified, but I don’t think all of it is. Oh well. Hopefully something that can be fixed over time…&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Added basic icinga/graphite based monitoring for contint project (runs our jenkins installation). Quite trivial, but should be ported over to shinken at some point soon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Contributed a fair bit to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/erming/shout&#34;&gt;Shout&lt;/a&gt; Web IRC project. I was looking around for an open source replacement to &lt;a href=&#34;https://irccloud.com&#34;&gt;IRCCloud&lt;/a&gt;, and found a bunch of OSS projects (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thedjpetersen/subway&#34;&gt;Subway&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://ircanywhere.com/&#34;&gt;http://ircanywhere.com/&lt;/a&gt; being the others). Shout seemed the most active (and simplest) of them all – I couldn’t actually get the others to a working installation. I fixed a bunch of code formatting issues, and also added a couple of features (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/erming/shout/pull/138&#34;&gt;Desktop notifications&lt;/a&gt; being the most significant, I think). The maintainer was fun to work with, and merged most of my changes quite promptly. I hang out on &lt;code&gt;#shout-irc&lt;/code&gt; channel now, and activity seems to be speeding along. Should be fun to see how it goes :)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Moved off IRCCloud. Stopped paying for it. I’ve also stopped doing email on my phone, in an effort to be more minimalistic / less distracted all the time. This meant no more IRC on phone, so my primary reason for using IRCCloud disappeared. Am back to using LimeChat with my ZNC bouncer now. And nothing on my phone. In case of emergencies, I still have the IRCCloud app on my phone, and can use the free edition to connect to my bouncer temporarily.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Started working on labs-specific monitoring, with &lt;a href=&#34;http://shinken-monitoring.org&#34;&gt;shinken&lt;/a&gt; – test instance at &lt;a href=&#34;http://shinken.wmflabs.org&#34;&gt;shinken.wmflabs.org&lt;/a&gt;. Discussion in the ops list about how to best implement this. Shinken is supposed to horizontally scale much better than icinga since it is implemented as a bunch of different daemons that can talk over the network. Right now they are just one machine, but will probably expand at some point not too far away. They are running as a labs project rather than on a physical machine (&lt;code&gt;labmon1001&lt;/code&gt;) because it is much easier from a networking perspective. Right now it only has a simple http check for betacluster, but more coming.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Started refactoring all our icinga code. Separating them out into &lt;code&gt;nagios_commmon&lt;/code&gt; module for config that can be shared between shinken and icinga, and into an &lt;code&gt;icinga&lt;/code&gt; module for everything else. Moved all the custom checks and check config we have, moving other things as we go. This is a bit hard / frustrating since I don’t have access to the machine icinga runs on (&lt;code&gt;neon&lt;/code&gt;), and also because I still do not have +2 in our ops repo (should change in a month, tho!). Am about 40 patches in (small ones!), let’s see how many more it takes!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Moved our &lt;code&gt;dsh&lt;/code&gt; code into a module. Was fairly trivial. Now to find ways to get it merged :)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Started trying out &lt;a href=&#34;http://pinboard.in&#34;&gt;pinboard&lt;/a&gt;. Interesting, barebones design. The bookmarklet is a bit slow to load, though. Let’s see how often I use this. (I did pay for it)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Five more days left in the UK :( Let me see if I can continue doing these when here, in a more prompt manner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for Sep 10-11 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-sep-10-11-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 20:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-sep-10-11-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back from an &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt; vacation. Too awesome to write about, even :) Suffice it to say, England has some really pretty places.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some Android app work, and lots of monitoring work&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fixed bugs causing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools.wmflabs.org/wikipedia-android-builds/&#34;&gt;Wikipedia Android Alpha&lt;/a&gt; from building properly. Now it builds properly whenever there is a new commit. Hooray! This was primarily caused by me forgetting to give it lots of RAM (8G VMEM) to execute the &lt;code&gt;mvn&lt;/code&gt; build commands (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159482/&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159482/&lt;/a&gt;) and also not cleaning up previous &lt;code&gt;.alpha&lt;/code&gt; subfolders (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159481/&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159481/&lt;/a&gt;) – this causes a chain of &lt;code&gt;.alpha.alpha.alpha.*&lt;/code&gt; subfolders, breaking the build.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Added a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159506/&#34;&gt;patch&lt;/a&gt; to the Android alpha app itself that checks for updates every day or so and notifies you if there’s a new one. Was fairly trivial to write, although I was hoping to make it more seamless (i.e. download the apk myself and just pop it up for people to tap). It now requires 4 clicks to install it, should be able to bring it down to 2 at some point in the future if people care enough.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Added a method to our &lt;code&gt;check_graphite&lt;/code&gt; code that lets you individually check a bunch of metrics for thresholds (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159473/)&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159473/)&lt;/a&gt;. This makes it much simpler to do icinga checks on a bunch of metrics that are all measuring the same thing but from different machines. BetaLabs and ToolLabs checks use this.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cleaned up a bunch of minor things with our &lt;code&gt;check_graphite&lt;/code&gt; script. Also fucked up trying to replace all double quotes in it with single quotes for consistency – it replaced the double quotes being used inside single quotes, and caused all checks to fail. Fixed shortly by &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159711/&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159711/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Added more monitoring for betalabs! Now checks for stale puppet runs (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159701/&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159701/&lt;/a&gt;) and low space on the root partition (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159694/)&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159694/)&lt;/a&gt;. All are green now, thanks to some work from bd808.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Added monitoring for ToolLabs! Now checks for stale puppet runs, low space on root and /var, and puppet failure events (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159709/)&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159709/)&lt;/a&gt;. Also checks for high sustained CPU usage (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159751/)&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159751/)&lt;/a&gt;. Then spent some time (with help from scfc_de (whose nick I kept spelling as scfe_de until today)) cleaning up the puppet failures. They are all green now as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Did a bunch of cleaning up work around the graphite role, removing the realm branching (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159759/)&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/159759/)&lt;/a&gt;. Ori says everytime realm branching code is removed, an angel gets its wings, so well done there.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not a bad day, eh? I’ve been trying to wake up early, perhaps that is helping.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 31 Aug, 1-4 Sep 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-31-aug-1-4-sep-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 10:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-31-aug-1-4-sep-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Missed DevLogging for a while.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Am in London now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Started using a spare &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.keyboardco.com/keyboard/uk-filco-ninja-majestouch-2-tenkeyless-nkr-tactile-action-keyboard.asp&#34;&gt;Majestouch Ninja 2&lt;/a&gt; over my regular &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kinesis-ergo.com/shop/advantage-for-pc-mac/&#34;&gt;Kinesis Advantage&lt;/a&gt;. This is way more portable, and my hand does not seem to be hurting while using it (so far only about 4-5 hours). If this keeps up, I should be able to move to a similar smaller keyboard over the much bulkier kinesis. There’s still a little bit of discomfort, so I’ll probably want a very portable and mechanical split keyboard. Can’t sadly seem to find any, though :( Maybe I should just build one with an arduino :)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Setup icinga checks for puppet failures and disk space issues on betalabs, and fixed a bunch of issues/docs in our icinga puppet code during that time. This still doesn’t properly work since our implementation of &lt;code&gt;check_graphite&lt;/code&gt; does not support wildcard metrics properly – it should check thresholds for each series, but it seems to do that only across the entire series combined, which is kinda useless. Should fix that soon by adding more features to it. Also might try out other alternatives to icinga, since our icinga puppet code is a fuckball anyway.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fix a couple more Quarry bugs. There’s still a random bug where &lt;code&gt;celery&lt;/code&gt; seems to be attempting to read data about a query run from mysql before the web has committed it, which is theoretically impossible (I do a commit before sending the task to celery with the id), so I suspect some mysql fuckery. Will need to debug that sooner than later, and also consider moving to &lt;code&gt;postgres&lt;/code&gt;. But then Quarry will have to deal with SQLite (for result storage), MySQL (for connecting to labsdb) and with postgres for local data, which sounds insanely complex. I also added CORS support to resultsets, and Magnus is playing with it (wooohhooooo!!!). I’m going to add more features to make it easier for people to use results from quarry in their JS applications elsewhere. Should be fun.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finished videos for the first week of the Coursera &lt;a href=&#34;https://class.coursera.org/statistics-002&#34;&gt;Data Analysis and Statistical Inference&lt;/a&gt; class I’m taking. Started poking around R since the labs for that class are from R, should be fun.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chad has started his &lt;a href=&#34;http://anyonecanedit.org/blog&#34;&gt;devlog&lt;/a&gt;. He does search stuff at Wikimedia and is a co-whiner about all things Java. Do check out :)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Am away on ‘vacation’ till Wednesday, yay! :) Should disconnect well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 29, 30 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-29-30-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 11:41:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-29-30-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chill weekend. Didn’t really do anything code related. Recovering from friday night party :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Started reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://infoactive.co/data-design/&#34;&gt;Data + Design&lt;/a&gt; which seems quite nice. Also starting a coursera course on &lt;a href=&#34;https://class.coursera.org/statistics-002&#34;&gt;Data analysis and Statistical Inference&lt;/a&gt; on Sep 1, should be fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 28 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-28-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 22:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-28-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s see. I’m also going to attempt to include patch links wherever possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cleaned up &lt;code&gt;session&lt;/code&gt; handling bugs in Quarry. They were previously not closing properly, causing SQLAlchemy exceptions now and then that’ll let queries die in a ‘queued’ state. This should &lt;em&gt;hopefully&lt;/em&gt; be fixed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/156909/&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/156909/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Made &lt;a href=&#34;https://graphite.wmflabs.org&#34;&gt;https://graphite.wmflabs.org&lt;/a&gt; somewhat more stable again for use by Wikimedia BetaLabs folks by just blacklisting all other projects from sending data to it (with a local whitelist hack + &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/156966/)&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/156966/)&lt;/a&gt;. This would let them use it, and they said they would find it massively useful. All this is a hack until &lt;a href=&#34;https://rt.wikimedia.org/Ticket/Display.html?id=8163&#34;&gt;https://rt.wikimedia.org/Ticket/Display.html?id=8163&lt;/a&gt; could be resolved and I can deploy graphite on a ‘real’ machine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Minor patch to my Gerrit -&amp;gt; IRC bot to make it strip a common prefix (‘operations/’) from change messages posted to the operations channel – &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/156877/&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/156877/&lt;/a&gt;. Also made one that calls jenkins-bot jerkins-bot if it -1’s your patch (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/156878/&#34;&gt;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/156878/&lt;/a&gt;) but it seems to have a bug that I can’t be bothered to debug atm.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Might spend some more time with Hive over the next few days – figured out an approach for using it from Python, and it should be fun to do so!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 25 and 26 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-26-27-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-26-27-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not very code heavy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Couple of pull requests(&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/atom/autosave/pull/22&#34;&gt;#1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/atom/autosave/pull/21&#34;&gt;#2&lt;/a&gt;) for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/atom/autosave&#34;&gt;Atom Autosave plugin&lt;/a&gt;. One adds a preference to not autosave by when you are explicitly closing a window / pane, and the other just sets the ‘enabled’ preference to default. CoffeeScript isn’t too bad either! I should consider writing more plugins (I currently use Atom for CSS/JS/Puppet, should try other languages)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Added CSV, TSV and JSON download options to Quarry. There’s another Webinar tomorrow by the Grantmaking team, and J-Mo asked for it. Streaming TSV and CSV implemented in a neat way, will write a blog post tomorrow about it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Started work on a ‘number of editors’ per country metric for WPDMZ, needs to be finished up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I feel a bit exhausted (physically and mentally) from the intense coding over the last few weeks, might have a few chill days to recharge myself. I’m growing old! :(&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for Aug 24, 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-aug-24-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 02:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-aug-24-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wooooo!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Moved &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yuvipanda/labsbooks&#34;&gt;labsbooks&lt;/a&gt; (described in &lt;a href=&#34;http://yuvi.in/blog/devlog-23-aug-2014/&#34;&gt;yesterday’s devlog&lt;/a&gt;) to use a shared readonly IPython virtualenv maintained by me. Also installed a bunch of modules people might want to use (SciPy, NumPy, Pandas, PyTables, matplotlib). Am considering just installing IPython notebook globally via puppet and using that, since that’ll enable users to just use the system packages. However, the version of IPython notebook from Ubuntu is ancient, so that’s probably a non-starter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Have a basic version of the IPython publishing process working! Any toollabs user can create a notebook by:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Creating a &lt;code&gt;~/notebooks&lt;/code&gt; folder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Doing a &lt;code&gt;chmod +x ~/notebooks&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Doing a &lt;code&gt;chmod +x ~&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Putting IPython notebooks into &lt;code&gt;~/notebooks&lt;/code&gt; (as &lt;code&gt;.ipynb&lt;/code&gt;) files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Going to &lt;code&gt;https://tools.wmflabs.org/notebooks/&amp;lt;user-shell-name&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;path-to-ipynb-file&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; Will have to do a bit more work before it can be considered ‘production grade’ (such as user pages, a nicer theme, etc, etc) BUT YAY GOOD START. It already caches the html output in Redis and invalidates with the &lt;code&gt;mtime&lt;/code&gt; of the file, so should be pretty quick.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Made the ssh tunneling process for &lt;code&gt;labsbooks&lt;/code&gt; purely python, without requiring the &lt;code&gt;ProxyCommand&lt;/code&gt;. This makes things simpler (and more portable!). I’ll need to work on securing this properly before I can publish it for broader use.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://lists.wikimedia.org/pipermail/analytics/2014-August/002437.html&#34;&gt;an email&lt;/a&gt; to the analytics mailing list about making public the ‘edits per country’ data. I hope to make this publicly available with enough granularity that not just me but others can use this for fun research as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://atom.io&#34;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; for puppet stuff, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/&#34;&gt;PyCharm&lt;/a&gt; for Python and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/&#34;&gt;IntelliJ&lt;/a&gt; for Java stuff, and that seems to be doing ok. They all have decent Vim keybindings as well, and good replacements for other functionality – and I might stick with Atom for a while to see how it goes :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 23 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-23-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 02:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-23-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in Glasgow! It was actually not very cold today, only cold! Progress.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Started working on my long-abandoned &lt;code&gt;labsbook&lt;/code&gt; project, which aims to make &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools.wmflabs.org&#34;&gt;Tool Labs&lt;/a&gt; a first class environment for people who want to run (and publish) &lt;a href=&#34;http://ipython.org/notebook.html&#34;&gt;iPython Notebooks&lt;/a&gt; while also being able to access the replica databases and the dumps. Doing this in a secure manner is kinda hard, but I think I’ve a neat solution that lets everyone run a personal iPython kernel on the Grid, access it from their local machine, and also publish it to the web from a standard location. So far, I’ve gotten my script to a point where it’ll setup an iPython environment for you if it doesn’t already exist, start the kernel if it isn’t already running, and tunnel the editing interface back to you to use! Things left to do include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devlog for Aug 22 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-aug-22-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 14:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-aug-22-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Was in Edinburgh again, missed writing it as I went along. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ported the code for the Wikipedia Android app automated builds to Python, and you can see it in action at &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.wmflabs.org/wikipedia-android-builds/&#34;&gt;http://tools.wmflabs.org/wikipedia-android-builds/&lt;/a&gt; now. It lets you download the latest build, and notes the last successful build time. Good enough :) It was originally in bash, and porting it to python allowed me to create a ‘fake’ API (just JSON blobs written to known locations in the file system). Next step is to write a helper app&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Atom experiment is coming along well. Am using it for most of my Puppet work these days. Should give LightTable another go as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That’s it!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devlog for 21 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-21-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 11:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-21-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Edinburgh! I’ve finally stopped spelling it as Edinborough!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Added ‘user group’ functionality to Quarry, and added a &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; user group that does what you would think it does. Will be assigned super, super sparingly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Found out that I’d have to explicitly specify charset of the database when I’m creating it or MySQL will default to a stupid charset. Forced all tables and columns to utf8 and that seems to have fixed a bunch of unicode issues. Yay?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Still facing occasional &lt;code&gt;MySQL server has gone away&lt;/code&gt; errors with SQLAlchemy for local MySQL instance, despite asking SQLAlchemy to recycle connections every hour or so. Reduced the recycle time to 10m, hopefully that helps.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Read Tony Hoare’s Turing Award speech from 1980, titled &lt;a href=&#34;http://zoo.cs.yale.edu/classes/cs422/2014/bib/hoare81emperor.pdf&#34;&gt;“The Emperor’s Old Clothes”&lt;/a&gt;. I think I should read more of these papers / speeches, helps keep perspective and ‘learn from history’. Lots of warnings against complexity seem to be a very common theme, and one I’ve also personally encountered many times. Recommend reading :)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;More DMZ work! Now running edits per country stats separated by mobile vs desktop for all countries for all wikipedias! EXCITING!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devlog for 20 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-20-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 03:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-20-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Woke up at 11AM again! w000t!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fixed a stupid bug in Quarry that made it fail if MySQL decided that a column you were selecting is a &lt;code&gt;Decimal&lt;/code&gt;. Fixed this in time for…&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Helped out with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/u/0/b/117126229120807344920/events/cngcjcmm1tcn1omqpalcm686044&#34;&gt;webinar&lt;/a&gt; from J-Mo for people to learn SQL and do research against Wikimedia stuff with Quarry! Went without a glitch mostly, so yay :) Oren asked for an API for Quarry, I’ll investigate ways to get that done&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Found that some queries against enwiki succeed on &lt;code&gt;s1.labsdb&lt;/code&gt; but not on &lt;code&gt;s4.labsdb&lt;/code&gt;. I attribute this to cache characteristics, and have switched Quarry to use s1 for now.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Did more work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Ironholds/WPDMZ&#34;&gt;DMZ&lt;/a&gt;, getting in place a runner / processor infrastructure and sqlite backed intermediary storage so I can write simpler code to get the data I want. Super excited to see how this goes. It’ll be much easier for me to add new queries now.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;More work on DMZ! I had a late night sprint and split edits by mobile and desktop (and was surprised by seeing how much lesser edits came from mobile). Next would be to gather up population and internet penetration data and then GO MAKE SOME GRAPHS, probably with iPython. I’m returning to making graphs for real after, what, 6 years or so? :) I was using C# and Excel then :) /nick ExcitedPanda&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also made some progress on our makeshift Android CI-ish build system for the Wikipedia app. Should be done soon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devlog for 19 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-19-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 11:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-19-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here we go again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://yuvi.in/blog/simple-python-packaging-debian-ubuntu/&#34;&gt;a small blog post&lt;/a&gt; talking about how to package python packages as debian packages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;More work on getting &lt;a href=&#34;https://graphite.readthedocs.org/en/latest/&#34;&gt;Graphite&lt;/a&gt; setup for Wikimedia Labs. Everything is up and running now (after a number of embarrassing typos). Need to figure out NAT rules to let labs machines talk to &lt;code&gt;labmon1001&lt;/code&gt;, and then it can start receiving data!!!1&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Got access to Wikimedia’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://hadoop.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Hadoop&lt;/a&gt; cluster, and ran my first &lt;a href=&#34;https://hive.apache.org/&#34;&gt;HIVE&lt;/a&gt; query ever! This is exciting :)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Made packages for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/appliedsec/pygeoip&#34;&gt;pygeoip&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tobie/ua-parser&#34;&gt;ua-parser&lt;/a&gt;. Having to make both trusty and precise packages was fun. I ended up building them on separate machines, but am sure there’s a simpler way.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Started doing some SQL about editors from different countries. Did you know that there are 2x as many edits to english wikipedia from India as from Germany? And that Wikidata has had 10x as many edits from Toollabs as from Germany (the largest contributing country)? I didn’t either! This is fun.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 18 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-18-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 12:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-18-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve started the habit of opening up a devlog post each morning and just filling it up as I go along. Let’s hope I can keep this up :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Merged a couple of Android patches. The app is getting better every day without too much involvement from me, and yay for that :) I’ve gotten closure over the Android app – it was fucking terrible, and now it is quite awesome. Need to write another post about that.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fixed annoying bug with mysql connections being reset in Quarry’s query runners after a few hours. I had fixed this earlier when I was using &lt;code&gt;pymysql&lt;/code&gt; directly with reconnect(ping=True), and assumed that switching to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sqlalchemy.org/&#34;&gt;SQLAlchemy&lt;/a&gt; would’ve fixed it for me automagically. &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.sqlalchemy.org/en/latest/faq.html#mysql-server-has-gone-away&#34;&gt;Apparently not&lt;/a&gt;. MySQL Y U SO BAD?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I have &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; access on &lt;code&gt;labmon1001&lt;/code&gt; in prod! First Wikimedia production cluster machine I have root on, and will spend time over the next few weeks setting it up to run graphite. Should be fun!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Getting slightly better at packaging python things. Packaged &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sidnei/txstatsd&#34;&gt;python-txstatsd&lt;/a&gt; with no lintian errors, and only a couple warnings :)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 17 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-17-mon-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 12:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-17-mon-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Devlogs again! Let’s see how long I can keep this one up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Been a whirlwind few months. I’m moving to the Wikimedia Ops team soon! The Wikipedia app has been released! Lots of excitement around, should do a bigger post sometime with details. This should just follow usual devlog format of stuff for the day&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Completed deployment of changing the results backend of &lt;a href=&#34;https://quarry.wmflabs.org&#34;&gt;Quarry&lt;/a&gt; to SQLite. That was a fun exercise, and I should write about that separately. Still have some unicode issues left (mostly from the MySQL side) that I’ve hacked around for now.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Quarry now uses a cron based query killer instead of relying on Celery. The day before I had force killed the celery deamons and this meant the query kill tasks didn’t run, leaving zombie queries behind. The simpler cron based killer won’t have this issue, since it’s super simple and does only one thing. The only reason I didn’t do this before was that I had not known about &lt;code&gt;SHOW PROCESSLIST&lt;/code&gt; before (yes, I suck). It seems to be working fine now, but doesn’t kill superseeded queries immediately. Should be interesting to figure out how to get that done properly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I’ve started trying out &lt;a href=&#34;https://atom.io&#34;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt; again. My previous attempt ended quickly when I ran into a bug which didn’t wrap text at all. A restart seems to have fixed that. The Vim keybindings are ‘ok’ – there’s no &lt;code&gt;hlsearch&lt;/code&gt;, which is painful, but I can live with it. I prefer the fuzzy finder in it to Ctrl-P in Vim.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Started working on making labs monitoring with graphite possible again. Our graphite / txstatsd roles weren’t meant to be run on trusty, so working on porting things to make sure they work fine on both. I’ve immensely come to appreciate ops over the last year or so, and am quite enjoying my work in that area :) I’ll probably be doing more of these over the next week, since Quarry has reached a nice state now and I await more usage before I spend more time on it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also did some code review on the Android app. It’s been chugging along quite happily these days :)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ran into a awake-when-he-should-not-have been &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ironholds.org/&#34;&gt;Oliver Keyes&lt;/a&gt; and we have conspired to start some &lt;a href=&#34;https://etherpad.wikimedia.org/p/flagellating-funnel&#34;&gt;researchy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Ironholds/WPDMZ&#34;&gt;things&lt;/a&gt;. I cleaned up some of the python code, and am writing out things to do. This should be fun!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devlog for Tuesday, September 24, 2013</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-tuesday-september-24-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 11:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-tuesday-september-24-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve given up on trying to make DevLogs really comprehensive and complete, and just try to make them – even if they are incomplete. Perhaps this will help me actually write more devlogs, and thus make it more comprehensive…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/course/progfun&#34;&gt;Functional Programming in Scala&lt;/a&gt; course today. I wanted to do it the last time, but did not find the time. This time will be different – I’m in a different spot mentally, and a big drain on my emotional / time resources (“college”) is no longer a factor. I’ve already gone through the first week’s lectures (most seem straight ports from &lt;a href=&#34;https://mitpress.mit.edu/sicp/&#34;&gt;SICP&lt;/a&gt;), and am 2/3 of my way through the assignments for the first week. Though I’m normally not fond of the typical types of exercises (“How many ways can you make change for this scenario?”), doing them functionally seems to be enough of a twist to keep me interested. The regular languages I seem to work with these days (Java, PHP, Puppet, Python and a bit of JS) aren’t exactly well tuned to the functional style of programming (except JS, but I don’t really do that much JS these days) – so going through this course and hopefully building something in Scala can exercise my ‘OMG HOLY SHIT THIS NEW THING IS AWESOME!!1’ muscles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devlog for Monday, Aug 26, 2013</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-for-monday-aug-26-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 13:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-for-monday-aug-26-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing new started. The UploadCampaigns &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/80782/&#34;&gt;API patch&lt;/a&gt; I &lt;a href=&#34;http://yuvi.in/blog/devlog-for-sun-aug-25-2013/&#34;&gt;talked about&lt;/a&gt; yesterday was fixed and merged. I also helped merge some of &lt;a href=&#34;http://marktraceur.info/&#34;&gt;MarkTraceur&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; JS cleanup patches to UploadWizard. And &lt;a href=&#34;https://brionv.com/log/&#34;&gt;Brion&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s big &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/81139/&#34;&gt;detail view patch&lt;/a&gt; for Android Commons app. Also another cleanup/api &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/81162/&#34;&gt;feature patch&lt;/a&gt; to UploadWizard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for Sun, Aug 25, 2013</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-for-sun-aug-25-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 23:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-for-sun-aug-25-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DevLogs have been something I&amp;rsquo;ve not been writing much of of late. Time to fix that!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;wlm-android-app&#34;&gt;WLM Android App&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spent some time &lt;a href=&#34;http://lists.wikimedia.org/pipermail/wikilovesmonuments/2013-August/006249.html&#34;&gt;reviving the WLM Android App&lt;/a&gt;. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t too hard, and am surprised at how well it still runs :) Some work still needed to update the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wikimedia/WLMMobile/commit/113d9abf7b675b147ece3f2be005ef1b6ba0e4cf#assets/www/js/campaigns-data.js&#34;&gt;templates&lt;/a&gt; and other metadata to refer to WLM2013 rather than WLM2012 – but that should not be too hard. The fact that it is an issue at all is simply because I ripped out all the Campaign related APIs a few weeks ago with my UploadCampaign rewrite.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First major feature to Commons deployed</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/first-major-feature-to-commons-deployed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 00:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/first-major-feature-to-commons-deployed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;https://mediawiki.org/wiki/User:Yuvipanda/Campaigns_namespace_proposal&#34;&gt;UploadWizard work&lt;/a&gt; has just been deployed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt; and my name is listed in the on site &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:Version&#34;&gt;credits&lt;/a&gt;. Special thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://marktraceur.info/&#34;&gt;Mark Traceur&lt;/a&gt; for code review!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This feels very, &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; nice :) Now to sneak more code into other extensions…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attempting to Secure Redis in a Multi Tenant environment</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/attempting-to-secure-redis-in-a-multi-tenant-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 23:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/attempting-to-secure-redis-in-a-multi-tenant-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When running &lt;a href=&#34;http://redis.io/&#34;&gt;Redis&lt;/a&gt; in a shared cluster/hosting environment (such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://wikitech.wikimedia.org/wiki/Nova_Resource:Tools/Help&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Tool Labs&lt;/a&gt;, on which I&amp;rsquo;ve been having fun doing a lot of work on), you would want to try to provide at least &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; guarantee of isolation for your keys from everyone else&amp;rsquo;s keys. Since Redis doesn&amp;rsquo;t do ACLs, this is problematic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This can be solved in a couple of ways&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;run-a-redis-instance-for-each-user&#34;&gt;Run a Redis instance for each user&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is simple enough to do – each user runs their own Redis instance, and has full access to it. Security is handled by setting a secret password, and running &lt;code&gt;redis-server&lt;/code&gt; as the user in question. Boom, secure!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: December 26, 2011 – Jan 3rd, 2012</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-26-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 01:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-26-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in Chennai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Moving yuvi.in to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://prgmr.com&#34;&gt;prgmr&lt;/a&gt; server. I want wordpress for my blog, but I don’t want to run MySQL. Solution? Keep blog where it is (with the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;http://webfaction.com&#34;&gt;webfaction&lt;/a&gt; people!) and use &lt;a href=&#34;http://nginx.org&#34;&gt;nginx&lt;/a&gt; to proxy requests to blog/. Seems to work, so yay!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rewrote tawp.in to use python/flask/memcached. Available on github. Replaced older node.js version&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reading through &lt;em&gt;The Art of Unix Programming&lt;/em&gt; on kindle. Amazing book so far.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fixed a few more bugs on Wikipedia App. I think I’ll keep ‘official’ Wiki related stuff off this, unless it’s big?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Partied along new year’s. Yay. Not particularly ‘dev’, but still :)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devlog: December 23, 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-23-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 02:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-23-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Worked the day first from Domlur bus terminus, and then from Exotel’s office (with @vijaysw).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Incorporated search results (rather than just suggestions) into the Wikipedia app. Was a slight bitch to get right, but after that have made a bunch of variants that the others are testing out to see which one feels good (Suggestion if exists, else search, or search alone). Took up most of my time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We put out a dud as RC3 for the Wikipedia app. A missing defaults statement. Lesson learnt: Test the entire process (uninstall -&amp;gt; install -&amp;gt; run -&amp;gt; test) before passing off RCs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;HyperJuice battery has arrived. Commence working out of random public places.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: December 21 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-21-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 23:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-21-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;livetrains work. Trying to move (minimal) build system to waf. Somewhat complicated, not as fluid as I’d like. Go to rake. Feel weird about starting from scratch, come back to waf. Not get anything done Another rake diversion. Final Makefile editing desperation. I give up – I need to spend atleast a day to get back on proper build tools. That day is not today.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Added feature to change font size to wikipedia app. That took almost a couple of days and ended up being less than 20 lines of code. First was trying to enable pinch and zoom, but only for an iframe – proved impossible. And then a long time of headwalling about how I’m not able to manipulate the DOM inside the iframe (despite code in other places being able to do it just fine (no crossdomain issues here)), I had given up and moved elsewhere. Finally brion suggested I try inserting a &lt;link&gt; into &lt;head&gt;, which actually did work. So much for the browser being sane&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;‘Refined’ the search behavior of the wikipedia app a bit more. Also got bit by a difference between zepto (that we use) and jQuery (whose docs I have to read, since zepto by itself seems to have no docs). Had to read through the code to fix it, and managed to.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Closed a *lot* of bugs. BOY THAT FEELS GREAT!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: December 11, 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-11-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 09:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-11-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Added UI for AssessmentLog [SelectionSifter]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Removed lots of dead code in SelectionSifter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Went to Bangalore Wikipedia Meetup. Was nice meeting people I knew online face to face. Talked about yenWikipedia, and learnt a lot about how article selection for offline wikipedia is done.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shot myself in the foot multiple times (over use of empty(), incomplete commit summaries and a tab/spaces issue). I’m rusty and it is showing. Shouldn’t be a problem anymore, though – because of you-know-what.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Built myself a local copy of mediawiki docs. No more annoying huge-images.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Got myself the solarized theme. And increased font size to normal levels (13pt). My eyes thank me.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fixed timestamp related bugs in SelectionSifter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devlog December 10, 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-10-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 18:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-10-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Looks like I’m going to be rewriting SelectionSifter’s UI a lot. No more QuickTemplates, as I found TablePager. Mediawik definitely needs to fix &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugzilla.wikimedia.org/show_bug.cgi?id=1&#34;&gt;Bug #1&lt;/a&gt; soon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Added proper i18n for SelectionSifter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Redid FilterRatings page completely.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Went through PhoneGap documentation, checked out state of its Photo handling API. Looks good.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Checked out &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Tpt/Wikipedia&#34;&gt;patch&lt;/a&gt; to official Wikipedia app that adds upload functionality. Needs lot more polish.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog December 7, 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-7-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 23:34:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-7-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Redid Blog template. Recategorized all blog posts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally enabled mobile banking on ICICI. Still need 8 days for Internet activation. Sigh.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ordered HyperJuice 60W battery + Airline Adapter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Read through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Template:WPBannerMeta&#34;&gt;WPBannerMeta&lt;/a&gt; template (and its subtemplates), figured out where to get the assessment markers in. Poof that was hard. These templates are perfect examples of ‘hacks’ – initially ‘designed’ for templating text, they’ve grown into homebrew programming languages that are worse than PHP. True evolution :)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Read through, replied to &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; detailed questions about MW development from the KovaiGeeks folks. Both me and Sumanah were amazed at the enthusiasm shown. Should be one fun workshop!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fixed arbit bugs in in SelectionSifter, moved away from anything in QueryPage&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Started using SparrowApp and WunderList. Amazing they are.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: December 5, 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-5-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 20:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-5-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Am migrating to per-day posts now. More granularity + I can fit more info in. The ultimate aim of the DevLog is to keep me on my toes and make sure I don’t relapse into no-productivity hellholes. Daily DevLogs should do a better job at them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spent some more time trying to get Kiwix to compile under OS X. Macports issue fixed, but more issues persist. It’s one damn complicated build system :| Not to mention that OS X sucks balls. Still no luck.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Moved my extension from GPoC to SelectionSifter, as picked by Sumanah (and remembered by Siebrand)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Added more content to my ‘&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/User:Yuvipanda/How_to_become_a_mediaWiki_hacker&#34;&gt;How to become a mediawiki hacker&lt;/a&gt;‘ page. Outline in shape, needs content. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/How_to_become_a_MediaWiki_hacker&#34;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; is the page I am rewriting)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cleaned up my Mediawiki.org &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/User:Yuvipanda&#34;&gt;userpage&lt;/a&gt;. Added stuff I’m working on there. Archived lots of older pages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Published &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/yuvipanda/livetrains&#34;&gt;livetrains&lt;/a&gt; to GitHub. As expected Kishore cleaned it up a bit. Have figured out how to do the time modelling (Thanks lifeeth!). Should finish up when I get time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Need.To.Be.More.Productive!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devlog December 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 21:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With me back to a place where I can be completely open about what code I am writing (yay!), I think it’s time I restart &lt;a href=&#34;http://yuvi.in/blog/tag/devlog/&#34;&gt;my devlog&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last time, I was using my old blogging engine, and hand-wrote them in a markdown file on my netbook. Things have changed a lot since then, and this time I’ll be directly writing/publishing them daily from WordPress&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;dec-4&#34;&gt;Dec 4&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I finally grokked Indexes in databases. It all makes perfect sense now. Yay! (And this was thanks to being able to read on the Kindle, so yay for that too). Nothing productive done though.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devlog May 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-may-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 13:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-may-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;may-25-june-13&#34;&gt;May 25-June 13&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Loads of things happened.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finished/polished up ShortUrl. Pending review. Would go into not just tawiki, but possibly all wmf wikis. YAY!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moved to a dual monitor setup. Dual 23″ Monitors, one Samsung LED and one Acer LCD. Also moved to 8G of RAM. VMs are much less painful now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Did a few back/forths with the GSoC extension architecture. It’s still blocking, so working with the non-blocking parts of GSoC now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: April 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-april-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 01:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-april-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve started keeping devlogs, recording productive activity every day in an attempt to publicly shame myself into doing productive things. This is the delayed april edition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;apr-30&#34;&gt;Apr 30&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Impromptu talk at ChennaiPy meet. Then fun discussions at Nerd Dinner. No code, sadly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;apr-29&#34;&gt;Apr 29&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Google Instant mostly works on yenWikipedia. Made a release. More exams.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;apr-22-8211-28&#34;&gt;Apr 22 – 28&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nothing much done. Exams and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tecoholic forked yenWikipedia and created a Firefox extension. Adding features faster than me. Yay! :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: Mar 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-mar-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 21:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-mar-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve started keeping devlogs, recording productive activity every day in an attempt to publicly shame myself into doing productive things. This is the delayed march edition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;mar-20-8211-31&#34;&gt;Mar 20 – 31&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More contract work for more money.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My dump patch to meidawiki got commited, then blasted during Code Review. This is what I get for trusting other people’s code blindly, especially after 5 years. Lesson learnt. Fixed all issues, and now waiting for a review before commit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: Feb 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-feb-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 21:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-feb-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’ve started keeping devlogs, recording everyday productive activity in an attempt to publicly shaming myselfinto doing something productive everyday. This is the delayed february editin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Links: &lt;a href=&#34;http://32hourstartup.com/&#34;&gt;32HourStartup&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://pitivi.org&#34;&gt;PiTiVi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://tedxssn.com&#34;&gt;TEDxSSN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;feb-26&#34;&gt;Feb 26&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Initial work on Busroutes.in wiki import script.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;feb-25&#34;&gt;Feb 25&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Audio Save Dialog mostly works now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;feb-23&#34;&gt;Feb 23&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Started implementing Audio Name dialog box in PiTiVi. Dad fixed laptop – new Ethernet port, and working speakers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;feb-22&#34;&gt;Feb 22&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Started doing layouts for WhyKCGRocks.com&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
