<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>personal on Yuvi Panda</title>
    <link>https://words.yuvi.in/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in personal on Yuvi Panda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 13:59:46 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://words.yuvi.in/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Note Taking Part I</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/note-taking-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 13:59:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/note-taking-part-i/</guid>
      <description>I am trying to find a nice way to keep thoughts, ideas and notes outside my head for a few months now. I worked my way through many applications, trying to use the system they promote as the basis for my own. Along the journey, I got a better sense of what was important to me in such an application. I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through the various applications I&amp;rsquo;ve tried, along with the criteria I&amp;rsquo;ve developed by the end</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I miss blogging too</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/miss-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 11:25:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/miss-blogging/</guid>
      <description>This person misses blogs a lot. So do I. I made many frients, built myself a platform, and expressed myself in ways I do not feel like I can anymore on my various blogs. Some of them are lost to time, but some are there if you know how to find it.
Part of it was where my life was - I had time, nobody physically nearby I jived with, and a lot of angst.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my first protest</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/first-protest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 22:37:21 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/first-protest/</guid>
      <description>I went to the protests at SFO last weekend. It was the first real set of protests I&amp;rsquo;ve been to. I write this to attempt to capture a sliver of what I felt that day.
I was there for about 10h on day 1, and came home exhausted. I went back on Day 2, and this time stayed for much shorter period of time (~4h?) before heading back home.
To everyone who was at the protest even if it does not directly affect you yet - thank you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Greatest Fear – ‘Flash and Fade’</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/greatest-fear-flash-fade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 03:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/greatest-fear-flash-fade/</guid>
      <description>HP:MORis an awesome fanfic that anyone intent on improving themselves should read. It’s a bit like HHG2G – you don’t read for the storyline (which is jumbled) but for the characters, wit, rationality and humor. Quite a few of those things hit very close to home – if you are a geek, they would perhaps to you too. Highly reccomended.
Of the many quotable parts of that book, here’s one little nugget I found:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Sriram Krishnan (5 years old)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/interview-sriram-krishnan-5-years-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 15:50:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/interview-sriram-krishnan-5-years-old/</guid>
      <description>5 years ago, I was in my 10th and new on the Internet. I had been coding for about 5-6 years already, but mostly with TurboC and VB6/C# (thanks to MSDN CDs I steal from Sudar). And then this interview happened and pushed me farther out into geekland :)
Presenting a reprint from 2006, my interview with Sriram Krishnan, then Microsoftie. Note that the opinions here are of a Sriram 5 years ago, and do not necessarily represent what he thinks now :D And the questions are obviously the questions a younger, naiver (and stupider) Yuvi would’ve asked, so bear with that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
