<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yuvi Panda</title>
    <link>http://words.yuvi.in/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yuvi Panda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 23:23:52 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.yuvi.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>systemd simple containment for GUI applications &amp; shells</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/systemd-simple-containment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 23:23:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/systemd-simple-containment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I earlier had &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.yuvi.in/post/systemd-gui-applications/&#34;&gt;a vaguely working setup&lt;/a&gt; for making sure browsers, shells and other applications don&amp;rsquo;t eat all RAM / CPU on my machine with systemd + sudo + shell scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a hacky solution, and also had complications when used to launch shells. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t passing in all the environment varialbes it should, causing interesting-to-debug issues. &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; rules were complex, and hard to do securely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had also been looking for an excuse to learn more Golang, so I ended up writing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yuvipanda/systemd-simple-containment&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;systemd-simple-containment&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;code&gt;ssc&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a simple golang application that produces a binary that can be &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Setuid&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;setuid&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt;, and thus get around all our &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; complexity, at the price of having to be very, very careful about the code. Fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s short enough (~100 lines) and &lt;code&gt;systemd-run&lt;/code&gt; helps it keep the following invariants:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It will never spawn any executable as any user other than the &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; uid / gid of the user calling the binary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow arbitrary systemd &lt;code&gt;properties&lt;/code&gt; to be set, ensuring a more limited attack surface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this is the first time I&amp;rsquo;m playing with setuid and with Go, so I probably fucked something up. I feel ok enough about my understanding of real and effective uids for now to use it myself, but not to recommend it to other people. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll be confident enough say that soon :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By using a real programming language, I also easily get commandline flags for sharing tty or not (so I can use the same program for launching GUI &amp;amp; interactive terminal applications), pass all environment variables through (which can&amp;rsquo;t be just standard child inheritence, since &lt;code&gt;systemd-run&lt;/code&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t work that way) &amp;amp; the ability to setuid (you can&amp;rsquo;t do that easily to a script).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was sure I&amp;rsquo;d hate writing go because of the constant &lt;code&gt;if err != nil&lt;/code&gt; checks, but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t bothered me that much. I would like to write more Go, to get a better feel for it. This code is too short to like a language, but I definitely hate it less :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, now I can launch GUI applications with &lt;code&gt;ssc -tty=false -isolation=strict firefox&lt;/code&gt; and it does the right thing. I currently have available &lt;code&gt;-isolation=strict&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;-isolation=relaxed&lt;/code&gt;, the former performing stronger sandboxing (NoNewPrivileges, PrivateTmp) than the latter (just MemoryMax). i&amp;rsquo;ll slowly add more protections here, but just keep two modes (ideally).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Gnome Terminal shell command is now &lt;code&gt;ssc -isolation=relaxed /bin/bash -i&lt;/code&gt; and it works great :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am pretty happy with &lt;code&gt;ssc&lt;/code&gt; as it exists now. Only thing I now want to do is to be able to use it from the GNOME launcher (I am using GNOME3 with gnome-shell). Apparently &lt;em&gt;shortcuts&lt;/em&gt; are no longer cool and hence pretty hard to create in modern desktop environments :| I shall keep digging!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systemd gui applications</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/systemd-gui-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 20:47:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/systemd-gui-applications/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jessfraz.com&#34;&gt;Jessie Frazelle&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s amazing setup&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jessfraz.com/post/ultimate-linux-on-the-desktop/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jessfraz.com/post/docker-containers-on-the-desktop/&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jessfraz.com/post/runc-containers-on-the-desktop/&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; for running GUI applications in docker containers, I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do something similar. However, I want to install things on my computer - not in docker images. So what I wanted was just isolation (no more Chrome / Firefox freezing my laptop), not images. I&amp;rsquo;m also not as awesome (or knowledgeable!) as Jess, so will have to naturally settle for less&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I am doing it in systemd!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before proceeding, I want to warn y&amp;rsquo;all that I don&amp;rsquo;t entirely know what I am doing. Don&amp;rsquo;t take any of this as security advice, since I don&amp;rsquo;t entirely understand X&amp;rsquo;s security model. Works fine for me though!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gui-applications&#34;&gt;GUI applications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started out using a simple systemd &lt;a href=&#34;https://fedoramagazine.org/systemd-template-unit-files/&#34;&gt;templated service&lt;/a&gt; to launch GUI applications, but soon realized that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freedesktop.org/software/systemd/man/systemd-run.html&#34;&gt;systemd-run&lt;/a&gt; is probably the better way. So I&amp;rsquo;ve a simple script, &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/bin/safeapp&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;#!/bin/bash
exec sudo systemd-run  \
    -p CPUQuota=100% \
    -p MemoryMax=70% \
    -p WorkingDirectory=$(pwd) \
    -p PrivateTmp=yes \
    -p NoNewPrivileges=yes \
    --setenv DISPLAY=${DISPLAY} \
    --setenv DBUS_SESSION_BUS_ADDRESS=${DBUS_SESSION_BUS_ADDRESS} \
    --uid ${USER} \
    --gid ${USER} \
    --quiet \
    &amp;quot;$1&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can run &lt;code&gt;safeapp /opt/firefox/firefox&lt;/code&gt; now and it&amp;rsquo;ll start firefox inside a nice systemd unit with a 70% Memory usage cap and CPU usage of at most 1 CPU. There&amp;rsquo;s also other minimal security stuff applied - &lt;code&gt;NoNewPrivileges&lt;/code&gt; being the most important one. I want to get &lt;code&gt;ProtectSystem&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;ReadWriteDirectories&lt;/code&gt; going too, but there seems to be a bug in &lt;code&gt;systemd-run&lt;/code&gt; that doesn&amp;rsquo;t let it parse &lt;code&gt;ProtectSystem&lt;/code&gt; properly&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/systemd/systemd/issues/3851&#34;&gt;an annoying bug&lt;/a&gt; in systemd v231 (which is what my current system has) - you can&amp;rsquo;t set &lt;code&gt;CPUQuotas&lt;/code&gt; over 100% (aka &amp;gt; 1 CPU core). This is annoying if you want to give each application 3 of your 4 cores (which is what I want). Next version of Ubuntu has v232, so my GUI applications will just have to do with an aggregate of 1 full core until then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two environment variables seem to be all that&amp;rsquo;s necessary for X applications to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, this might ask you for your password. I&amp;rsquo;ll clean this up into a nice non-bash script hopefully soon, and make all of these better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, &lt;em&gt;it works&lt;/em&gt;! I can now open sketchy websites with scroll hijacking without fear it&amp;rsquo;ll kill my machine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cli&#34;&gt;CLI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted each tab in my terminal to be its own systemd service, so they all get equitable amount of  CPU time &amp;amp; can&amp;rsquo;t crash machine by themselves with OOM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve this script as &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/bin/safeshell&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;`#!/bin/bash
exec sudo systemd-run \
    -p CPUQuota=100% \
    -p MemoryMax=70% \
    -p WorkingDirectory=$(pwd) \
    --uid yuvipanda \
    --gid yuvipanda \
    --quiet \
    --tty \
    /bin/bash -i
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;--tty&lt;/code&gt; is magic here, and does the right things wrt passing the tty that GNOME terminal is passing in all the way to the shell. Now, my login command (set under profile preferences &amp;gt; command in gnome-terminal) is &lt;code&gt;sudo /usr/local/bin/safeshell&lt;/code&gt;. In addition, I add the following line to &lt;code&gt;/etc/sudoers&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;%sudo ALL = (root) NOPASSWD:SETENV: /usr/local/bin/safeshell
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This + just specifying the username directly in &lt;code&gt;safeshell&lt;/code&gt; are both hacks that make me cringe a little. I need to either fully understand how sudo&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;-E&lt;/code&gt; works, or use this as an opportunity to learn more Go and make a setuid binary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-do&#34;&gt;To do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ ] Generalize this to not need hacks (either with better sudo usage or a setuid binary)
[ ] Investigate adding more security related options.
[ ] Make these work with desktop / dock icons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d normally have just never written this post, on account of &amp;lsquo;oh no, it is imperfect&amp;rsquo; or something like that. However, that also seems to have come in the way of ability to find joy in learning simple things :D So I shall follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://jvns.ca/&#34;&gt;b0rk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s lead in spending time &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.yuvi.in/post/things-to-learn/&#34;&gt;learning&lt;/a&gt; for fun again :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>things to learn</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/things-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 15:27:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/things-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Keeping a running list of things I want to learn!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to use org mode properly? Should I use it for notes over markdown?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do linux network namespaces work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to run GUI apps with systemd?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What exactly is a &amp;lsquo;tty&amp;rsquo;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does HTTP2 actually work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do X509 / TLS certificates work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to use cgroups directly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I just use emacs terminals for all my terminal needs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does NFS work, and why is it so crappy?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does ssh work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does mosh work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do contact lenses work? HOW DO LENSES WORK?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know of resources that&amp;rsquo;ll help me learn these things, do let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moving to hugo</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/moving-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 23:46:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/moving-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m attempting to now blog at &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.yuvi.in&#34;&gt;http://words.yuvi.in&lt;/a&gt;, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt; rather than wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, IRC, Twitter &amp;amp; WhatsApp have ruined my public writing. I shall now slowly attempt to bring that back :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>liberal software</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/liberal-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 22:45:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/liberal-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/i3nJR7PNgI4?ecver=1&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran into this thought provoking though when randomly attempting to relax this weekend. There&amp;rsquo;s a summary at &lt;a href=&#34;https://lwn.net/Articles/712376/&#34;&gt;LWN&lt;/a&gt; if you do not want to watch the talk - but as the lwn summarizer admits, the video definitely conveys things that are hard to capture on text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core takeaway for me is to think about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what is the future of free and open-source software? The answer was: it has no future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems somehow connected to &amp;lsquo;democratizing programming&amp;rsquo;, which I had earlier given a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rEyqVXzCJJc&#34;&gt;talk about&lt;/a&gt;. Somehow, it feels like there needs to be an update / rebirth of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html&#34;&gt;GNU Freedoms&lt;/a&gt; for the world we live in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my first protest</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/first-protest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 22:37:21 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/first-protest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to the protests at SFO last weekend. It was the first real set of protests I&amp;rsquo;ve been to. I write this to attempt to capture a sliver of what I felt that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was there for about 10h on day 1, and came home exhausted. I went back on Day 2, and this time stayed for much shorter period of time (~4h?) before heading back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To everyone who was at the protest even if it does not directly affect you yet - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the wonderful amazing women of color who were leading the protest - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;. You are an inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the brass band and the troupe of drummers who showed up - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the people I already know from other contexts who I ran into at the protest - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To those who were protesting for the first time in their lives (as I was) - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the fucking ACLU - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;! I&amp;rsquo;ll send you all the money I can :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the people who provided infrastructure (food, water, snacks, first aid, printers, internet, etc) - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the journalists who covered this - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up that saturday feeling very depressed, angry, and helpless. By sunday night, I was only depressed and angry - but not helpless. The number and variety of people at the protests was very heartwarming, and made me feel distinctly not alone. Before going I was not sure what going to a protest accomplishes. I still do not know - but I know it gave me hope and restored my sense of agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I promise I&amp;rsquo;ll continue doing all I can, even and especially when it is about things that do not affect me yet. I hope you do too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What hurts the victim most is not the cruelty of the oppressor but the silence of the bystander&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- from a sign at the protest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>making twitter useful again</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/making-twitter-useful-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 22:17:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/making-twitter-useful-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve unfollowed everyone I follow on Twitter, and am slowly starting back up from scratch. I&amp;rsquo;m only going to follow people who are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Underrepresented people in Tech (as broadly construed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journalists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it. I&amp;rsquo;ll follow back friends I&amp;rsquo;m not otherwise in contact with as well, but might take a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had this for a few days and am already enjoying using it far more than I did before. A lot of the people I&amp;rsquo;m following now I did not know before, and the vibe is totally different. I&amp;rsquo;m able to understand and appreciate things I was not able to before. I know this is a bubble, but it is certainly a different bubble than the one I was in before. Bubbles also intersect - I&amp;rsquo;ve interactions with other types of people elsewhere, just not on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I unfollowed you, don&amp;rsquo;t take it personally! DM me for a phone number you can use for Signal / WhatsApp / Telegram - that&amp;rsquo;s how 90% of my social activities seem to happen these days anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;h/t to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaijin.com/&#34;&gt;Jorm&lt;/a&gt; for the idea of targetted following!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;ve also setup &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/leechblock/&#34;&gt;LeechBlock&lt;/a&gt; to only allow me 5mins of Twitter every 2h, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have the twitter app on my phone. I wish there was a leechblock type thing for my Phone tho.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>