<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Yuvi Panda</title>
    <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Yuvi Panda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 23:46:17 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://words.yuvi.in/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>moving to hugo</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/moving-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 23:46:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/moving-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m attempting to now blog at &lt;a href=&#34;http://words.yuvi.in&#34;&gt;http://words.yuvi.in&lt;/a&gt;, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt; rather than wordpress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, IRC, Twitter &amp;amp; WhatsApp have ruined my public writing. I shall now slowly attempt to bring that back :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>liberal software</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/liberal-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 22:45:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/liberal-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/i3nJR7PNgI4?ecver=1&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran into this thought provoking though when randomly attempting to relax this weekend. There&amp;rsquo;s a summary at &lt;a href=&#34;https://lwn.net/Articles/712376/&#34;&gt;LWN&lt;/a&gt; if you do not want to watch the talk - but as the lwn summarizer admits, the video definitely conveys things that are hard to capture on text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core takeaway for me is to think about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what is the future of free and open-source software? The answer was: it has no future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems somehow connected to &amp;lsquo;democratizing programming&amp;rsquo;, which I had earlier given a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rEyqVXzCJJc&#34;&gt;talk about&lt;/a&gt;. Somehow, it feels like there needs to be an update / rebirth of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html&#34;&gt;GNU Freedoms&lt;/a&gt; for the world we live in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my first protest</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/first-protest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 22:37:21 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/first-protest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to the protests at SFO last weekend. It was the first real set of protests I&amp;rsquo;ve been to. I write this to attempt to capture a sliver of what I felt that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was there for about 10h on day 1, and came home exhausted. I went back on Day 2, and this time stayed for much shorter period of time (~4h?) before heading back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To everyone who was at the protest even if it does not directly affect you yet - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the wonderful amazing women of color who were leading the protest - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;. You are an inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the brass band and the troupe of drummers who showed up - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the people I already know from other contexts who I ran into at the protest - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To those who were protesting for the first time in their lives (as I was) - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the fucking ACLU - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;! I&amp;rsquo;ll send you all the money I can :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the people who provided infrastructure (food, water, snacks, first aid, printers, internet, etc) - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the journalists who covered this - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up that saturday feeling very depressed, angry, and helpless. By sunday night, I was only depressed and angry - but not helpless. The number and variety of people at the protests was very heartwarming, and made me feel distinctly not alone. Before going I was not sure what going to a protest accomplishes. I still do not know - but I know it gave me hope and restored my sense of agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I promise I&amp;rsquo;ll continue doing all I can, even and especially when it is about things that do not affect me yet. I hope you do too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What hurts the victim most is not the cruelty of the oppressor but the silence of the bystander&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- from a sign at the protest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>making twitter useful again</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/making-twitter-useful-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 22:17:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/making-twitter-useful-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve unfollowed everyone I follow on Twitter, and am slowly starting back up from scratch. I&amp;rsquo;m only going to follow people who are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Underrepresented people in Tech (as broadly construed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journalists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it. I&amp;rsquo;ll follow back friends I&amp;rsquo;m not otherwise in contact with as well, but might take a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had this for a few days and am already enjoying using it far more than I did before. A lot of the people I&amp;rsquo;m following now I did not know before, and the vibe is totally different. I&amp;rsquo;m able to understand and appreciate things I was not able to before. I know this is a bubble, but it is certainly a different bubble than the one I was in before. Bubbles also intersect - I&amp;rsquo;ve interactions with other types of people elsewhere, just not on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I unfollowed you, don&amp;rsquo;t take it personally! DM me for a phone number you can use for Signal / WhatsApp / Telegram - that&amp;rsquo;s how 90% of my social activities seem to happen these days anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;h/t to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gaijin.com/&#34;&gt;Jorm&lt;/a&gt; for the idea of targetted following!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;ve also setup &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/leechblock/&#34;&gt;LeechBlock&lt;/a&gt; to only allow me 5mins of Twitter every 2h, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have the twitter app on my phone. I wish there was a leechblock type thing for my Phone tho.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>