<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Yuvi Panda</title>
    <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Yuvi Panda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 02:15:15 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://words.yuvi.in/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JupyterHub for all tools</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/hub-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 02:15:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/hub-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>JupyterHub was designed to provide multi-user access to Classic Jupyter notebook and JupyterLab, running on machines far away with access to data &amp;amp; compute your local machines don&amp;rsquo;t have. However, there are a lot of users this leaves out - R users on RStudio, folks who prefer ssh based interfaces, people on local IDEs like vscode or pycharm, etc. We trust that these users know better than &amp;lsquo;us&amp;rsquo; developers &amp;amp; admins what user interface works best for them, and make sure that our JupyterHub setups work for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kbatch: sbatch, but for kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/kbatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 13:40:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/kbatch/</guid>
      <description>Submitting &amp;lsquo;non-interactive&amp;rsquo; jobs that can run independent of a user&amp;rsquo;s current session on a JupyterHub is a pressing problem. There are many many solutions to this, but I think there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of value in having an extremely simple solution that solves exactly one extremely well defined problem.
We will only consider JupyterHubs running on top of Kubernetes, since that has all the actual capabilities we need to solve this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a &#34;Production Ready&#34; TLJH</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/production-tljh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 17:09:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/production-tljh/</guid>
      <description>The Littlest JupyterHub is an extremely capable hub distribution that I&amp;rsquo;d recommend for situations where you expect, on average, under 100 active users.
Why not Kubernetes? The primary reason to use Zero to JupyterHub on k8s over TLJH in cases with smaller number of users would be to reduce costs - Kubernetes can spin down nodes when not in use. However, you&amp;rsquo;ll always have at least one node running - for the hub / proxy pods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access dask-kubernetes clusters running on a cloud from your local machine</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/dask-local-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 13:27:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/dask-local-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>You can run your Jupyter Notebook locally, and connect easily to a remote dask-kubernetes cluster on a cloud-based Kubernetes Cluster with the help of kubefwd. This notebook will show you an example of how to do so. While this example is a Jupyter Notebook, the code will work any local python medium - REPL, IDE (vscode), or just plain ol&#39; .py files
Latest executable version of this notebook can be found in this repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check if an organization is using GSuite</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/google-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 17:01:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/google-domain/</guid>
      <description>I needed to find out if an organization was using GSuite for their emails, so I can allow their users to login to a JupyterHub I was setting up. I use Google Auth in other places, so I wanted to find out if this organization was using GSuite.
I could&amp;rsquo;ve just asked them, but where&amp;rsquo;s the fun in that? Instead, you can use dig to find out!
For example, if I were to test berkeley.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Being an &#39;Entitled User&#39;</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/on-being-entitled-user/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 12:34:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/on-being-entitled-user/</guid>
      <description>Entitled users burn out maintainers. While my massive burning out wasn&amp;rsquo;t directly related, it didn&amp;rsquo;t help either. For a lot of other maintainers, it has been a primary source of burnout. This is an unfortunate reality of our time. There are a ton of stories from maintainers out there -see this for a recent example. Not going to rehash that.
However, I&amp;rsquo;ve recently found myself on the &amp;lsquo;other side&amp;rsquo; of this coin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note taking: Why bother?</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/note-taking-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 14:05:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/note-taking-why/</guid>
      <description>Talking to Ankur Sethi made me think more clearly about why I want note-taking, bookmarking setups.
I am trying to stop feeling so overwhelmed by moving things out of my puny brain.
The solution to this is two fold.
 Commit to and do fewer things. Already working on this. Be more efficient in the things you are doing.  A few years ago I gave up on chasing efficiency gains because they were all so marginal (hello, maintaining a super customized .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note Taking II - Retaining consumed content</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/note-taking-ii-bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 11:13:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/note-taking-ii-bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>In conversation with Nirbheek about my blog post on note taking, he said something like &amp;lsquo;my system of knowledge has holes, and I lose track of stuff I learnt because of that&amp;rsquo;. This was slightly complementary to my earlier quest - the outliner helped me in structuring how I thought and produced content. However, a bookmarking system will help me consume and retain knowledge. Both need to be integrated, but I currently had only one half of the puzzle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note Taking Part I</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/note-taking-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 13:59:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/note-taking-part-i/</guid>
      <description>I am trying to find a nice way to keep thoughts, ideas and notes outside my head for a few months now. I worked my way through many applications, trying to use the system they promote as the basis for my own. Along the journey, I got a better sense of what was important to me in such an application. I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through the various applications I&amp;rsquo;ve tried, along with the criteria I&amp;rsquo;ve developed by the end</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I miss blogging too</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/miss-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 11:25:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/miss-blogging/</guid>
      <description>This person misses blogs a lot. So do I. I made many frients, built myself a platform, and expressed myself in ways I do not feel like I can anymore on my various blogs. Some of them are lost to time, but some are there if you know how to find it.
Part of it was where my life was - I had time, nobody physically nearby I jived with, and a lot of angst.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog 2018 12 26</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/devlog-2018-12-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 10:23:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/devlog-2018-12-26/</guid>
      <description>Physical activity I walked for about 6 miles yesterday evening, after doing 3-4 miles each day for about 2-3 days before. The roads were empty, and it was lovely. I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to maybe 6-10 hours of Deborah Frances-White in the last week or so, split between The Guilty Feminist and Global Pillage. Next time though, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try listen to podcasts less &amp;amp; observe my surroundings more. I am doing this (plus PT) to rehab my knee mostly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog 2018 12 24</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/devlog-2018-12-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 10:51:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/devlog-2018-12-24/</guid>
      <description>Gracefully exiting asyncio application Continuing yesterday&amp;rsquo;s work on my simple supervisor library, I continued trying to propagate signals cleanly to child processes before exiting. I remembered that it isn&amp;rsquo;t enough to just propagate signals - you also have to actually reap them. This meant waiting for wait calls on them to return.
I had a task running concurrently that is waiting on these processes. So &amp;lsquo;all&amp;rsquo; I had to do was make sure the application does not exit until these tasks are done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog 2018 December 23</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/devlog-2018-12-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 19:44:53 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/devlog-2018-12-23/</guid>
      <description>I have enjoyed keeping running logs of my coding work (devlogs) in the past, and am going to start doing those again now.
This &amp;lsquo;holiday&amp;rsquo; season, I am spending time teaching myself skills I sortof know about but do not have a deep understanding of.
JupyterLab extension I spent the first part of the day (before I started devlogging) working on finishing up a jupyterlab extension I started the day before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freedoms for Open Source Software users in the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/oss-in-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 22:41:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/oss-in-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>This post is from conversations with Matt Rocklin and others at the PANGEO developer meeting at NCAR
Today, almost all of &amp;lsquo;the cloud&amp;rsquo; is run by ruthlessly competitive hypercapitalist large scale organizations. This is great &amp;amp; terrible.
When writing open source applications that primarily run on the cloud, I try to make sure my users (primarily people deploying my software for their users) have the following freedoms:
 They can run the software on any cloud provider they choose to They can run the software on a bunch of computers they physically own, with the help of other open source software only  Ensuring these freedoms for my users requires the following restrictions on me:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aug 2018 Work Plan</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/aug-2018-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 18:32:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/aug-2018-plan/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing up monthly &amp;lsquo;work plans&amp;rsquo; to plan what work I&amp;rsquo;m trying to do every month, and do a retrospective after to see how much I got done. I work across a variety of open source projects with ambiguous responsibilities, so work planning isn&amp;rsquo;t very set. This has proven to be somewhat quite stressful for everyone involved. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if this helps!
JupyterCon JupyterCon is in NYC towards the end of August, and it is going to set the pace for a bunch of stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conda Constructor Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/conda-constructor-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 22:43:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/conda-constructor-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by conversations with Nick Bollweg and Matt Rocklin, I experimented with using conda constructor as the installer for The Littlest JupyterHub. Theoretically, it fit the bill perfectly - I wanted a way to ship arbitrary packages in multiple languages (python &amp;amp; node) in an easy to install self-contained way, didn&amp;rsquo;t want to make debian packages &amp;amp; wanted to use a tool that people in the Jupyter ecosystem were familiar with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Littlest Jupyterhub</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/the-littlest-jupyterhub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 13:14:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/the-littlest-jupyterhub/</guid>
      <description>This idea comes from brainstorming along with Lindsey Heagy, Carol Willing, Tim Head &amp;amp; Nick Bollweg at the Jupyter Team Meeting 2018. Most of the good ideas are theirs! The name is inspired by one of favorite TV series of one of my favorite people.
I really love the idea of JupyterHub distributions - opinionated combination of components that target a specific use case. The Zero to JupyterHub distribution is awesome &amp;amp; works for most people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubectl verbose logging tricks</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/kubectl-rbac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 15:15:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/kubectl-rbac/</guid>
      <description>Recently I had to write some code that had to call the kubernetes API directly, without any language wrappers. While there is pretty good reference docs, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go and construct all the JSON manually in my programming language.
I discovered that kubectl&amp;rsquo;s -v parameter is very useful for this! With this, I can do the following:
 Perform the actions I need to perform with just kubectl commands Pass -v=8 to kubectl when doing this, and this will print all the HTTP traffic (requests and responses!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 16:29:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/2017/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t done a &amp;lsquo;year in retrospective&amp;rsquo; publicly for a long time, but after reading Alice Goldfuss&#39; 2017 year in review decided to do one for me too!
This is a very filtered view - there are lots of important people &amp;amp; events in 2017 that are not contained here, and that is ok.
Professional   New Job
I finished around 6-ish years at the Wikimedia Foundation, and joined UC Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s Data Science Division early in the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why repo2docker? Why not s2i?</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/why-not-s2i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 01:23:54 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/why-not-s2i/</guid>
      <description>The wonderful Graham Dumpleton asked on twitter why we built an entirely new tool (repo2docker) instead of using OpenShift&amp;rsquo;s cool source2image tool.
This is a very good question, and not a decision we made lightly. This post lays out some history, and explains the reasons we decided to stop using s2i. s2i is still a great tool for most production use cases, and you should use it if you&amp;rsquo;re building anything like a PaaS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>maintainerati 2017</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/maintainerati-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 23:15:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/maintainerati-2017/</guid>
      <description>I was at maintainerati today, which was super fun &amp;amp; quite intense! I highly appreciate GitHub &amp;amp; the individuals involved in making it happen!
Here&amp;rsquo;s my key takeaways from this (and several other conversations over the last few weeks leading up to this):
 I am now a maintainer, which is quite a different thing from a core contributor or just a contributor. The power dynamics are very different, and so are the responsibilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>designing data intensive applications</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/designing-data-intensive-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 22:47:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/designing-data-intensive-applications/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading Designing Data Intensive Applications book &amp;amp; am using this post to keep notes!
I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up ideas on scaling systems through the years, but never actually sat down to actually study them semi-formally. This seems like a great start to it!
It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big book, and it&amp;rsquo;s gonna take me a while to go through it :) Will update these notes as I go! Trying to do a chapter a week!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>think os</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/think-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 11:41:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/think-os/</guid>
      <description>Following a trail from a wonderful Julia Evans post led me to Allen Downey&amp;rsquo;s nice textbook manifesto. Also led me to the nice Think OS book, which seems like a super nice introduction to Operating System principles.
It is short enough (~100 pages) that I wanted to read through it. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a good chunk of time absorbing how Operating Systems work by dint of diving into things and working through them, but it would be nice to get a refresher on the basics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>learning selinux and apparmor</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/learning-selinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:01:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/learning-selinux/</guid>
      <description>I am trying to understand SELinux and AppArmor, and collecting resources here as I learn. k
SELinux for mere mortals (2014) This was the first video I watched, and it helped me understanding what SELinux does at a fundamental basic level. It&amp;rsquo;s probably useless in a container-filled world (where I doubt Fedora shipes pre-configured SELinux rules for my containers), but it helped me think I understood types / labels, so that seems like a positive step?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>things to build</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/things-to-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 13:24:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/things-to-build/</guid>
      <description>This is a running list of things I want to build!
There&amp;rsquo;s an analogous running list of things I want to learn. Things move between them :) I also have higher standards of documentation (other people should be able to use it) before marking these as complete.
  kubernetes-login A helper to openssh that allows users to log in to a configurable user pod running on a kubernetes cluster. Should ideally support scp / sftp too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>python gil resources</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/python-gil-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 23:18:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/python-gil-resources/</guid>
      <description>I was in a conversation about the Python GIL with friends a few days ago, and realized that my understanding of the specifics of the GIL problem were super hand-wavy &amp;amp; unstructured. So I spent some time collecting resources to learn more, and now have a better understanding!
Python&amp;rsquo;s Infamous GIL (Larry Hastings) This was a great introduction to the history of the GIL, why it was necessary &amp;amp; reasons why getting rid of it is complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systemd simple containment for GUI applications &amp; shells</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/systemd-simple-containment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 23:23:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/systemd-simple-containment/</guid>
      <description>I earlier had a vaguely working setup for making sure browsers, shells and other applications don&amp;rsquo;t eat all RAM / CPU on my machine with systemd + sudo + shell scripts.
It was a hacky solution, and also had complications when used to launch shells. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t passing in all the environment varialbes it should, causing interesting-to-debug issues. sudo rules were complex, and hard to do securely.
I had also been looking for an excuse to learn more Golang, so I ended up writing systemd-simple-containment or ssc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systemd gui applications</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/systemd-gui-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 20:47:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/systemd-gui-applications/</guid>
      <description>Update: There&amp;rsquo;s a follow-up post with a simpler solution now.
Ever since I read Jessie Frazelle&amp;rsquo;s amazing setup (1, 2, 3) for running GUI applications in docker containers, I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do something similar. However, I want to install things on my computer - not in docker images. So what I wanted was just isolation (no more Chrome / Firefox freezing my laptop), not images. I&amp;rsquo;m also not as awesome (or knowledgeable!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>things to learn</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/things-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 15:27:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/things-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>Keeping a running list of things I want to learn!
There&amp;rsquo;s also a list of things I want to build.
 How to use org mode properly? Should I use it for notes over markdown? Develop a deep understanding of how networks work. How do linux network namespaces work? How to run GUI apps with systemd?  I did learn! Both a hacky version and a much better version that also taught me some Go!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moving to hugo</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/moving-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 23:46:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/moving-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m attempting to now blog at http://words.yuvi.in, using hugo rather than wordpress.
Over the last few years, IRC, Twitter &amp;amp; WhatsApp have ruined my public writing. I shall now slowly attempt to bring that back :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>liberal software</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/liberal-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 22:45:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/liberal-software/</guid>
      <description>I ran into this thought provoking though when randomly attempting to relax this weekend. There&amp;rsquo;s a summary at LWN if you do not want to watch the talk - but as the lwn summarizer admits, the video definitely conveys things that are hard to capture on text.
The core takeaway for me is to think about:
 what is the future of free and open-source software? The answer was: it has no future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my first protest</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/first-protest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 22:37:21 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/first-protest/</guid>
      <description>I went to the protests at SFO last weekend. It was the first real set of protests I&amp;rsquo;ve been to. I write this to attempt to capture a sliver of what I felt that day.
I was there for about 10h on day 1, and came home exhausted. I went back on Day 2, and this time stayed for much shorter period of time (~4h?) before heading back home.
To everyone who was at the protest even if it does not directly affect you yet - thank you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>making twitter useful again</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/making-twitter-useful-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 22:17:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/making-twitter-useful-again/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve unfollowed everyone I follow on Twitter, and am slowly starting back up from scratch. I&amp;rsquo;m only going to follow people who are:
 Underrepresented people in Tech (as broadly construed) Journalists  And that&amp;rsquo;s it. I&amp;rsquo;ll follow back friends I&amp;rsquo;m not otherwise in contact with as well, but might take a while.
I&amp;rsquo;ve had this for a few days and am already enjoying using it far more than I did before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCI Conflicts Class: Notes from Week 1 – Part I</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/uci-conflicts-class-notes-week-1-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 18:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/uci-conflicts-class-notes-week-1-part/</guid>
      <description>I’ve started taking a Coursera class on Conflicts from UCI.
Just dumping notes from me going through the video lectures here. I’ve a bunch more videos to go through for Week 1, but dumping what I have for now.
Types of Conflict:
 Constructive Destructive  Caused by lack of flexibility, getting interpersonal things get in the way and the sureness that ones way is the right way Leads to stiffling of anything new, resulting in ‘this is the way things have always been’ being used as an actual legitimate reason for things    Sources of Conflict</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Side Project: UA Emoji Firefox Extension</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/side-project-ua-emoji-firefox-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 05:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/side-project-ua-emoji-firefox-extension/</guid>
      <description>Note: I’m trying to spend time explicitly writing random side projects that are not related to what I’m actively working on as my main project in some form.
A random thread started by Ironholds on a random mailing list I was wearily catching up on contained a joke from bearloga about malformed User Agents. This prompted me to write UAuliver (source), a Firefox extension that randomizes your user agent to be a random string of emoji.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper notes: ‘The impact of syntax colouring on program comprehension’</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/the-impact-syntax-colouring-program-comprehension-paper-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 08:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/the-impact-syntax-colouring-program-comprehension-paper-notes/</guid>
      <description>I’ve recently started reading more academic papers, and thought it’d be useful to write notes about them and publish them as I go along! This one is for The impact of syntax colouring on program comprehension
 I was amazed at the amount of prior research it is citing. Why have I not been reading these for the last 10 years of my life? Apparently it is ok to report findings with a sample size of 10 people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lua Paper</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/lua-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 21:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/lua-paper/</guid>
      <description>http://www.lua.org/spe.html is a pretty nice read!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS servers, localhost and asynchronous code</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/dns-servers-localhost-asynchronous-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 02:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/dns-servers-localhost-asynchronous-code/</guid>
      <description>localhost is always 127.0.0.1, right? Nope, can also be ::1 if your system only has IPV6 (apparently).
Asking a DNS server for an A record for localhost should give you back 127.0.0.1 right? Nope – it varies wildly! 8.8.8.8 gives me an NXDOMAIN which means it tells you straight up THIS DOMAIN DOES NOT EXIST! Which is true, since localhost isn’t a domain. But if you ask the same thing of any dnsmasq server, it’ll tell you localhost is 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 21-30 Dec 2015</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-21-30-dec-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 23:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-21-30-dec-2015/</guid>
      <description>Clearly I missed an entire week. I need to build a better system to make this easier…
Random notes.
 Kicked out NFS from the Tool Labs proxies (with 1). Yay! This hopefully explains the lockup of tools-proxy-01 yesterday night, maybe? It’s been restarted since, and I hope to no longer have instances randomly locoking on me. Infrastructure standards of 2009, here we come! :D I’ve also removed NFS from tools-redis, and migrated them to Jessie as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 2015 Dec 20</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-2015-dec-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 17:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-2015-dec-20/</guid>
      <description>Probably going to take it easy and chill. Already sent a trivial PR up though.
Also saw the old devlog mailing list and feeling happy memories. Clearly need to bring something back like that, but I don’t know / think mailing lists are the best medium. More thinking!
Ended up learning some Tornad and wrote nbserve to serve rendered notebooks and static files in a configurable way. I should refactor PAWS to have separate jupyterhub, proxy and nbserve pods tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 2015 Dec 19</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-2015-dec-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 09:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-2015-dec-19/</guid>
      <description>Today looks like a day of finding, reporting and fixing bugs in WikiChatter. I had made a stupid mistake yesterday that meant not all of the Teahouse pages were being parsed, and I immediately started running into bugs. Have reported (and fixed!) two (1 and 2), and ran into another bug in mediawikiparserfromhell itself. I’m sure I’ll find more. Another bug in WikiChatter! 3 Perils of digging through archives – you find Wikipedians giving relationship advice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 2015 Dec 18</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-2015-dec-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 07:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-2015-dec-18/</guid>
      <description>Haven’t done these in a while, let’s see if I can get this back on the wagon!
 Discovered the WikiChatter library (thanks to @halfak!), and using that in my Teahouse analysis notebook. Far better than writing my own parser and fighting with that. Lets me get on with the actual fun stuff I wanted to do (which is the actual analysis) Learning about pandas, checking out matplotlib, bokeh and wordcloud libraries to use in the analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Things”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 00:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/things/</guid>
      <description>I’m writing this post in an attempt to catalog the list of things I own so I can evaluate if I really need them and get rid of them.
 15″ rMBP Kinesis Keyboard Apple Trackpad Moto X Kindle Nexus 7 (To be returned to the WMF) Broken Nexus 4 (To be backed up and then… something) iPod Touch Earphones (Soundmagic E10) Headphones (AudioTechnica ATH M50) Battery Pack #1 Battery Pack #2 MiFi (US Only) Multi USB Charger + 6 USB Cables Bluetooth Speaker (JBL Flip 2) Assorted Medication (in several loose covers, need to consolidate) Toiletries (Emergency Soap, Toothbrush, Toothpaste, Hair Gel, Shampoo, Conditioner) Velcro Rolls Box of Leaves Octopus Letter in Envelope Universal plug convertor Physical paper notebook Nailcolor Glasses + backup glasses Small Green Foldable Bag Pens Wallet with assorted currencies and cards Raspberry PI Assorted USB chargers (accumulated from various devices) Wrist Straps (left and right) Beard Trimmer  Clothes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Green Stuff”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/green-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 20:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/green-stuff/</guid>
      <description>“Green Stuff”
TIL that Gregory Kohs was actually allowed to post on wikimedia-l at some point in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global merge of accounts at Wikimedia</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/global-merge-accounts-wikimedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2015 12:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/global-merge-accounts-wikimedia/</guid>
      <description>is now slowly happening, and I am the test subject!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best talk ever?</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/talk-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 08:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/talk-ever/</guid>
      <description>(Funniest, at least!). Well worth the 27min watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for Jan 5, 2015</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-for-jan-5-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 21:52:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-for-jan-5-2015/</guid>
      <description>DevLog for Jan 5, 2015
Trying out the ByWord app, since it has MarkDown support and also publishes to WordPress. Paid Rs. 900 for it, let’s hope it is useful. Hate the default font, though.
 Need to parse View definitions on labsdb public databases and verify that we aren’t leaking any info (https://phabricator.wikimedia.org/T85783). Was going to use the sqlparse library, but that doesn’t seem very complete or useful. Will attempt to use regexes now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for Jan 3-4 2015</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-jan-3-4-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 19:18:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-jan-3-4-2015/</guid>
      <description>Nothing much going on…
 Continue reading Real World Haskell. This is indeed expanding my horizons, but I haven’t found any project I could use haskell in yet. Will keep looking. Helped fix a parsoid outage yesterday. No biggie. I still do not understand fully how parsoid works / how it is set up, should do. Spend most of the rest of the time in ‘weekend mode’, which includes mostly not doing things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for Jan 2, 2015</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-jan-2-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 21:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-jan-2-2015/</guid>
      <description>Woohoo, 2015! :) Let’s see if I can keep this going this time :)
 Have started taking weekends slightly more seriously. My brain feels less overwhelmed after that. Should take weekends even more seriously going forward. Merged labsdb-auditor rewrite patch. Code clean enough for my tastes now, although not documented enough. Lots of back and forth CR with valhallasw was really nice – it’s something I’ve been missing for the past few months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugging a keyboard into my Nexus 7</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/plugging-a-keyboard-into-my-nexus-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 18:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/plugging-a-keyboard-into-my-nexus-7/</guid>
      <description>Was a great idea! It just worked (with an OTP cable), and I can now probably find much more uses for this thing than I could before. Yay!
I wonder if I can use this to write code. However, a 7 inch tablet is very poorly suited for that task – would need at least a 10″ one. But there aren’t many of those going around these days…
I’ll probably use this for random browsing / commenting, and use my Mac for actual programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog Sep 12-24, 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-sep-12-24-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 15:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-sep-12-24-2014/</guid>
      <description>That was a long break. Should get into better habits. I’m sure I’d miss some here. Oh well.
It was a very interesting week, culminating in some very interesting things at Trafalgar Square. I feel much better as a person and more calmer/chilled out now :) Should remember to take weekends off.
 Helped the WikiMetrics people with some puppet changes. They were requiring mysql directly instead of using the class we have in ops/puppet, which meant it put data in the /var partition instead of in /srv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for Sep 10-11 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-sep-10-11-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 20:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-sep-10-11-2014/</guid>
      <description>Back from an awesome vacation. Too awesome to write about, even :) Suffice it to say, England has some really pretty places.
Some Android app work, and lots of monitoring work
 Fixed bugs causing the Wikipedia Android Alpha from building properly. Now it builds properly whenever there is a new commit. Hooray! This was primarily caused by me forgetting to give it lots of RAM (8G VMEM) to execute the mvn build commands (https://gerrit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shitty Web advertising #1</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/shitty-web-advertising-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 12:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/shitty-web-advertising-1/</guid>
      <description>The message icon was flashing obnoxiously. I wonder how much money CNet made off that.
I don’t notice these on desktop thanks to Adblock. Should set it up on my phone too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 31 Aug, 1-4 Sep 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-31-aug-1-4-sep-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 10:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-31-aug-1-4-sep-2014/</guid>
      <description>Missed DevLogging for a while.
Am in London now.
 Started using a spare Majestouch Ninja 2 over my regular Kinesis Advantage. This is way more portable, and my hand does not seem to be hurting while using it (so far only about 4-5 hours). If this keeps up, I should be able to move to a similar smaller keyboard over the much bulkier kinesis. There’s still a little bit of discomfort, so I’ll probably want a very portable and mechanical split keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 29, 30 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-29-30-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 11:41:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-29-30-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>Chill weekend. Didn’t really do anything code related. Recovering from friday night party :)
Started reading Data + Design which seems quite nice. Also starting a coursera course on Data analysis and Statistical Inference on Sep 1, should be fun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 28 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-28-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 22:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-28-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>Let’s see. I’m also going to attempt to include patch links wherever possible.
 Cleaned up session handling bugs in Quarry. They were previously not closing properly, causing SQLAlchemy exceptions now and then that’ll let queries die in a ‘queued’ state. This should hopefully be fixed by https://gerrit.wikimedia.org/r/#/c/156909/. Made https://graphite.wmflabs.org somewhat more stable again for use by Wikimedia BetaLabs folks by just blacklisting all other projects from sending data to it (with a local whitelist hack + https://gerrit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 25 and 26 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-26-27-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-26-27-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>Not very code heavy
 Couple of pull requests(#1 and #2) for the Atom Autosave plugin. One adds a preference to not autosave by when you are explicitly closing a window / pane, and the other just sets the ‘enabled’ preference to default. CoffeeScript isn’t too bad either! I should consider writing more plugins (I currently use Atom for CSS/JS/Puppet, should try other languages) Added CSV, TSV and JSON download options to Quarry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for Aug 24, 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-aug-24-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 02:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-aug-24-2014/</guid>
      <description>Wooooo!
 Moved labsbooks (described in yesterday’s devlog) to use a shared readonly IPython virtualenv maintained by me. Also installed a bunch of modules people might want to use (SciPy, NumPy, Pandas, PyTables, matplotlib). Am considering just installing IPython notebook globally via puppet and using that, since that’ll enable users to just use the system packages. However, the version of IPython notebook from Ubuntu is ancient, so that’s probably a non-starter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 23 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-23-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 02:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-23-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>Back in Glasgow! It was actually not very cold today, only cold! Progress.
Started working on my long-abandoned labsbook project, which aims to make Tool Labs a first class environment for people who want to run (and publish) iPython Notebooks while also being able to access the replica databases and the dumps. Doing this in a secure manner is kinda hard, but I think I’ve a neat solution that lets everyone run a personal iPython kernel on the Grid, access it from their local machine, and also publish it to the web from a standard location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog for Aug 22 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-aug-22-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 14:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-aug-22-2014/</guid>
      <description>Was in Edinburgh again, missed writing it as I went along. Oh well.
 Ported the code for the Wikipedia Android app automated builds to Python, and you can see it in action at http://tools.wmflabs.org/wikipedia-android-builds/ now. It lets you download the latest build, and notes the last successful build time. Good enough :) It was originally in bash, and porting it to python allowed me to create a ‘fake’ API (just JSON blobs written to known locations in the file system).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog for 21 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-21-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 11:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-21-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>In Edinburgh! I’ve finally stopped spelling it as Edinborough!
 Added ‘user group’ functionality to Quarry, and added a sudo user group that does what you would think it does. Will be assigned super, super sparingly. Found out that I’d have to explicitly specify charset of the database when I’m creating it or MySQL will default to a stupid charset. Forced all tables and columns to utf8 and that seems to have fixed a bunch of unicode issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog for 20 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-20-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 03:39:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-20-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>Woke up at 11AM again! w000t!
 Fixed a stupid bug in Quarry that made it fail if MySQL decided that a column you were selecting is a Decimal. Fixed this in time for… Helped out with a webinar from J-Mo for people to learn SQL and do research against Wikimedia stuff with Quarry! Went without a glitch mostly, so yay :) Oren asked for an API for Quarry, I’ll investigate ways to get that done Found that some queries against enwiki succeed on s1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog for 19 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-19-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 11:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-19-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>Here we go again.
 Wrote a small blog post talking about how to package python packages as debian packages. More work on getting Graphite setup for Wikimedia Labs. Everything is up and running now (after a number of embarrassing typos). Need to figure out NAT rules to let labs machines talk to labmon1001, and then it can start receiving data!!!1 Got access to Wikimedia’s Hadoop cluster, and ran my first HIVE query ever!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple python packaging for Debian / Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/simple-python-packaging-debian-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 13:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/simple-python-packaging-debian-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>(As requested by Jean-Fred)
One of the ‘pain points’ with working on deploying python stuff at Wikimedia is that pip and virtualenvs are banned on production, for some (what I now understand as) good reasons (the solid Signing / Security issues with PYPI, and the slightly less solid but nonetheless valid ‘If we use pip for python and gem for ruby and npm for node, EXPLOSION OF PACKAGE MANAGERS and makes things harder to manage’).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paying for IRCCloud</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/paying-irccloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 12:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/paying-irccloud/</guid>
      <description>I’ve started paying for IRCCloud.
It is the first ‘service’ I am paying for as a subscriber, I think. I’ve considered doing that for a long time, but ‘paying for IRC’ just felt… odd. I’ve been using ZNC + LimeChat. It’s decent, but sucks on Mobile. Keeping a socket open all the time on a phone just kills the battery, plus the UX on most Android clients sucks.
So after seeing Sam Smith use IRCCloud during Wikimania, I made the plunge and paid for IRCCloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 18 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-18-aug-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 12:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-18-aug-2014/</guid>
      <description>I’ve started the habit of opening up a devlog post each morning and just filling it up as I go along. Let’s hope I can keep this up :)
 Merged a couple of Android patches. The app is getting better every day without too much involvement from me, and yay for that :) I’ve gotten closure over the Android app – it was fucking terrible, and now it is quite awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 17 Aug 2014</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-17-mon-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 12:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-17-mon-2014/</guid>
      <description>Devlogs again! Let’s see how long I can keep this one up.
Been a whirlwind few months. I’m moving to the Wikimedia Ops team soon! The Wikipedia app has been released! Lots of excitement around, should do a bigger post sometime with details. This should just follow usual devlog format of stuff for the day
 Completed deployment of changing the results backend of Quarry to SQLite. That was a fun exercise, and I should write about that separately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English Translation of ‘Tamil Hip Hop’ song</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/english-translation-tamil-hip-hop-song/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 12:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/english-translation-tamil-hip-hop-song/</guid>
      <description>This is a best effort translation of the song ‘Clubbule Mabbule‘ (Drunk in a Club) from Tamil to English.
  Fuck, get lost. This is modern culture, eh? If you call this westernization modern culture, then this song is dedicated right for you. Hip hop tamizha, your Aaadheeee.
Women roaming around drunk in clubs What the fuck is happening in Tamil Nadu I salute you all All your honor is flying away</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Scouting for Boys”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/scouting-boys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 19:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/scouting-boys/</guid>
      <description>In Welcome to the Machine there is a line that goes “provided with toys and scouting for boys”. I had initially assumed that it was referring to a young guy who is gay and is ‘scouting for boys’.
And then a few days later I realized that it is talking about ‘the book‘. That is now doubly funny because of the Boy Scouts’ attitude towards gays</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 4 of 2014: Small Gods (Discworld)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/book-4-2014-small-gods-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 18:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/book-4-2014-small-gods-2014/</guid>
      <description>Another nice, one off Discworld book. Nice bits about how Gods are created by us, and need us more than the other way around. The philosophers are incredibly funny wherever they turn up too. The Desert after you Die bit was… beautiful – Judgement happens, but by yourself. Fun digs at governments and organized religion throughout made it rather enjoyable :)
4/5</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 3 of 2014: Pyramids (Discworld)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/book-3-2014-pyramids-discworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 06:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/book-3-2014-pyramids-discworld/</guid>
      <description>Finished that yesterday. Fun digs at war, and fun digs at people (literally) stuck in a paste despite being in the present. The bit with the Greek philosophers was also nice. No memorable recurring characters, however.
3/5</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 2 of 2014: Pro Git</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/book-2-2014-pro-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 17:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/book-2-2014-pro-git/</guid>
      <description>Pro Git is a nice book I recommend to newbies – yet I hadn’t fully read it once. I decided to do so, and I think it was reasonably useful. Most of the stuff in here I already knew, and the treatment of the stuff I did not (Git Internals, mostly) wasn’t deep enough to be useful. Nevertheless, reinforced some useful concepts in my head and probably gave me enough strong foundations for when I decide to dive into the actual internals of git more (probably by reading the source code?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book 1 of 2014: Hogfather (Discworld)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/book-1-2014-hogfather-discworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 14:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/book-1-2014-hogfather-discworld/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been reading a lot over the last few months (Discworld + Foundation gives me about 24 books in the last 3 months), and figured I’d extend that for the next year with a little more underlying planning. So along with Bala, Arun &amp;amp; Surya, I’ll try to read a hundred books this year, and also do a blog post each about them.
Hogfather is the 21st book in the Discworld series I’ve read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discworld Series progress</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/discworld-series-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 16:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/discworld-series-progress/</guid>
      <description>Contains a list of Discworld Novels. Am reading them all, and will cross them out here as I finish each. Number of books currently finished: 24 (as of 16 Jan 2014)
 The Colour of Magic (1983) (Rincewind) The Light Fantastic (1986) (Rincewind) Equal Rites (1987) (Witches) Mort (1987) (Death) Sourcery (1988) (Rincewind) Wyrd Sisters (1988) (Witches) Pyramids (1989) (One-off) Guards! Guards! (1989) (City Watch) Eric (1990) (Rincewind) Moving Pictures (1990) (One-off) Reaper Man (1991) (Death) Witches Abroad (1991) (Witches) Small Gods (1992) (One-off) Lords and Ladies (1992) (Witches) Troll Bridge (1992) (Short story) Men at Arms (1993) (City Watch) Theatre of Cruelty (1993) (Short story) Soul Music (1994) (Death) Interesting Times (1994) (Rincewind) The Discworld Companion (1994) (Companion) Maskerade (1995) (Witches) Feet of Clay (1996) (City Watch) Hogfather (1996) (Death) Jingo (1997) (City Watch) The Unseen University Diary (1998) (Diary) The Last Continent (1998) (Rincewind) Carpe Jugulum (1998) (Witches) The Sea and Little Fishes (1998) (Short story) The Ankh-Morpork City Watch Diary (1999) (Diary) The Fifth Elephant (1999) (City Watch) The Science of Discworld (1999) (Science) Nanny Ogg’s Cookbook (1999) (Recipes) The Assassins’ Guild Yearbook and Diary (2000) The Truth (2000) (One-off) The Fools’ Guild Yearbook and Diary (2001) (Diary) Thief of Time (2001) (Death) The Last Hero (2001) (Rincewind, although this is debatable) The Amazing Maurice and his Educated Rodents (2001) (One-off, children’s) The Thieves’ Guild Yearbook and Diary (2002) (Diary) Night Watch (2002) (City Watch) Death and What Comes Next (2002) (Short story) The Science of Discworld II: The Globe (2002)(Science) The Wyrdest Link (2002) (Quizbook) The (Reformed) Vampyre’s Diary (2003) (Diary) The Wee Free Men (2003) (Wee Free Men) The New Discworld Companion (2003) (Companion) Monstrous Regiment (2003) (One-off) A Hat Full of Sky (2004) (Wee Free Men) Going Postal (2004) (Post Office) Once More* *With Footnotes (2004) (Compilation of short works) The Discworld Almanack (2005) (Almanack) Thud!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terry Prachett on the word ‘synergistically’</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/terry-prachett-word-synergistically/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 15:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/terry-prachett-word-synergistically/</guid>
      <description> You had to admire the way perfectly innocent words were mugged, ravished, stripped of all true meaning and decency and then sent to walk the gutter for Reacher Gilt, although ‘synergistically’ had probably been a whore from the start Going Postal, Terry Prachett </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling Agile today</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/feeling-agile-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 03:54:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/feeling-agile-today/</guid>
      <description>From twitter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Write once, attempt to debug everywhere”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/write-once-debug-everywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 02:20:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/write-once-debug-everywhere/</guid>
      <description>“Write once, attempt to debug everywhere” is probably way more accurate than “Write once, run anywhere” – at least for GUI apps. There’s something rather special about ideas that are theoretically amazingly wonderful yet end up being a major pain in the butt when you try to put them in practice, isn’t it?
The older Wikipedia App happened to be in PhoneGap, and I consider it one of my biggest blunders to not have torn it down on day 0 and rewritten it in something saner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia Apps reboot taking shape nicely</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/wikipedia-apps-reboot-taking-shape-nicely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 15:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/wikipedia-apps-reboot-taking-shape-nicely/</guid>
      <description>Prettier, faster and more feature packed! Native Wikipedia app for Android coming real soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP being insane, part 5832</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/php-insane-part-5832/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 17:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/php-insane-part-5832/</guid>
      <description>Somehow: ( $a &amp;amp;&amp;amp; $b ) || ( $b &amp;amp;&amp;amp; $c ) || ( $a &amp;amp;&amp;amp; $c )
Became: $a ? ( $b || $c ) : ( $b &amp;amp;&amp;amp; $c )
Became: count( array_filter( array( $a, $b, $c ) ) ) &amp;gt;= 2
Became: &amp;quot;$a$b$c&amp;quot; &amp;gt; 1
God dammit PHP…
(from discussion among me, ^d, ori-l, bd808 and anomie on #mediawiki-core about how to represent ‘if at least 2 of three conditions are true’)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lots of discussion over tiny things that do not matter in the long run, part 5321</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/lots-discussion-tiny-matter-long-run-part-5321/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 21:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/lots-discussion-tiny-matter-long-run-part-5321/</guid>
      <description>On gerrit this time
Sigh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing Laundry</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/doing-laundry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 07:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/doing-laundry/</guid>
      <description>At a hotel in SF, doing my laundry. This trip has made me more amenable to taking my time to do things. Feel more happy in general and less restless :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog for Tuesday, September 24, 2013</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-tuesday-september-24-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 11:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-tuesday-september-24-2013/</guid>
      <description>I’ve given up on trying to make DevLogs really comprehensive and complete, and just try to make them – even if they are incomplete. Perhaps this will help me actually write more devlogs, and thus make it more comprehensive…
I started on the Functional Programming in Scala course today. I wanted to do it the last time, but did not find the time. This time will be different – I’m in a different spot mentally, and a big drain on my emotional / time resources (“college”) is no longer a factor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science!</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 23:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/science/</guid>
      <description>This AskReddit thread about a HIV survivor (is that even the right term?) is heartwarming. SCIENCE!!!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comments on again</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 22:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/comments/</guid>
      <description>WordPress decided to be a dick and turned off comments without telling me. They’re back on now.
Why does all software suck?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Entire Night Wasted</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/an-entire-night-wasted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 21:49:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/an-entire-night-wasted/</guid>
      <description>[Warning: Childish rant ahead]
My natural sleep cycle seems to be one that tends towards the darker times – sleeping before 3AM feels like an abomination, before midnight unheard of. My best work seems to be done between 2AM and 5AM. My current &amp;lsquo;sleep cycle&amp;rsquo; has me sleeping at about 8AM, and waking up at about 5PM. Plenty of sleep for the day, eh?
It is probably not healthy. I don&amp;rsquo;t look, or feel healthy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog for Monday, Aug 26, 2013</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-for-monday-aug-26-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 13:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-for-monday-aug-26-2013/</guid>
      <description>Nothing new started. The UploadCampaigns API patch I talked about yesterday was fixed and merged. I also helped merge some of MarkTraceur&amp;rsquo;s JS cleanup patches to UploadWizard. And Brion&amp;rsquo;s big detail view patch for Android Commons app. Also another cleanup/api feature patch to UploadWizard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“If you help block Ads, you should be in prison!”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/if-you-help-block-ads-you-should-be-in-prison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 11:55:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/if-you-help-block-ads-you-should-be-in-prison/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t understand how ad-blocking is even legal. It&amp;rsquo;s like stealing – stealing content for free, IMHO there&amp;rsquo;s no difference between stealing MP3s and news or any other content. There&amp;rsquo;s some kind of user agreement between websites and its users – &amp;ldquo;you can use our site for free, but you have to watch the ads&amp;rdquo;. Adblock violates this agreement. The people responsible for this should be in prison, they&amp;rsquo;re thieves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for Sun, Aug 25, 2013</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-for-sun-aug-25-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 23:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-for-sun-aug-25-2013/</guid>
      <description>DevLogs have been something I&amp;rsquo;ve not been writing much of of late. Time to fix that!
WLM Android App Spent some time reviving the WLM Android App. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t too hard, and am surprised at how well it still runs :) Some work still needed to update the templates and other metadata to refer to WLM2013 rather than WLM2012 – but that should not be too hard. The fact that it is an issue at all is simply because I ripped out all the Campaign related APIs a few weeks ago with my UploadCampaign rewrite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disconnecting, for real</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/disconnecting-for-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 15:56:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/disconnecting-for-real/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the Internet since I was 14. And I don&amp;rsquo;t remember a time when I did not have a computer – I think I got mine when I was 10. Growing up, writing code has always been a major part of me – my identity. I&amp;rsquo;ve never quite managed to separate &amp;lsquo;me&amp;rsquo; from &amp;lsquo;my code&amp;rsquo; – despite mouthing off the soundbite &amp;lsquo;You are not your code!&amp;rsquo; to plenty of people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Die ’80 cols or die!’ guidelines!</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/die-80-cols-or-die-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 16:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/die-80-cols-or-die-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Python&amp;rsquo;s PEP8 has just been changed to no longer recommend sticking to 79 columns! The new text says:
Aim to limit all lines to a maximum of 79 characters, but up to 99 characters is acceptable when it improves readability.  It would be nice to not have any such set limits at all, and just depend on programmers not being insane, but this is still an improvement!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sprinkling some Douchebaginess in code</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/sprinkling-some-douchebaginess-in-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2013 08:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/sprinkling-some-douchebaginess-in-code/</guid>
      <description>After being frustrated at Java&amp;rsquo;s lack of a generic &amp;lsquo;callback&amp;rsquo; type, I created this interface:
 public interface ContributionUploadProgress {void onUploadStarted(Contribution contribution);boolean isJavaAPieceOfShit();}  And randomly throw around (with onComplete implementing ContributionUploadProgress)
 assert onComplete.isJavaAPieceOfShit();  This, of course, is trivial to fix with an IDE. Should be more fun with a dynamic language :)
(And yes, I removed that code before committing)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nitpicking about the Order of Cards</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/nitpicking-about-the-order-of-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 01:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/nitpicking-about-the-order-of-cards/</guid>
      <description>Someone pointed out this happening on Gerrit…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Streaks</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/github-streaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 22:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/github-streaks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m on my longest GitHub Streak this year – currently 20 days (was previously 18 days). That means I&amp;rsquo;ve had at least one commit (though usually more!) each day for the last 20 days. Sounds much easier than it actually is. Wanting to keep my streak unbroken is also making me write more diverse code – I think those 20 days feature code in Javascript, Python, Java, PHP and Python. It&amp;rsquo;s also distributed across a lot of projects – at least 8-9 different ones on last count.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game of Life in APL</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/game-of-life-in-apl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2013 10:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/game-of-life-in-apl/</guid>
      <description>Ran across a video explaining building Game of Life in APL. Pretty awesome, and surprisingly – quite understandable too!
I should learn J at some point, I think. My problem with trying to learn such languages is that I find it hard to find something to build that&amp;rsquo;s not a mere academic exercise, and I still do not have a solution as such. Just &amp;lsquo;try harder&amp;rsquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t really work. Perhaps invent some sort of wonderful number crunching idea and then implement it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can’t take the India out of the W3C…</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/cant-take-the-india-out-of-the-w3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 07:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/cant-take-the-india-out-of-the-w3c/</guid>
      <description>Presenting, the W3C India website, apparently from 2013. Funniest bit was probably:
 Best view in IE 9+, latest version of chrome, mozilla, opera and safari.
 Number of interactions with CDAC that have given me faith in any semblance of their competence: 0</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First major feature to Commons deployed</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/first-major-feature-to-commons-deployed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2013 00:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/first-major-feature-to-commons-deployed/</guid>
      <description>My UploadWizard work has just been deployed to Wikimedia Commons and my name is listed in the on site credits. Special thanks to Mark Traceur for code review!
This feels very, very nice :) Now to sneak more code into other extensions…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bikeshedding on Gerrit #1</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/bikeshedding-on-gerrit-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 14:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/bikeshedding-on-gerrit-1/</guid>
      <description>First there was this.
I was bored, and so there was this. That of course, brought a swift end to the bikeshed. I&amp;rsquo;m only slightly ashamed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>God, biological engineering and friendly AIs</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/god-biological-engineering-and-friendly-ais/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 18:09:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/god-biological-engineering-and-friendly-ais/</guid>
      <description>Talking to God is an interesting piece about apparent &amp;lsquo;dangers&amp;rsquo; of knowledge and the necessary side effects of evolution. Thought provoking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attempting to Secure Redis in a Multi Tenant environment</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/attempting-to-secure-redis-in-a-multi-tenant-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 23:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/attempting-to-secure-redis-in-a-multi-tenant-environment/</guid>
      <description>When running Redis in a shared cluster/hosting environment (such as Wikimedia Tool Labs, on which I&amp;rsquo;ve been having fun doing a lot of work on), you would want to try to provide at least some guarantee of isolation for your keys from everyone else&amp;rsquo;s keys. Since Redis doesn&amp;rsquo;t do ACLs, this is problematic.
This can be solved in a couple of ways
Run a Redis instance for each user This is simple enough to do – each user runs their own Redis instance, and has full access to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Platen Blog Editor</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/testing-platen-blog-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 12:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/testing-platen-blog-editor/</guid>
      <description>Ever since the death of Windows Live Writer, I’ve never managed to find a nice blog editor that I really liked and also worked fine. I had a nice Vim plugin that posted to wordpress for a while, but that seems to have stopped working. The WordPress interface itself is mostly fine, but still a fair bit ‘meh’.
Platen is a markdown based editor that’s a Chrome Web Store app that looks cool so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comedy Central Censored in India</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/comedy-central-censored-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 09:50:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/comedy-central-censored-india/</guid>
      <description>Comedy Central has been banned in India for the next ten days. Reasons?
 Whereas, the programme showed a man performing an act of stand_up comedy and mouthing vulgar words accompanied by obscene and suggestive gesture and gyration. During his performance, the man was shown uttering dialogues denigrating women, indecently and crudely referred to sex organs of men-and women and the sing-song rendition by the man sought to pornographically describe .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotional Blackmail</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/emotional-blackmail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 22:18:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/emotional-blackmail/</guid>
      <description>Potential trigger warning
I keep trying to tell myself “People are not evil. They are just doing the best they can with what they have”. But then I’ve to read shit like this, and I’m not so sure anymore.
Growing up to lose respect for people you considered heros is a horrible thing. Friends don’t let friends fall prey to emotional blackmail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autosuggest for Tamil in Android Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/autosuggest-tamil-android-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 21:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/autosuggest-tamil-android-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Screenshot of Autosuggest working in Tamil on my variant of the Android keyboard. I’ve been working on this on and off for the last few months (this is also my final year project in college). I’ve ported all of the jQuery.IME languages to work on the keyboard natively.
Now experimenting with Autosuggest. It only needs an appropriate dictionary now and we’ll be good to go. Currently I’m getting Autosuggest working only on Tamil, but the plan is to get it to work for all Indian languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia has a new Favicon!</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/wikipedia-favicon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 12:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/wikipedia-favicon/</guid>
      <description>Not sure if you’ve noticed, but over the last few days Wikipedia has a new Favicon – featuring (according to the commit message), “Multi-resolution, new render, rounded corners, very confused and angry graphic designer” :)
New Favicon:

Old Favicon:

Looks much nicer when not on a light background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the dead</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/remembering-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 21:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/remembering-dead/</guid>
      <description>Potential trigger warning
 Like if you ask three separate groups of Canadian households how much they’ll pay to save two thousand, twenty thousand, or two hundred thousand birds from dying in oil ponds, the three groups will respectively state that they’re willing to pay seventy-eight, eighty-eight, and eighty dollars. No difference, in other words. It’s called scope insensitivity. Your brain imagines a single bird struggling in an oil pond, and that image creates some amount of emotion that determines your willingness to pay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greatest Fear</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/greatest-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 06:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/greatest-fear/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people confuse being physically alone with being lonely. Not even remotely close to being the same thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bugs RESOLVED HUMOROUS</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/bugs-resolved-humorous/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 14:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/bugs-resolved-humorous/</guid>
      <description>Mediawiki has a number of humorous bug reports, though not as many as I’d like. Still, they’re quite funny.
I think my favorites are the request for RESOLVED MURDERED, the real reason why MediaWiki runs on MySQL, someone asking where the community consensus is to stop Volcanoes exploding, offers of shamanic help, a ground breaking report on US Government corruption, and a warning about zoning laws required for shipping Ponies,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving ICICI Bank</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/leaving-icici-bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 01:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/leaving-icici-bank/</guid>
      <description>I’m going to be moving all my cash off ICICI and on to… somewhere else (undecided) ASAP.
They have paste disabled everywhere, by placing onpaste=”return false” on all their text elements. I know that this is easily fixable, so let me open inspector by right cli-oh!

Well, no matter – I can simply use a short cut. Once getting rid of the frustrating onpaste, I found this in the HTML right below it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puppy pregnancy syndrome</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/puppy-pregnancy-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 12:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/puppy-pregnancy-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>Today’s share of well sourced but WTF wikipedia article is the Puppy pregnancy syndrome, a psychosomatic illness in humans that makes them believe that they’re pregnant with a puppy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onion on Mass Shootings in the US</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/onion-mass-shootings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 15:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/onion-mass-shootings/</guid>
      <description>I do love the Onion Channel on Youtube.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death by toilet</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/death-by-toile/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 12:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/death-by-toile/</guid>
      <description>I will start posting amusing but fairly well sourced wiki articles here occasionally.
Starting with the article on Toilet related deaths &amp;amp; injuries. I love the caption for the photograph :)
Also has fun part about how Elvis probably died. Highly recommended read :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code in Times New Roman</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/code-times-roman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 19:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/code-times-roman/</guid>
      <description>Quoting from Anna University’s guidelines for submitting a ‘project report’
 Appendix 1: Sample Code. Font style: Times New Roman, Font Size:12 and 1.5 line spacing.
 Shoot me now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculating the population of India on Wikipedia</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/calculating-population-india-wikipedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 01:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/calculating-population-india-wikipedia/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the English Wikipedia randomly, I encountered this template used to approximate the current live population of India. It uses the following simple formula:
  It’s based on population at a specific data + projected growth. The ‘update’ is done by (best guess) some bot hitting action=purge every night to re-do the calculation.
And where is this used? After looking at the template’s info page, the only article this seems to be used in is the India article, and that too only for population density statistics, rather than actual population statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arranged Shag &amp; Childbirth Without Sex</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/arranged-shag-childbirth-sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 01:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/arranged-shag-childbirth-sex/</guid>
      <description>Absolutely hilarious, but you could easily dub out a few words and have it pass for real. Not sure if funny or sad.
Has quote about how Jesus was Indian, because among other things, because “Parents had a son without having sex”.
This entire BBC series (Goodness Gracious Me) is incredibly hilarious. Most of them are on Youtube. Highly recommended.
Thanks to QCoder from #wikipedia-en for the tip. Cheered up an otherwise bad day :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entitled to an Outsourced Job</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/entitled-outsourced-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 21:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/entitled-outsourced-job/</guid>
      <description>Trigger warning: Completely inappropriate background music for the subject matter being discussed
I ran into this very interesting video from Senthil‘s facebook feed. The part that I found most interesting was the sense of entitlement – that despite not knowing anything about what they are going to be hired for (aka Programming), and admitting it to everyone, they still expect to be given jobs when they want.
While this would make sense in someplace like the military, where you go in and then train, it makes no sense for graduates of an engineering program, where they spent 4 years of their life training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tor Flashproxies on your browser</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/tor-flashproxies-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 14:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/tor-flashproxies-browser/</guid>
      <description>Tor is one of those things that you don’t really need at all until you really really need it. I don’t need it right now, but I still try to help it as much as possible. One of the easiest way to do so is to run a flashproxy (has nothing to do with Adobe!) on your browser – super simple to setup, and effective for people looking for bridges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiencing ‘Embrace, Extend &amp; Extinguish’</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/experiencing-embrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 19:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/experiencing-embrace/</guid>
      <description>I am too young to remember Microsoft doing anything that could be considered effective ‘Embrace, Extend &amp;amp; Extinguish’ (my first browser when using internet at home was Firefox 0.9), and hence could never appreciate the general suspicion with which everything Microsoft was viewed with. Google’s handling of Reader has remedied that for me, however. I was around to witness all the events that Ed Bott at ZDNet discusses, and hopefully I have learnt my lesson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Whatsapp</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/511/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 12:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/511/</guid>
      <description>Whatsaapp (and GTalk) has completely replaced SMS for me. The only sore point was that it was not ‘Android’y enough – looked too much like an iOS port, but it worked well enough (and had enough people in it) that my forays into Hike were never long enough. The latest update fixes the design to be a lot more flat and pleasing to the eyes, and I’m quite happy to stick to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mediawiki Bugzilla quips, aka ‘Behind the Scenes (sortof)’</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/mediawiki-bugzilla-quips-aka-behind-scenes-sortof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 22:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/mediawiki-bugzilla-quips-aka-behind-scenes-sortof/</guid>
      <description>You might have heard of bash.org. If not, do go there! (And I am sorry about your afternoon)
Mediawiki maintains something similar, but much shorter in size &amp;amp; form, at Bugzilla quips. I already appear a few times, but will try to appear some more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android RegEx bug: ‘null’ replacement with Matcher.replaceAll</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/android-regex-bug-null-replacement-matcher-replaceall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 22:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/android-regex-bug-null-replacement-matcher-replaceall/</guid>
      <description>Android’s Regular Expressions engine is API compatible with the generic Java implementation, but under the hood uses ICU’s RegEx engine. This usually causes no problems, until it does and then you’re sortof fucked, but not really.
On a recent project, a subtle bug in Android’s Matcher.replaceAll behavior bit me. When replacing values of captured groups (&#39;$1&#39;&amp;lt;/code,&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&#39;$2&#39;, etc), Android’s implementation replaced a reference to an empty group with the literal string &#39;null&#39; instead of just skipping it (aka replacing with empty string &#39;&#39;), which is what most other Java implemetations do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to file a bug report</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/file-bug-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/file-bug-report/</guid>
      <description>Valerie, our awesome ‘Bug Wrangler in Training’, has written a nice blog post on how to report your first bug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging more often, bye bye Twitter</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/blogging-more-often-bye-bye-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 14:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/blogging-more-often-bye-bye-twitter/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been mostly off Twitter for a while now, interacting with it rarely, and only on my Phone. While I’ve had a vague feeling of uneasiness ever since they unveiled their now business friendly developer policies, it really hit home when my favorite Android twitter app, Falcon Pro, hit Twitter’s arbitrary user token limit (and Twitter declined to care). That, plus the Google Reader saga have jolted me out of complacency a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindless Television</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/mindless-television/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 13:40:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/mindless-television/</guid>
      <description>Somehow, I found http://neave.com/television earlier today. Addictive.
P.S. Blogging from a tablet with a bluetooth keyboard is not bad at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choices</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/choices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 10:24:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/choices/</guid>
      <description>They suck. It’s easy when it is ‘useless test to take’ vs ‘GSoC’. Painful for a lot of other things. Ugh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open License everything!</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/open-license-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 10:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/open-license-everything/</guid>
      <description>Should have done this a while back. Added a CC BY mark to the blog. Will add a notice to the front page as well, stating that all media I produce (when not bound to someone else’s copyright) is CC BY. I think code is already taken care of, but I’ll add a note here saying that all code I release (unless explicitly licensed otherwise) is CC0 Licensed.
Now to actually produce something of value…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immortality of Youth</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/immortality-of-youth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 20:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/immortality-of-youth/</guid>
      <description>Reading this blog post from Wesley CrusherWil Wheatonreminded me first of my visit to the beach a few hours before Cyclone Nilam hit landfall (at the Thiruvanmiyur Beach). The fact that I couldn’t stand in one place (wind) and was constantly being attacked by sand – it was exhilarating.
The blog post also reminded me of how much I mis-treat my body. I’m surprised I’m not bedridden, immovable and with a host of diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worse is Worse</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/worse-worse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 16:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/worse-worse/</guid>
      <description>Richard Gabriel’s Worse is Better (falsly attributed to jwz by many), is a piece on how LISP lost out to C, despite being ‘better’.
Jim Waldo’s Worse is Worse notes, quite accurately, that what us geeks consider ‘better’ might not what is, in the context of the universe at large, ‘better’. To quote,
 […] what we see is that better is a complicated notion, and can depend on a variety of different metrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Month of Awesome (2012 Edition)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/month-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 19:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/month-awesome/</guid>
      <description>I left Chennai on the 3rd of November. I (will be) leaving Delhi on the 4th of December. That’s a 31 day trip. It taught me to be optimistic. It taught me in very real terms that the world is a large place, and so is life.
A few highlights:
 Building an app from nothing to workable state in a few days An actual first class train ride in India Running into a bunch of random french people who ended up becoming travel buddies Feeling small, and very temporary being in the ruins of Hampi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happiness #1</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/happiness-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 19:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/happiness-1/</guid>
      <description>Happiness is fixing a bug with no obvious cause with a one liner and pushing it out to five million people with wonderful support from a team sitting halfway across the world :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Eye flight</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/red-eye-flight/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 16:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/red-eye-flight/</guid>
      <description>I am not a fan of red eye flights. Nobody is
I have one tomorrow. Which brings up the question – do I stay up, or go to sleep and risk not waking up in time?
I am going to stay up. Let’s see how that goes :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wretched City</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/wretched-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 06:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/wretched-city/</guid>
      <description>There has been no power here since yesterday night.
I have a million other reasons to not like Chennai. And scarce few reasons to like it.
I need to get out of here. As soon as I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neglect and Sorrow</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/neglect-sorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 20:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/neglect-sorrow/</guid>
      <description>SumaStorm was my desktop computer. She died a slow, silent and agonizing death over the past few months, which came to light only today. Due to my neglect, she is dead today.
I built SumStorm with my own hands, bought with my own money (thanks to several amazing people on the web) when I was 16 or so. It felt amazing when I first booted it up. It felt amazing when I maxed out all its cores running distcc with my netbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying on the bleeding Edge</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/blogging-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 14:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/blogging-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>I’m blogging from (one of the many) browsers on this Raspberry Pi. Testing setting it up to do slideshows during JSFoo 2012.
THIS IS SO COOL!
I am now editing this blog post from my new Nexus 7.
THIS IS SO COOL!
I am a few years behind the curve on this. Last year was spent slogging my ass out at a wonderful startup and travelling to a lot of places meeting and working with some wonderful people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House painters of Programming</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/house-painters-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 07:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/house-painters-programming/</guid>
      <description>We’re the Michelangelos of the great age of machine intelligence which is yet to come. We’re sketching out how it’s all going to look. We’re at the forefront of solving incredible problems and creating magical devices. – DanielBMarkham
 If there’s a great age of machine intelligence to come, then one in a million of us may be a Michelangelo. The rest of us are house-painters, and the houses we paint are slated for demolition within our own lifetimes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vague Sense of Order, No Sense of Purpose</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/vague-sense-order-sense-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 06:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/vague-sense-order-sense-purpose/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this month I spent a couple of days as a ‘guest’ at Infosys Mahindra City (district finals for Aspirations 2020 – a TopCoder style programming competition). Interesting experience.
No laptops allowed. No storage devices either. Cameras are okay, but “please don’t take pictures”. Phones are okay too. The usual complimentary grope as you enter. Random security guards ask “Where is your ID card?” at random times. Buses bringing in hordes of people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“What still puzzles us?”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/what-puzzles-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 06:12:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/what-puzzles-us/</guid>
      <description>A screenshot from the etherpad used for last week’s WMF Mobile Team retrospective meeting. I could (and should!) fill in several volumes about how awesome working for (and with) the WMF Mobile team is, but that screenshot is a start in explaining the general fun and silliness of the place :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you do when only 0.3% of School Teachers pass the Eligibility Exam for Teaching?</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/0-3-school-teachers-pass-teachers-recruitment-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 09:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/0-3-school-teachers-pass-teachers-recruitment-exam/</guid>
      <description>You increase the time from 1.5 hours to 3 hours and give them another chance, of course!
 Keeping in mind the welfare of children and the need for teachers to fill vacancies, the government directed TRB to conduct re-examination for candidates who failed to obtain 60 per cent marks.
The government has directed TRB to increase the duration of the test time from one-and-a-half hours to three hours with additional 30 minutes for blind candidates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My .vimrc</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/my-vimrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2012 12:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/my-vimrc/</guid>
      <description>I’ve gotten rid of my Vim repo from GitHub, and switched to using Vundle + DropBox to keep my vim environment safely backed up.
You can find my .vimrc file here. With just this and Vundle setup, I find it much easier to port my settings elsewhere instead of using git.
Hat tip to tecoholic for pushing me to switch to Vundle :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I’m not a college drop out</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/college-drop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 09:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/college-drop/</guid>
      <description>I’m just on a one year break from college doing Interesting Things and growing up. Going great on both counts.
I will go back to college next year and finish. I understand that it will not be easy and that many people would consider it a pointless waste of time. That’s OK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing Headers along while Proxying with nginx</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/passing-headers-proxying-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 20:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/passing-headers-proxying-nginx/</guid>
      <description>When you’re proxying requests via nginx, you might assume after reading [the documentation][1] that every header is forwarded, except for the Host and Connection headers.
You’d also be wrong.
nginx drops all headers with an underscore in them.
This is a configurable settings. You can turn it on with a simple
I’m still baffled as to *why* this is [a configuration parameter][2]. And why it is turned off by default. And why there is no mention of it in the proxy docs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Program</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 21:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/program/</guid>
      <description>Note: These are almost a decade old. Reproduced as close to memory as possible
My first memories of programming aren’t actually C. They were GW-BASIC, and later on, LOGO. I don’t remember any of my BASIC – but I do remember the look on my computer science teacher’s face in 5th grade when I managed to draw a flower with LOGO when everyone else was doing rectangles and lines. I vividly remember it – you draw an arc for a certain length, then stop, draw another arc in the reverse direction for the same length – and you have a petal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: December 26, 2011 – Jan 3rd, 2012</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-26-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 01:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-26-2011/</guid>
      <description>Back in Chennai
 Moving yuvi.in to my prgmr server. I want wordpress for my blog, but I don’t want to run MySQL. Solution? Keep blog where it is (with the awesome webfaction people!) and use nginx to proxy requests to blog/. Seems to work, so yay! Rewrote tawp.in to use python/flask/memcached. Available on github. Replaced older node.js version Reading through The Art of Unix Programming on kindle. Amazing book so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog: December 23, 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-23-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 02:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-23-2011/</guid>
      <description>Worked the day first from Domlur bus terminus, and then from Exotel’s office (with @vijaysw).
 Incorporated search results (rather than just suggestions) into the Wikipedia app. Was a slight bitch to get right, but after that have made a bunch of variants that the others are testing out to see which one feels good (Suggestion if exists, else search, or search alone). Took up most of my time. We put out a dud as RC3 for the Wikipedia app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: December 21 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-21-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 23:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-21-2011/</guid>
      <description>livetrains work. Trying to move (minimal) build system to waf. Somewhat complicated, not as fluid as I’d like. Go to rake. Feel weird about starting from scratch, come back to waf. Not get anything done Another rake diversion. Final Makefile editing desperation. I give up – I need to spend atleast a day to get back on proper build tools. That day is not today. Added feature to change font size to wikipedia app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: December 11, 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-11-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 09:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-11-2011/</guid>
      <description>Added UI for AssessmentLog [SelectionSifter] Removed lots of dead code in SelectionSifter. Went to Bangalore Wikipedia Meetup. Was nice meeting people I knew online face to face. Talked about yenWikipedia, and learnt a lot about how article selection for offline wikipedia is done. Shot myself in the foot multiple times (over use of empty(), incomplete commit summaries and a tab/spaces issue). I’m rusty and it is showing. Shouldn’t be a problem anymore, though – because of you-know-what.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog December 10, 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-10-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 18:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-10-2011/</guid>
      <description> Looks like I’m going to be rewriting SelectionSifter’s UI a lot. No more QuickTemplates, as I found TablePager. Mediawik definitely needs to fix Bug #1 soon. Added proper i18n for SelectionSifter. Redid FilterRatings page completely. Went through PhoneGap documentation, checked out state of its Photo handling API. Looks good. Checked out patch to official Wikipedia app that adds upload functionality. Needs lot more polish.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog December 7, 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-7-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 23:34:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-7-2011/</guid>
      <description>Redid Blog template. Recategorized all blog posts Finally enabled mobile banking on ICICI. Still need 8 days for Internet activation. Sigh. Ordered HyperJuice 60W battery + Airline Adapter Read through the WPBannerMeta template (and its subtemplates), figured out where to get the assessment markers in. Poof that was hard. These templates are perfect examples of ‘hacks’ – initially ‘designed’ for templating text, they’ve grown into homebrew programming languages that are worse than PHP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Story of Average Indian ‘Techie’</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/story-average-indian-techie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 09:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/story-average-indian-techie/</guid>
      <description>Note: I am just reformatting + putting this in one piece rather than have it split across multiple comments on reddit. Am not the original author
Beautifully laid out by someone in the under-trafficked r/india:
 my state has 300+ engineering colleges and my parents decided that i am going to be an engineer. so, i wrote an exam and got into one institute (luckily i can make it into a good institute where there are campus interviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: December 5, 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-5-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 20:31:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-5-2011/</guid>
      <description>Am migrating to per-day posts now. More granularity + I can fit more info in. The ultimate aim of the DevLog is to keep me on my toes and make sure I don’t relapse into no-productivity hellholes. Daily DevLogs should do a better job at them.
 Spent some more time trying to get Kiwix to compile under OS X. Macports issue fixed, but more issues persist. It’s one damn complicated build system :| Not to mention that OS X sucks balls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog December 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 21:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-december-2011/</guid>
      <description>With me back to a place where I can be completely open about what code I am writing (yay!), I think it’s time I restart my devlog :)
Last time, I was using my old blogging engine, and hand-wrote them in a markdown file on my netbook. Things have changed a lot since then, and this time I’ll be directly writing/publishing them daily from WordPress
–
Dec 4 I finally grokked Indexes in databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learnt from reading “Javascript – The Good Parts”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/learnt-reading-javascript-good-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 10:40:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/learnt-reading-javascript-good-parts/</guid>
      <description>Just finished reading ‘Javascript – The Good Parts’. Here is what I learnt:
 I knew jack shit about JavaScript. I was able to get along so far simply because I knew jQuery and understood how closures work. Holy shit that’s one fucked up language. Quite schizophrenic, saved by almost limitless extensibility/monkey-patchability/watcha-gonna-do-write-a-java-applet-hahaha . If you’re going to write Javascript, you’ll have to subset. Subsetting/augmenting has its own share of problems – primarily that map in your code might not be the same as map in someone else’s code, even if they seem to be working on the same ‘type’ jQuery is incredible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 reasons why people join ‘IT companies’</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/3-reasons-people-join-it-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 08:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/3-reasons-people-join-it-companies/</guid>
      <description>Source: Friend of mine who is sadly ‘training’ at a big ‘IT company’ now (He wishes to remain anonymous, and I could see why)
 Because everyone else did Because parents told Because it will be very sophisticated and relaxing there, with lots of recreational facilities  I’m just going to leave this here, and hope that when this boom does bust, it doesn’t leave too many dead bodies in its wake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Greatest Fear – ‘Flash and Fade’</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/greatest-fear-flash-fade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 03:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/greatest-fear-flash-fade/</guid>
      <description>HP:MORis an awesome fanfic that anyone intent on improving themselves should read. It’s a bit like HHG2G – you don’t read for the storyline (which is jumbled) but for the characters, wit, rationality and humor. Quite a few of those things hit very close to home – if you are a geek, they would perhaps to you too. Highly reccomended.
Of the many quotable parts of that book, here’s one little nugget I found:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Sriram Krishnan (5 years old)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/interview-sriram-krishnan-5-years-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 15:50:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/interview-sriram-krishnan-5-years-old/</guid>
      <description>5 years ago, I was in my 10th and new on the Internet. I had been coding for about 5-6 years already, but mostly with TurboC and VB6/C# (thanks to MSDN CDs I steal from Sudar). And then this interview happened and pushed me farther out into geekland :)
Presenting a reprint from 2006, my interview with Sriram Krishnan, then Microsoftie. Note that the opinions here are of a Sriram 5 years ago, and do not necessarily represent what he thinks now :D And the questions are obviously the questions a younger, naiver (and stupider) Yuvi would’ve asked, so bear with that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Vim setup</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/my-vim-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 22:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/my-vim-setup/</guid>
      <description>I moved from emacs to vim a while ago, and have been steadily accumulating a series of plugins in my .vim. They’re all up in my rather messy dotfiles repo. Here’s a slightly more neatly organized list of the plugins I currently use:
 command-t – File opener and buffer switcher. In-fuckin-credibly useful. vimpress – What I use to blog since moving to wordpress. matchit – Lets % work with html tags commentary – Generic commenting and uncommenting scriptNERDCommenter has replaced commentary due to being more flexible and having more options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fridge at InterviewStreet office</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/the-fridge-at-interviewstreet-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 08:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/the-fridge-at-interviewstreet-office/</guid>
      <description>We bought a fridge two days ago, and spent a day stocking it up. Perhaps it needs a bit more non-liquid content in it, but I think the choco fills and Dark Fantasy biscuits (not to mention the litres of Ice Cream we’ve stocked up on) would do just fine for now :)
And before you start harping on about ‘health’ – the bottom tray has a mysterious cover full of apples shipped from Chennai by mom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-ASCII Characters in HTTP Headers</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/non-ascii-characters-http-headers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 00:56:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/non-ascii-characters-http-headers/</guid>
      <description>I was debugging an issue at work today where a (generated) file refused to download in Chrome, but the same URL worked just fine with wget. I remember reading in the HTTP Spec that HTTP headers can only be lower ASCII, so when wget mangled the output file’s name, the problem was obvious – the file name contained a character that wasn’t in lower ASCII (an accented A). Chrome had borked on encountering it, while wget soldiered on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are a programmer if you can run code in your head</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/programmer-run-code-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 04:09:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/programmer-run-code-head/</guid>
      <description>From HN:
 From my experience, the largest hurdle first time programmers have is being able to execute programs in their head. It takes a cognitive leap to go from the source code in front of them, and what happens at runtime.
 (emphasis mine)
I believe that if you have made that cognitive leap, you can call yourself a programmer. It means you’ve entered into the second hump – you are a programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temptations</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/temptations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 18:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/temptations/</guid>
      <description>Just came across this beautiful piece of conversation that had me doubled up for quite while:
 Him: The Nexus S tempts me. Only 20k.
Her: The Galaxy SII tempts me.
Him: Hehe, that’s way out of my range though.
Him: You tempt me!
Her: Hehe, that’s way out of your range too!
 :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“What is the best way to stop your child becoming an athiest?”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/what-stop-child-athiest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 13:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/what-stop-child-athiest/</guid>
      <description>From the usually boring Yahoo answers, we have this gem of a question:
 What is the best way to stop your child becoming an athiest?
I don’t want any of my children to be punished by God.
 However, it also had this gem of an answer:
 Do not educate them, or expose them to critical thinking, logic or science.
Lie to them constantly about how the world works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SleepSort from 4Chan</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/sleepsort-4chan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2011 01:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/sleepsort-4chan/</guid>
      <description>4Chan isn’t exactly what you’d associate with ‘shit, that’s a cool piece of code!’, but look what I found!
(via HN)
Nice hack. And it is O(N) in bitsize of largest number (Ignoring all the overhead of forking new processes, the problem with the race conditions(Sort 0 and 0.1? How about 0.01 and 0.011?), processor contention, etc,.) They basically delegated the sorting to the process scheduler, treating it as a sort of priority queue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devlog May 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-may-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 13:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-may-2011/</guid>
      <description>May 25-June 13 Loads of things happened.
Finished/polished up ShortUrl. Pending review. Would go into not just tawiki, but possibly all wmf wikis. YAY!
Moved to a dual monitor setup. Dual 23″ Monitors, one Samsung LED and one Acer LCD. Also moved to 8G of RAM. VMs are much less painful now.
Did a few back/forths with the GSoC extension architecture. It’s still blocking, so working with the non-blocking parts of GSoC now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note from Present Self to Future Self: Pre-Book your Travel Tickets</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/note-present-future-self-pre-book-travel-tickets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 08:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/note-present-future-self-pre-book-travel-tickets/</guid>
      <description>Dear Future Me,
I know you don’t want to pre-book travel tickets. You tell yourself that you like the sense of adventure and uncertainity that it gives you. You tell yourself that you need these life expriences.
But I know the truth, ofcourse. You’re just plain ol’ lazy. Too lazy to book your damn tickets. So, get off your ass and book them now. I’ll promise you that I’ll hunt you through time and kill you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So, I broke a law by photographing a clock in a railway station</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/broke-nonexistent-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 15:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/broke-nonexistent-law/</guid>
      <description>(Update 3: Manish (@jimanish) was awesome enough to point me to the official stuff from Railway Ministry (pdf here). It starts off by stating the cause for the rules being strict:
 A case relating to lapses in allowing shooting of a feature film (which resulted inburning/damage of some passenger coaches provided to the party causing a huge loss tothe Railways)
 It then notes that it’s archaic, since you can even shoot from mobile phones, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why working at “Big Co” is unsatisfying</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/working-big-co-unsatisfying/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 13:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/working-big-co-unsatisfying/</guid>
      <description>Update: As usual, good comments at HN.
I’ve been trying to put it in words for a while, and failing utterly every time. swombat gets to the crux of it wonderfully:
 At the same time, something really bothered me about my work. It felt pointless. One project I did (whose output was basically a PPT and Word document outlining the successes and failures of a client project), which took two and a half months, had, as its only apparent purpose, the promotion of the person who had led the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Infosys, TCS or Wipro?” “None”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/infosys-tcs-or-wipro-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 04:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/infosys-tcs-or-wipro-none/</guid>
      <description>Succinctly written post that every engineering college student should read.
Ofcourse, someone should write a post called “CS, EC or EEE?” “Neither” for high school students, because for a lot of people the answer to the question “Should you do Engineering?” is a huge “No”.
The comments section is even more awesome. Choice quotes:
A sympathizer/astroturfer/cognitively dissonant person writes:
 Are you saying that anybody who can browse the internet and knows about the computer can do our jobs?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My New Canon 550D from Flipkart</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/my-new-canon-550d-from-flipkart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 13:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/my-new-canon-550d-from-flipkart/</guid>
      <description>I was finally able to order my Canon 550D from Flipkart. Their customer service was awesome – both on twitter (when the camera was out of stock) and via the phone after it was ordered. I ordered Cash on Delivery, and despite some minor issues with the delivery person (uhm, so I’m supposed to hand over 39k, and then open the box? What if I found a box of bricks?) – I got the camera within 3 working days of ordering it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belated Samsung Galaxy 3 Review</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/belated-samsung-galaxy-3-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 02:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/belated-samsung-galaxy-3-review/</guid>
      <description>Very late one. I’ve been using this since last September (as those of you on twitter and following me would know).
It was on 2.1 for a long, long time – and even after 2.2 came out (first unofficially and then officially) I didn’t upgrade for almost a month (thanks to a missing usb cable and some laziness). I then upgraded to official 2.2, then one of the ‘Stock’ bootloaderless ROMs, and then to InDroid 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving back to WordPress</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/moving-back-to-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 18:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/moving-back-to-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>A while back, I moved my blog (from a wordpress install whose data I lost) to my own platform (HiSlain).
After several close calls, I’m officially moving from HiSlain back to WordPress. I just don’t have enough time to maintain all the things I wanted in a blog platform in HiSlain, hence the move back. However, it satisfied it’s purpose – I learnt to write code I could use, others could use, and others could contribute to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six Years of Blogging and Eleven Years of Coding</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/six-years-of-blogging-and-eleven-years-of-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 09:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/six-years-of-blogging-and-eleven-years-of-coding/</guid>
      <description>It was exactly six years ago that I started blogging. My first blog post ow seems to be rather childish, but considering I was 14 then, maybe it is excusable :)
I’ve moved across several blogging platforms and urls in the meantime (Blogspot, wordpress and now my own custom engine. I’ve sadly lost a good portion of my blogs thanks to a domain loss and a server crash. Sigh.
Also, looks like I’ve been writing code for almost eleven years now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SICP and BrainFuck</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/sicp-and-brainfuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 05:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/sicp-and-brainfuck/</guid>
      <description>No, I’m not going to blow your mind by telling you I’m going to do the SICP exercises in BrainFuck :)
I just wrote my first brainfuck program. Might as well be my last, but not sure. Tape-based turing-ish programing seems fun, so maybe I’ll try that again with something more expressive than brainfuck (or maybe that is pointless?)
And I’m doing the SICP Exercises. In MIT-Scheme. I’ve put them up on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orwell and Huxley</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/orwell-and-huxley/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 21:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/orwell-and-huxley/</guid>
      <description>I just finished 1984. Had finished Animal Farm and Brave New World a while ago. Orwell is scarier, but Huxley seems to be closer to real life already – I know several people (perhaps too many) who wouldn’t flinch at all at the world Huxley created. Scary.
 Sanity is not Statistical
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: April 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-april-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 01:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-april-2011/</guid>
      <description>I’ve started keeping devlogs, recording productive activity every day in an attempt to publicly shame myself into doing productive things. This is the delayed april edition
Apr 30 Impromptu talk at ChennaiPy meet. Then fun discussions at Nerd Dinner. No code, sadly.
Apr 29 Google Instant mostly works on yenWikipedia. Made a release. More exams.
Apr 22 – 28 Nothing much done. Exams and stuff.
Tecoholic forked yenWikipedia and created a Firefox extension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: Mar 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-mar-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 21:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-mar-2011/</guid>
      <description>I’ve started keeping devlogs, recording productive activity every day in an attempt to publicly shame myself into doing productive things. This is the delayed march edition
Mar 20 – 31 More contract work for more money.
My dump patch to meidawiki got commited, then blasted during Code Review. This is what I get for trusting other people’s code blindly, especially after 5 years. Lesson learnt. Fixed all issues, and now waiting for a review before commit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: Feb 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-feb-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2011 21:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-feb-2011/</guid>
      <description>I’ve started keeping devlogs, recording everyday productive activity in an attempt to publicly shaming myselfinto doing something productive everyday. This is the delayed february editin
Links: 32HourStartup, PiTiVi, TEDxSSN
Feb 26 Initial work on Busroutes.in wiki import script.
Feb 25 Audio Save Dialog mostly works now.
Feb 23 Started implementing Audio Name dialog box in PiTiVi. Dad fixed laptop – new Ethernet port, and working speakers.
Feb 22 Started doing layouts for WhyKCGRocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GStreamer 101 at GNOME Asia 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/gstreamer-101-at-gnome-asia-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2011 23:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/gstreamer-101-at-gnome-asia-2011/</guid>
      <description>My GStreamer 101 presentation at GNOME.asia was very wel received. I was quite happy with the way it turned out. Thanks to Ford_Prefect and Bharath Acharya for pulling me in :)
My very minimal slides are here. You can reuse them if you want to.
Sadly, missed the week long hackfest :( Next time!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevLog: Jan 2011</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-jan-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 12:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-jan-2011/</guid>
      <description>I’ve started keeping devlogs, recording everyday ‘productive’ activity I do everyday. Publicly shaming myself into doing something productive every day. Just records for this month, next month on should provide time spent as well. There’s an entry for every day when I’ve touched a computer. I’ll be continuously refining this format, so feedback welcome
Links: 32HourStartup, Busroutes.in Wiki, PiTiVi, Geekweekend
27 Jan More of nothing productive. 32HourStartup is eating into my dev time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NEN First Dot 2010 – What I learnt</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/nen-first-dot-2010-what-i-learnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2011 00:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/nen-first-dot-2010-what-i-learnt/</guid>
      <description>I was part of the team that organized NEN First Dot – a student startup showcase. I was involved from day 0, so I was able to see it evolve from a high-in-the-sky concept to something that actually did happen. It was an incredible experience, to say the least.
What I learnt I was the ‘tech’ guy – working with a few people (Karthik, Arun, Madhu, Dinesh, etc) to take care of most things tech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional Programming Geekweekend at Thoughtworks</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/functional-programming-geekweekend-at-thoughtworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 18:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/functional-programming-geekweekend-at-thoughtworks/</guid>
      <description>[Note: I’ve a rather large backlog of blog posts to do, will push them out as soon as I can]
Saturday (22 Jan 2011) was spent at Geekweekend, organized at Thougtworks Chennai. The event had awesomeness written all over it, even before it started – how can any event where you register through a (rather limited, but still) command line interface on a website be not good? :D
I was late as usual (damn living so far away from everywhere) – and found my way walking through the underbelly of the Kathipara junction thanks to Google Maps’ Walking Directions :P</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enthusiastic Teachers and Naive Implementation of Gauss Seidel Approximations</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/enthusiastic-teachers-and-naive-implementation-of-gauss-seidel-approximations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2010 11:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/enthusiastic-teachers-and-naive-implementation-of-gauss-seidel-approximations/</guid>
      <description>This semester, one of our so called electives (despite the fact that we have no real choice in them) is Numerical Methods. I don’t quite like the actual way the subject is taught – mind numbing, error prone calculations with a calculator. However, the methods are pretty awesome.
The staff explained Gauss Seidel yesterday, and it seemed a straightforward recursive solution to me. So in the break, I cooked up a small python script that gave me all the intermediate answers as well – so for any assignments I could just run them through this and copy it to paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serendipity</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/serendipity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 09:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/serendipity/</guid>
      <description>I’m back at home after travelling almost ten days – ACM ICPC at Coimbatore, One day at Ooty, the last FOSS.in at Bangalore, Nonameconf at Bangalore, and finally chilling out losing at XBox 360 Takken at the [Zynga][z] office.
One thing I’ve realized sharply is that “Life will take you to interesting places and make you do interesting things, if only you let it“
I realized that my days were being pretty much the same all day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Effects for Cheese!</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/more-effects-for-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 02:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/more-effects-for-cheese/</guid>
      <description>Watch two rather handsome1 dudes (daniel and andreas) in this screencast where they show off some more effects (thanks to fargiolas!). Newer effects are easier to add (feels awesome that that was my work) – and more will be on their way :)
footnote: 1: Professional opinion from one of my lady friends :P</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Vim from Emacs</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/moving-to-vim-from-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2010 01:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/moving-to-vim-from-emacs/</guid>
      <description>I moved to Vim from Emacs a while back. I realized I was not using emacs to its fullest extent – I was using it as ‘just a text editor’, and alt-tabbing to gnome-terminal for most of my work. I was using one tool per job anyway, so why not go all the way and use a text editor for a text editor instead of yet another operating system :P</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to increase Cheese’s Burst Mode Photo Count</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/how-to-increase-cheeses-burst-mode-photo-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 14:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/how-to-increase-cheeses-burst-mode-photo-count/</guid>
      <description>“Why does Cheese have a maximum photo count of 100 in burst mode?” questions have popped up quite a few times on the cheese list. It is just a teeny, tiny bug – fixed in master.
The work around is simple:
Till Cheese 2.32
Raise it to whatever value you want in line 8 of /usr/share/cheese/cheese-prefs.ui.
(If you don’t know what version you are running, check Help -&amp;gt; About)
(Fix is just raising the limit from 100 to something that most people will likely not hit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I moved off Arch (on my Netbook)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/why-i-moved-off-arch-on-my-netbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 17:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/why-i-moved-off-arch-on-my-netbook/</guid>
      <description>I posted a while back that I moved to Arch (from Ubuntu) on my Netbook. That was almost two months back. My Arch experiment, sadly, didn’t work out for long. I moved back to Ubuntu within a couple of week’s time. Why?
 Lack of binary packages. I had to build quite a few packages from source because there were no binary packages available. The tilting point was when I figured there were no binary packges for mit-scheme!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to Kerala</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/trip-to-kerala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 21:19:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/trip-to-kerala/</guid>
      <description>I, along with about a 100 other classmates of mine, went on an Industrial Visit to Kerala a few weeks back. It was a 3 day, 4 night affair – and was incredibly fun and refreshing. New friendships were forged, old ones rekindled, temptations resisted, a thousand pictures clicked (thanks to @RohitP’s camera), group dynamics studied and incredible fun had. It was very refreshing (for the most part), and I realized just why vacations are important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging From Under The Table During Class</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/blogging-from-under-the-table-during-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 14:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/blogging-from-under-the-table-during-class/</guid>
      <description>One of the major advantages of my netbook is that I can actually use it in class, under the desk – and most staff won’t notice ;) And even if they do, I can easily and neatly close the lid, put it in standby and become innocent good boy :D
I’ve zoned out from what’s happening in class a long time back. I just looked up, and it’s something I really do like (withheld to protect the name of subject).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running ArchLinux</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/running-archlinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 22:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/running-archlinux/</guid>
      <description>I’m blogging from Arch Linux :D
I’ve been meaning to setup Arch on my netbook for a while, after hearing a lot of people rave about how awesome pacman is and how fast their system is. I didn’t want to spend time on moving to a new distro during my GSoC, so I kept putting it off. Yesterday Ubuntu borked on my netbook for some weird reason (I suspect it was my friend Rathna sitting on it, but might have been because I was thinking of moving to Vim too) – and I took the opportunity to install Arch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ihave a motorbike!</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/ihave-a-motorbike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2010 00:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/ihave-a-motorbike/</guid>
      <description>So, I now have a motorbike!
It’s a Bajaj Platina, and bought off GSoC money from my cousin Sudar. I’ve been learning to ride for a while, and it’s been good. Had my first accident a while back, and started riding again a few days back.
I’m still very conscious about riding. I still think before clutching, braking, changing gears, etc. It hasn’t been internalized in the same way typing on a Keyboard has been – with enough practice (and accidents!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of GSoC 2010</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/the-end-of-gsoc-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 23:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/the-end-of-gsoc-2010/</guid>
      <description>Google Summer of Code ended a while back. Me (and most on #gsoc) agreed on one thing – WHERE DID THOSE 3 MONTHS GO? Amazing time it was – thanks to _ke (Who is frolicking somewhere in Thailand right now), fargiolas and the rest of the GNOME guys (#clutter, #gstreamer and #gtk+ yay!) for making it awesome. #hackers-india was a great venting place too :)
Cheese‘s master needs quite a bit of work before it can be included in GNOME 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Life Balance</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/work-life-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 16:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/work-life-balance/</guid>
      <description>aeoo 221 points222 points223 points 1 day ago* [-]
 recognize that work is something you do to live and isn’t your whole life
 Let’s examine this as objectively as we can manage. Lets assume a 40 hour work week where the employer pays for lunch, as the employer should be doing, which results in a real 8 hour day instead of a 9 hour day. Of course a 9 hour day will work even more in favor of my argument.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheese 2.31.1 Released</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-2-31-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 19:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-2-31-1-released/</guid>
      <description>If you had read my Cheese GSoC proposal, it would’ve stressed on one major point – make Cheese sexy.
Two days ago, one of my classmates spent 5 minutes on the bus using Cheese and trying out different effects (and poses!). Today, my brother spent 20 minutes trying to get the perfect combination of style and vagueness for his Facebook profile picture – using Cheese. He then asked me to create an account for him in Ubuntu (he was an exclusively Win7 user till then) before leaving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Room Full of People Like Me”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/room-full-of-people-like-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 03:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/room-full-of-people-like-me/</guid>
      <description>I would give an arm, a leg, an eye and other assorted body parts if I could find such a room. And live there.
Hackerpace Chennai or The Startup Center better turn up fast :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My GSoC 2010 Proposal</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/my-gsoc-2010-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 02:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/my-gsoc-2010-proposal/</guid>
      <description>I used gist to publish my GSoC proposal. Diffs, easy to show off, and Markdown support – made gist perfect for me to make modifications and get feedback easily.
It is the first ‘real’ document I’ve written – it actually had a tangible effect.
Now that I don’t need to make any modifications, I’ve moved it to my site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheese GSoC Report – Week 8</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-gsoc-report-week-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2010 00:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-gsoc-report-week-8/</guid>
      <description>This week on Cheese….
WE MADE A RELEASE! :)
http://ftp.gnome.org/pub/GNOME/sources/cheese/2.31/
Cheese 2.31.1 is out. It’s a dev release. Does not have zarro boogs.
But it is a release!
This week, we
 Fixed several perf bugs. Fixed some weird preferences dialog bugs Filed (and eventually had fixed) a bug in GStreamer. Fixed a regression Beautified the UI a bit (text name overlay of effects, etc) Assorted administrative work to prepare for release (Copyright  updating, merging back into master, etc)  I also passed my mid terms :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheese GSoC Report – Week 7</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-gsoc-report-week-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 18:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-gsoc-report-week-7/</guid>
      <description>This week on Cheese….
 Performance enhancements. Sacrificed some startup time for much improved usage time. Viewing live effects are now a snap. So is selecting an effect. We went in some cases from ~15s to &amp;lt;1s. Thanks to Tester (and other folks) at #gstreamer for helping out :) Paging of effects. Effects are now in pages of 9 each, instead of a huge scroller area. Applying effects without stopping the pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reddit University – SICP Reading Group</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/reddit-university-sicp-reading-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2010 17:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/reddit-university-sicp-reading-group/</guid>
      <description>I’ve joined Reddit University‘s SICP Reading Group class. I’ve wanted to read through SICP for a long time, and have gotten started many times – never completed it. Maybe the group effects will help me finish this time :)
If you’re interested in expanding your horizons beyond mere code-monkey programming, join up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheese GSoC Report – Week 5</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-gsoc-report-week-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2010 02:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-gsoc-report-week-5/</guid>
      <description>Late report. But I did get quite a bit done!
Last week…
 Video Effects file format reader Live Preview of Effects! (YAY!) Effect files added  Live Preview took most of my time. We bought down CPU usage from ~90% to a more manageable ~50%. Cleaned up code a bit (still needs more cleanup). It is rather very ‘demoable’, provided you gloss over the slowdowns.
Coming up next week would be…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheese GSoC Report – Week 4</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-gsoc-report-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 04:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-gsoc-report-week-4/</guid>
      <description>Fourth week of the Summer of Code was over a few days back, and this report is overdue :( I’ve not been able to code as much as I wanted to this week – due to various non-technical issues. Will compensate in the next week.
Last week…
 Countdown Animations (Thanks to _ke for cleanup!) GConf Cleanup  Yes, that was it.
Totally failed to meet last week’s goals. Sigh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheese GSoC Report – Week 3</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-gsoc-report-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 04:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-gsoc-report-week-3/</guid>
      <description>Third week of the Summer of Code is over! And during this week….
 Successfully wrapped up the core cheese functionality (libcheese) with a vala wrapper Made Photo Mode work Made Video Mode work Made Burst Mode work Made cheese single instance using libunique Started work on cleaning up GConf code.  In last week’s report, I mentioned that I didn’t quite like my pace of work. It is still the same (approx.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheese GSoC Report – Week 2</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-gsoc-report-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2010 04:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-gsoc-report-week-2/</guid>
      <description>Second week of the (rather hot and sweaty) Summer of Code is over! And during this week….
 Replicated most of the UI of Cheese Learnt how to make C and Vala code co-exist (Thanks folks at #vala!) Made the thumbnail widget work, in both modes/orientations Implemented fullscreen mode, with autohiding of the action buttons Started modifying parts of libcheese to support clutter for video output  In last week’s report, I mentioned that I didn’t quite like my pace of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheese GSoC Report – Week 1</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-gsoc-report-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2010 02:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/cheese-gsoc-report-week-1/</guid>
      <description>First week of official coding is over. What do I have to show for it?
 Moved code from Github to GNOME Git (Thanks fargiolas!) Learnt how to use GTKBuilder, and how to autoconnect signals to vala callback functions. Learnt some of the intricacies of Gtk+ Layouts (They still have a lot to teach me!) Got a very basic version of the basic Cheese window up and running. Learnt how to embed Clutter into the Gtk+ base of Cheese.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vala, GTKBuilder and Autoconnecting Signal Handlers</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/vala-gtkbuilder-and-autoconnecting-signal-handlers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2010 02:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/vala-gtkbuilder-and-autoconnecting-signal-handlers/</guid>
      <description>Note: I’m not an expert on Vala, GTK+, or anything else for that matter. If I am off base someplace, comment.
I spent quite a some time today trying to get GTKBuilder to automagically connect all my signals to their handlers. I tripped up at a few places, and so recording them here for posterity.
  If you are using instance methods (like most of us are), you’ve to decorate your handler function with the attribute [CCode (instance_pos=-1)].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Milestones – Vala Build using AutoTools</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/gsoc-milestones-vala-build-using-autotools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2010 07:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/gsoc-milestones-vala-build-using-autotools/</guid>
      <description>I’m using a RTM List to track my milestones for this my GSoC this year. I’ll be making a blog post for each item ticked off that list, to share what I’ve learnt in my journey from n00b to someone whose code is good enough to be included in GNOME. This is part 1 in the series, where I tell you about autotools
My GSoC project involves, moving major parts (UI) of Cheese to a new language – Vala.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Milestone 0 – What does my project do?</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/gsoc-milestone-0-what-does-my-project-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 00:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/gsoc-milestone-0-what-does-my-project-do/</guid>
      <description>I’m using a RTM List to track my milestones for this my GSoC this year. I’ll be making a blog post for each item ticked off that list, to share what I’ve learnt in my journey from n00b to someone whose code is good enough to be included in GNOME. This is part 0 in the series, where I tell you what my project is all about and how Cheese is going to become awesomer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Accepted Patch!</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/my-first-accepted-patch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 19:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/my-first-accepted-patch/</guid>
      <description>As part of my GSoC preparations, I wrote a few patches for Cheese. One of them (a one liner to fix a crash) has made it to GNOME 2.30.1 – the other two (1 and 2) are slightly more significant and involve UI changes, and so will be integrated later.
Free beer to everyone who can catch me in a bar! Free Pepsi/Sprite/Egg Puff to anyone who can catch me in the College Stores ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC 2010 – The Beginning</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/gsoc-2010-the-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 18:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/gsoc-2010-the-beginning/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned this in passing in my earlier post, and was tweeting about it quite furiously – I’ve been selected to work on Cheese for this year’s Google Summer of Code :D
Link to my, uhm, cheesy proposal
What Now? Getting accepted doesn’t mean shit. Actually finishing whatever I was supposed to within 3 months does mean something – especially since I’ve taken on quite a bit of stuff to do (Move to new language + 2 new features).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking more!</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/hacking-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 20:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/hacking-more/</guid>
      <description>Quoting from Steven Levy‘s Hackers:
 [..] a project undertaken or a product built not solely to fulfill
  some constructive goal, but with some wild pleasure taken in mere
  involvement, was called a “hack.”
 Building things for the fun of building them is hacking. And hacking is not illegally breaking into computers.
I like hacking. I want to be a real hacker. I can’t call myself one yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I spent the Day today</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/how-i-spent-the-day-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 02:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/how-i-spent-the-day-today/</guid>
      <description>Wake up at 10. Roll around bed for half an hour. Chase brother away from your computer (on which he was playing GTA (or NFS)). Check mail. Find something to code on, code. Check mail. Check proggit. Check HN. Waste some time on Twitter. Waste some more time on IRC. Check mail. Check proggit. Check HN. Tab around, really fast. Tab around, really fast. Go have breakfast. Or lunch – doesn’t matter what you call it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dokuwiki plugin to easily embed Gists</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/dokuwiki-plugin-to-easily-embed-gists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 19:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/dokuwiki-plugin-to-easily-embed-gists/</guid>
      <description>I love Gist.
I recently started a project that required me to embed gists in Dokuwiki. I hunted around and found no plugins, so created my own. Needs the superawesome command plugin too. Released under the 3 clause BSD License.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCon India 2009</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/pycon-india-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 17:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/pycon-india-2009/</guid>
      <description>Warning: Rambling, unedited, 7 month old recollection ahead. Proceed at your own risk.
Ah, PyCon India 2009. My first solo bit of travel outside Chennai. What fun it was :) Though it was almost 7 months ago, most of the memories are still fresh. Compare that to college, where I struggle to remember what happened last week…
Anyway, it was fun. I went off by bus with the rather interesting Anirudh – a profitable startupeer and someone I met when working with Busroutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webfaction Review</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/webfaction-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 16:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/webfaction-review/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been running yuvi.in and busroutes.in on my [Webfaction][3] account for a while. I got the account for free – after Remi Delon from Webfaction noticed one of my tweets.
Review: I’m going to save that when my free one year plan expires, I can upgrade to one of their better plans. It is so good :)
Highly Reccomended!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samsung N210 Review</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/samsung-n210-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2010 20:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/samsung-n210-review/</guid>
      <description>I bought a brand new Samsung N210 Netbook about two weeks back – and have been using it almost non-stop since. I’ve been taking it to college every day, using it at every oportunity I get – on the college bus, on MTC buses, on the train, while waiting for the train, hell even during a rather very boring class!
The Great  The Screen! The matte screen is totally awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“We must take [India] as it is” – Jules Verne</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/we-must-take-india-as-it-is-jules-verne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 22:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/we-must-take-india-as-it-is-jules-verne/</guid>
      <description>I’ve gotten back to reading fiction ever since I got my netbook (review comin up!). Project Gutenberg has been very helpful. Jules Verne’s Adventures of a Special Correspondent was the first one I completed. It is a good book – but not phenomenal. It does have a few very good moments, and one of them hit extremely close to home.
Towards the end, when Claudius Bombarnac rumbles about how the Chinese do not make full use of the engine’s power – always keeping it running at 40 mph even though it could be pushed to do way more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Binary Dream</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/first-binary-dream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 13:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/first-binary-dream/</guid>
      <description>I had my first ever dream in binary today.
The cycle moved like this:
Borg -&amp;gt; nanoprobes -&amp;gt; a scene in Minority Report when nanobots go around looking for John Anderton (Tom Cruise), who was hiding in a bathtub full of water -&amp;gt; Will Smith and his Dog cuddling in a bathtub in I am Legend -&amp;gt; the climax of I am Legend when Will Smith blows himself up to save the others -&amp;gt; A column of binary numbers came up, showing state of Will Smith as ‘SAD’ AND MSB FLIPPED TO ZERO, and then he has this epiphany (Realization of God Moment) and becomes ‘HAPPY’ and the MSB FLIPS TO ONE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure of Learning: Epiphanies per Session</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/measure-of-learning-epiphanies-per-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 03:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/measure-of-learning-epiphanies-per-session/</guid>
      <description>The measure of code quality is WTFs/minute.
I just realized, after a rather intriguing facebook conversation with Shiva, that the only true measure of learning is Epiphanies per Session.
My latest Epiphany was a couple of days back. And the one before that was a month or so back, when I was ‘pairing’ with Sid. I think the one before that was quite some time back – when I understood the true meaning of closures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2010 – The Beginning, the bicycle ride and external dependencies</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/2010-the-beginning-the-bicycle-ride-and-external-dependencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 01:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/2010-the-beginning-the-bicycle-ride-and-external-dependencies/</guid>
      <description>I was writing a post on how 2009 ended. Here is the tl;dr version: It was my ‘growing-up’ year in Tech, and ‘roller-coaster’ year in personal stuff. There! I’m certainly significantly wiser at the end of 2009, and that is due more to my state at the beginning of 2009 than at the end :) Good enough
So how did I celebrate? By joining the KPP competition at Kurukshetra. That’s what I did at around 12 on New Year’s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Python Workshop</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/the-python-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2009 02:53:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/the-python-workshop/</guid>
      <description>We had a python workshop at college a week back.
One hellova workshop it was! Kausik conducted it, and about 14 people turned up (We picked 15, one girl had to miss it ‘coz of fever). Every single one of them was there because they wanted to be there. This happened during semester holidays, so they came to college just for this. And from the feedback (and the actions that followed it) I got, it was worth their while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I lack</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/what-i-lack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2009 03:52:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/what-i-lack/</guid>
      <description>Commitment.
I keep jumping around. My GitHub profile is proof for that. So are the large number of projects I’ve taken up only to leave in the middle. Unless and until I fix my commitment issues, I’ll be just-another-guy-who-learnt-to-code-in-his-teens, not the-guy-who-changed-the-world. Just reading a lot of stuff isn’t going to do me any good unless I actually get off my ass and do something.
Hopefully, putting this up in public will make it more real.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Block cursor vs Post Cursor (gVim vs Emacs)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/block-cursor-vs-post-cursor-gvim-vs-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 00:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/block-cursor-vs-post-cursor-gvim-vs-emacs/</guid>
      <description>Here is an approximate timeline of the editors I’ve used so far:
 Turbo C++ (4th grade to 8th grade) Visual Basic 6 (8th grade to 10th grade) Visual Studio 2005 (10th grade to 11th grade) Visual Studio 2008 (11th grade to 1st year of college) gVim (1st year of college) GNU Emacs (after gVim)  Now, the one thing, maybe even the only thing I miss is the fact that gVim gives me the I-Bar cursor, while Emacs by default gave me the block cursor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect Day #1</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/perfect-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 00:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/perfect-day-1/</guid>
      <description>So, I wake up at noon.
And my phone doesn’t work.
Then I find out my Internet doesn’t work.
Then I find my TV’s crapped.
Then I find that I’ve to go to college tomorrow.
The last thing is good. The others aren’t. Oh well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy of an impromptu hackathon (Git vs SVN)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/anatomy-of-an-impromptu-hackathon-git-vs-svn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2009 12:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/anatomy-of-an-impromptu-hackathon-git-vs-svn/</guid>
      <description>One of the (good) things that came out of the IIT Hackfest was me hanging out on the #hackers-india IRC channel. It is wild, swingy and usually fun. Usually.
So yesterday night, ideamonk casually mentioned that he was working on something called pymos. It was a python script that made mosiacs. Now that was something I was totally interested in – I tried making a similar ‘script’ a long time back (in C#), and totally utterly failed, simply because I was so caught up with the part that downloaded pictures from flickr that I didn’t do the part that generated the actual Mosaic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I got rid of my fork of Waffle</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/why-i-got-rid-of-my-fork-of-waffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2009 00:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/why-i-got-rid-of-my-fork-of-waffle/</guid>
      <description>For those of you who didn’t know, Waffle is a schemaless storage layer that sits on top of SQLAlchemy. Something that I was initially very interested in.
Not anymore.
Why?
Because I found MongoDB.
And fell in love.
Yes, I do know they both are different, but MongoDB has the things that attracted me to Waffle (very flexible schema, great querying, indexes) and is just as easy to set up (maybe not as easy as Waffle over SQLite, but only slightly less easier).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attraction or Admiration</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/attraction-or-admiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2009 22:28:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/attraction-or-admiration/</guid>
      <description>If you are a college student, especially my college’s student, please go read this. I wish Divya had written this a year and a half back. :D</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I learnt from the Hackfest at IITM</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/what-i-learnt-from-the-hackfest-at-iitm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2009 23:10:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/what-i-learnt-from-the-hackfest-at-iitm/</guid>
      <description>I was about to just type a list of stuff here, but that doesn’t do the topic justice. So here I am, at 3:30 in the morning, sleep cycle screwed up by the Hackfest, typing out a post on what all I learnt from there. I spent pretty much my entire awake-time at the IIT, so it helped me a lot.
Your college doesn’t matter much IIT Envy. Every non-IITian has that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackfest ’09 – Expectations</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/hackfest-09-expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 01:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/hackfest-09-expectations/</guid>
      <description>I’m going to participate in Hackfest at IITM’s Shaastra, starting tomorrow. Will hopefully be a lot of fun – and may I be able to contribute my first ever patch during the event ;) Got permission to not get back home – but wondering, where would I stay? Probably pass out in front of the computers :)
I’ll be hackin on GNOME Apps – hopefully Banshee (since that’s one app I love), or write a newish, smallish app with PyGTK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code I’ve written so far</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/code-ive-written-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 00:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/code-ive-written-so-far/</guid>
      <description>Code I have written so far:
 HiSlain: A static blog publishing system (NOT A DJANGO BLOG!). Runs this blog wtfimb: The code that powers Busroutes.in frailgrey: Markov Chain based page generator (pretty lame, actually) GoodFather: Collection of utils for web data scraping and storing reappy: A Twitter Search Application Framework SadIvy: A pure WSGI URL Shortener  Now, I’ve been doing a shit job of documenting them – none exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learnt from working with the Symposium</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/lessons-learnt-from-working-with-the-symposium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 23:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/lessons-learnt-from-working-with-the-symposium/</guid>
      <description>Document Everything! On paper. Will save you from hell later. There is never enough time. Start earlier than you think is early enough. Sell people things. Make them want it. Think from their point of view. Prioritize. Delegate. Responsibly. And follow up. Know when to stop. Recognize when something is good enough. Printing takes a long time. Very long timeE. And is boring. People often do not mean what they say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICC Rules for Backyard Cricket</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/icc-rules-for-backyard-cricket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2009 18:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/icc-rules-for-backyard-cricket/</guid>
      <description>ICC’s Code of Conduct for Backyard Cricket. We followed every single one of them religiously :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3hours of code &amp; 1 blog post per day</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/3hours-of-code-1-blog-post-per-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 00:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/3hours-of-code-1-blog-post-per-day/</guid>
      <description>Those are my new goals.
I’ve got a mechanism to track the code accomplishments (will make that public soon), and maybe I’ll write a widget for HiSlain for the blog post/day accomplishment.
I’m liking it so far – 7 hours of code yesterday, along with 2 blog posts. Couldn’t hit my code target today – but am hitting my blog target. I should figure out more ways to make this work better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCon 2009 – Are you coming?</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/pycon-2009-are-you-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 00:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/pycon-2009-are-you-coming/</guid>
      <description>I’m going to PyCon India 2009. Are you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Premature Greying</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/premature-greying/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2009 16:02:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/premature-greying/</guid>
      <description>He liked her. Very much. He had never felt like that before. The butterflies in his stomach were beating up a storm. He had never believed in love at first sight. Till he saw her.
Her waitress uniform made her look cuter than ever. He knew he had to ask her out. He drummed up enough courage, went to her and said ‘Hi’.
She turned, gave him a cute smile, and replied ‘Hello uncle, what can I do for you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoKrish: Because we don’t get enough jilpa</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/autokrish-because-we-dont-get-enough-jilpa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 02:03:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/autokrish-because-we-dont-get-enough-jilpa/</guid>
      <description>I dig KrishAshok‘s writing. Been lurking there for a long time.
Only problem is, he doesn’t write often. Nor does he tweet often.
Only solution is, ofcourse, to create a bot that writes like him, and another bot that tweets like him.
UPDATE: Some of my favorites: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, etc. Too many to list :)
UPDATE 2: Absolute Ripper</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Automatic Quote Generators (aka AutoPeople)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/the-automatic-quote-generators-aka-autopeople/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 01:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/the-automatic-quote-generators-aka-autopeople/</guid>
      <description>An Automatic Quote Generator – generates sound bites that almost sound like someone else, and are somtimes funny as hell:
 AutoFreya, emulating the doubtfully-anonymous-teen Freya AutoLG, for popular blogger Louis Gray AutoMona, for, well, I can’t describe who Mona is yet. I haven’t figured out. Just someone cool, maybe? AutoAtwood, for one of the few for-the-masses dev coder Jeff Atwood  A few of them (@AutoLG &amp;amp; @AutoMona) also have twiwtter bots for them, posting short tweets once every seven minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABigger, binary heart</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/abigger-binary-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 23:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/abigger-binary-heart/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New email id</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/new-email-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 00:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/new-email-id/</guid>
      <description>I’ve got a new email id.
It’s me@yuvisense.net
Groovy, uh? ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alone</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 00:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/alone/</guid>
      <description>He was sitting in class. Bored. He looked around. He saw sixty other people, but felt alone. He stood up, shouted ‘Why am I here?!? This won’t do!’ and walked out of the class, leaving everyone confused and weirded out.
He moved out of the campus, and saw sixty thousand other people. He still felt alone. He realized the problem is not the world, but him. Within the next few hours, the problem went away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carrier Error</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/carrier-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 20:55:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/carrier-error/</guid>
      <description>The bus lurched to one side, and fell of the bridge. He felt his skull crack. He realized he had just seconds to live. One hand immobilized, he used the other to find the mobile. Two well practiced presses later, he was at the Compose Message screen. Five seconds later, he had the words ‘love ya’ typed out. He hit send, and died peacefully.
Five second later, an error popped up on the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chennai’s Concentration camps (aka Colleges)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/chennais-concentration-camps-aka-colleges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 09:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/chennais-concentration-camps-aka-colleges/</guid>
      <description>As someone with a lot of friends in these concentration camps, I can say that this is SPOT ON.
(Subtitles by Krish Ashok)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Picks from autogenerated Freya Quotes (NSFW?)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/picks-from-autogenerated-freya-quotes-nsfw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2009 23:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/picks-from-autogenerated-freya-quotes-nsfw/</guid>
      <description>I love autogenerating text.
So I ran Freya’s Blog through a markov chain text generator, and it came up with a ton of potentially funny quotes that had me in splits for a while. Here are the best:
 They say its gonna kill me But still, his eyes are in no way good. Thank God I never pick it up. But hello, which parent accompanies a full-grown daughter to her lover When you win, nobody knows that she’s thinking of marriage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Highligting Plugin for HiSlain</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/code-highligting-plugin-for-hislain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 23:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/code-highligting-plugin-for-hislain/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been hacking ’round with HiSlain, and wrote a syntax highlighting plugin for it. Nothing fancy – just uses Pygments, but the process of modifying the plugin architecture to support this has been an awesome ride. I’ll probably open up a new GitHub project just for HiSlain Themes and Plugins.
And since I’ve to test out Syntax Highlighting,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress on HiSlain #1</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/progress-on-hislain-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 23:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/progress-on-hislain-1/</guid>
      <description>Small status update on my blogging platform‘s progress.
I’ve got the plugin infrastructure (mostly) in. Google Analytics Plugin and the RSS link plugin are working :)
Next Step is to make DISQUS a plugin too, and then I can start on porting themes!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I’m jealous of her</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/im-jealous-of-her/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/im-jealous-of-her/</guid>
      <description>I’m Jealous of Freya. I can’t really seem to figure out why.
Okay, I think I can. Guess it’s the anonymity. That she can write whatever se wants, without caring a damn.
I can’t. :(
Go, get jealous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treat of a Lifetime</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/treat-of-a-lifetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2009 23:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/treat-of-a-lifetime/</guid>
      <description>I promise her ‘the Treat of a Lifetime’. I cook up a reason realistic enough for her to buy it. I bribe off everyone else to make sure she is alone. And she is.
We walk along the sides of a typical city street. She is talking – she always is. When has she ever been quiet? Quiet is an adjective one doesn’t use with the noun ‘girl’. And she’s no ordinary girl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My involvement in Novelrace</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/my-involvement-in-novelrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2009 19:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/my-involvement-in-novelrace/</guid>
      <description>It started when @msnarain pinged me one day and asked if I could help out with a small project involving twitter. I asked how small – and he described what would later on become http://novelrace.in. It ended up being pretty small – about 150 lines of code, excluding styles and stuff. Not bad, eh?
Oh, and if you have no idea what novelrace is – this post should clear things up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cute Dress</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/cute-dress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 23:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/cute-dress/</guid>
      <description>Should I tell her?
I shouldn’t.
I don’t even know her. She’s new in class. So am I. We’re all new in this class. We are first years, at the first day of college.
I don’t even know her name! And she obviously doesn’t know my name. We are, for all intents and purposes, complete strangers in the same class.
What if she takes it seriously? I’ll probably be branded the classholic flirt of the class, and never be taken seriously ever again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 02:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/emacs/</guid>
      <description>He was coding.
He was on a bus, and coding. He had bought himself a cute little black Netbook just so he could open up Vim on a bus and code Python. He is a geek. A young, 18 year old typical geek. As typical as your usual geek.
The bus was quite empty. It was late at night, this was proably the last bus for the day, and except the Driver &amp;amp; Conductor, there were probably 4 people on the bus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isoooo want this on a T-Shirt</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/isoooo-want-this-on-a-t-shirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 01:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/isoooo-want-this-on-a-t-shirt/</guid>
      <description>Seirously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evanescence: Enjoyed best without the Music Vids</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/evanescence-enjoyed-best-without-the-music-vids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 17:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/evanescence-enjoyed-best-without-the-music-vids/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shirts</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/shirts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 15:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/shirts/</guid>
      <description>My shirts went from L to M
My pants went from 40 to 34
I’m awesome :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I need time to do</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/things-i-need-time-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 11:47:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/things-i-need-time-to-do/</guid>
      <description>Put on muscle/reduce weight. Master jQuery Learn CSS Process photos and put them up on flickr Put up college’s (awesome) dance videos on Facebook and Youtube Go out more. Fix my glasses. Get ontacts if possible – or change my frames. Write stats posts. Develop goodfather Add a plugin system to HiSlain Publish a paper or two! (yeah, I know) Blog more (duh) Go out more. Learn to bike (of the petrol eating variety, that is) Go out more Photograph more Kick everyone’s ass in studies (I can do that this sem, we have 3 CS papers!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World, Again!</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/hello-world-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 10:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/hello-world-again/</guid>
      <description>I’m Yuvi. This is my second blog. My old one has been retired because, well, it’s old! It contained too much ranting. It has content from me since I was 14 – a lot of that is just plain stupid, and a few are even embarassingly inaccurate &amp;amp; naive. You can still possibly checkout the old blog – if I manage to get the content back :)
This new blog will be about me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Life</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/optimizing-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 10:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/optimizing-life/</guid>
      <description>Geeks Optimize Life. True that. I do optimize the short route from when I get down from my college bus to my home, and me and Sudar did have an argument about optimization when we took the train together one day. My argument was that the distance you are going to walk is constant anyway (you either walk it at the station you are boarding the train, or where you are getting down), so moving to the extreme end of the train is pointless.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
