<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning on Yuvi Panda</title>
    <link>http://words.yuvi.in/tags/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning on Yuvi Panda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 22:47:06 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://words.yuvi.in/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>designing data intensive applications</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/designing-data-intensive-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 22:47:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/designing-data-intensive-applications/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading Designing Data Intensive Applications book &amp;amp; am using this post to keep notes!
I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up ideas on scaling systems through the years, but never actually sat down to actually study them semi-formally. This seems like a great start to it!
It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty big book, and it&amp;rsquo;s gonna take me a while to go through it :) Will update these notes as I go! Trying to do a chapter a week!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>think os</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/think-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 11:41:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/think-os/</guid>
      <description>Following a trail from a wonderful Julia Evans post led me to Allen Downey&amp;rsquo;s nice textbook manifesto. Also led me to the nice Think OS book, which seems like a super nice introduction to Operating System principles.
It is short enough (~100 pages) that I wanted to read through it. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a good chunk of time absorbing how Operating Systems work by dint of diving into things and working through them, but it would be nice to get a refresher on the basics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>learning selinux and apparmor</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/learning-selinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:01:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/learning-selinux/</guid>
      <description>I am trying to understand SELinux and AppArmor, and collecting resources here as I learn. k
SELinux for mere mortals (2014)  This was the first video I watched, and it helped me understanding what SELinux does at a fundamental basic level. It&amp;rsquo;s probably useless in a container-filled world (where I doubt Fedora shipes pre-configured SELinux rules for my containers), but it helped me think I understood types / labels, so that seems like a positive step?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>things to build</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/things-to-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 13:24:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/things-to-build/</guid>
      <description>This is a running list of things I want to build!
There&amp;rsquo;s an analogous running list of things I want to learn. Things move between them :) I also have higher standards of documentation (other people should be able to use it) before marking these as complete.
 kubernetes-login A helper to openssh that allows users to log in to a configurable user pod running on a kubernetes cluster. Should ideally support scp / sftp too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>python gil resources</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/python-gil-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 23:18:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/python-gil-resources/</guid>
      <description>I was in a conversation about the Python GIL with friends a few days ago, and realized that my understanding of the specifics of the GIL problem were super hand-wavy &amp;amp; unstructured. So I spent some time collecting resources to learn more, and now have a better understanding!
Python&amp;rsquo;s Infamous GIL (Larry Hastings) This was a great introduction to the history of the GIL, why it was necessary &amp;amp; reasons why getting rid of it is complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systemd simple containment for GUI applications &amp; shells</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/systemd-simple-containment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 23:23:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/systemd-simple-containment/</guid>
      <description>I earlier had a vaguely working setup for making sure browsers, shells and other applications don&amp;rsquo;t eat all RAM / CPU on my machine with systemd + sudo + shell scripts.
It was a hacky solution, and also had complications when used to launch shells. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t passing in all the environment varialbes it should, causing interesting-to-debug issues. sudo rules were complex, and hard to do securely.
I had also been looking for an excuse to learn more Golang, so I ended up writing systemd-simple-containment or ssc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>systemd gui applications</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/systemd-gui-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 20:47:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/systemd-gui-applications/</guid>
      <description>Update: There&amp;rsquo;s a follow-up post with a simpler solution now.
Ever since I read Jessie Frazelle&amp;rsquo;s amazing setup (1, 2, 3) for running GUI applications in docker containers, I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do something similar. However, I want to install things on my computer - not in docker images. So what I wanted was just isolation (no more Chrome / Firefox freezing my laptop), not images. I&amp;rsquo;m also not as awesome (or knowledgeable!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>things to learn</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/things-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 15:27:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/things-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>Keeping a running list of things I want to learn!
There&amp;rsquo;s also a list of things I want to build.
 How to use org mode properly? Should I use it for notes over markdown? Develop a deep understanding of how networks work. How do linux network namespaces work? How to run GUI apps with systemd?  I did learn! Both a hacky version and a much better version that also taught me some Go!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>