<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resistance on Yuvi Panda</title>
    <link>http://words.yuvi.in/tags/resistance/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resistance on Yuvi Panda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC0</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://words.yuvi.in/tags/resistance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>my first protest</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/post/first-protest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 22:37:21 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/post/first-protest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to the protests at SFO last weekend. It was the first real set of protests I&amp;rsquo;ve been to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was there for about 10h on day 1, and came home exhausted. I went back on Day 2, and this time stayed for much shorter period of time (~4h?) before heading back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To everyone who was at the protest even if it does not directly affect you yet - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the wonderful amazing women of color who were leading the protest - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;. You are an inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the brass band and the troupe of drummers who showed up - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the people I already know from other contexts who I ran into at the protest - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To those who were protesting for the first time in their lives (as I was) - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the fucking ACLU - &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt;! I&amp;rsquo;ll send you all the money I can :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up that saturday feeling very depressed, angry, and helpless. By sunday night, I was only depressed and angry - but not helpless. The number and variety of people at the protests was very heartwarming, and made me feel distinctly not alone. Before going I was not sure what going to a protest accomplishes. I still do not know - but I know it gave me hope and restored my sense of agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I promise I&amp;rsquo;ll continue doing all I can, even and especially when it is about things that do not affect me yet. I hope you do too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What hurts the victim most is not the cruelty of the oppressor but the silence of the bystander&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- from a sign at the protest&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>