<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>So-Called-IT on Yuvi</title>
    <link>https://words.yuvi.in/categories/so-called-it/</link>
    <description>Recent content in So-Called-IT on Yuvi</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 07:12:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://words.yuvi.in/categories/so-called-it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Can’t take the India out of the W3C…</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/cant-take-the-india-out-of-the-w3c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 07:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/cant-take-the-india-out-of-the-w3c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Presenting, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3cindia.in/HTML5-tour-2013/index.html&#34;&gt;W3C India website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;apparently&lt;/em&gt; from 2013. Funniest bit was probably:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Best view in IE 9+, latest version of chrome, mozilla, opera and safari.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Number of interactions with &lt;a href=&#34;http://cdac.in/&#34;&gt;CDAC&lt;/a&gt; that have given me faith in any semblance of their competence: 0&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entitled to an Outsourced Job</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/entitled-outsourced-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 21:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/entitled-outsourced-job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trigger warning: Completely inappropriate background music for the subject matter being discussed&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I ran into &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=0hY1_5NWaa4&#34;&gt;this very interesting video&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.senthil.me/&#34;&gt;Senthil&lt;/a&gt;‘s facebook feed. The part that I found most interesting was the sense of entitlement – that despite not knowing anything about what they are going to be hired for (aka Programming), and admitting it to everyone, they still expect to be given jobs when they want.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While this would make sense in someplace like the military, where you go in and then train, it makes no sense for graduates of an engineering program, where they spent 4 years of their life training. They claim that t&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 13px;&#34;&gt;hey spent four years studying programming but can not pass a simple written programming test, and do not want to even attempt writing it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Vague Sense of Order, No Sense of Purpose</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/vague-sense-order-sense-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 06:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/vague-sense-order-sense-purpose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month I spent a couple of days as a ‘guest’ at Infosys Mahindra City (district finals for &lt;a href=&#34;http://campusconnect.infosys.com/Aspirations/&#34;&gt;Aspirations 2020&lt;/a&gt; – a TopCoder style programming competition). Interesting experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No laptops allowed. No storage devices either. Cameras are okay, but “&lt;em&gt;please don’t take pictures”&lt;/em&gt;. Phones are okay too. The usual complimentary grope as you enter. Random security guards ask “&lt;em&gt;Where is your ID card?”&lt;/em&gt; at random times. Buses bringing in hordes of people. Couples being couply in food courts. Reasonably good food. Formal clothes, without regard to the weather.  Everyone smiles when talking (unless they’re security guards). Respectful deference to hierarchical authority (with a big smile &amp;amp; explicit announcements of gratefulness). Unlocked cycles to travel around the campus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Story of Average Indian ‘Techie’</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/story-average-indian-techie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 09:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/story-average-indian-techie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: I am just reformatting + putting this in one piece rather than have it split across multiple comments on reddit. Am not the original author&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/n1ddk/why_i_will_never_feel_threatened_by_programmers/c35juok&#34;&gt;Beautifully laid out by someone&lt;/a&gt; in the under-trafficked &lt;a href=&#34;http://reddit.com/r/india&#34;&gt;r/india&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;my state has 300+ engineering colleges and my parents decided that i am going to be an engineer. so, i wrote an exam and got into one institute (luckily i can make it into a good institute where there are campus interviews.. the luck being i might have gotten 2 multiple choice questions correct than an unfortunate guy who will be discarded by our society)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 reasons why people join ‘IT companies’</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/3-reasons-people-join-it-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 08:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/3-reasons-people-join-it-companies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Friend of mine who is sadly ‘training’ at a big ‘IT company’ now (He wishes to remain anonymous, and I could see why)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Because everyone else did&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Because parents told&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Because it will be very sophisticated and relaxing there, with lots of recreational facilities&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m just going to leave this here, and hope that when this boom does bust, it doesn’t leave too many dead bodies in its wake.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why working at “Big Co” is unsatisfying</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/working-big-co-unsatisfying/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 13:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/working-big-co-unsatisfying/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; As usual, &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=2636486&#34;&gt;good comments at HN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to put it in words for a while, and failing utterly every time. &lt;a href=&#34;http://swombat.com/&#34;&gt;swombat&lt;/a&gt; gets to the crux of it wonderfully:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the same time, something really bothered me about my work. &lt;strong&gt;It felt pointless.&lt;/strong&gt; One project I did (whose output was basically a PPT and Word document outlining the successes and failures of a client project), which took two and a half months, had, as its only apparent purpose, the promotion of the person who had led the project. Accenture was paid (quite well) so that I would sit there and produce a piece of paper that justified this person’s promotion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Infosys, TCS or Wipro?” “None”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/infosys-tcs-or-wipro-none/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 04:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/infosys-tcs-or-wipro-none/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.susam.in/2011/05/infosys-tcs-or-wipro.html&#34;&gt;Succinctly written post that every engineering college student should read&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ofcourse, someone should write a post called “CS, EC or EEE?” “Neither” for high school students, because for a lot of people the answer to the question “Should you do Engineering?” is a huge “No”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The comments section is even more awesome. Choice quotes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A sympathizer/astroturfer/cognitively dissonant person writes:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are you saying that anybody who can browse the internet and knows about the computer can do our jobs? Don’t you think we would find that a bit insulting? It might be true in many cases where the proper training can make a monkey do our jobs, but isn’t that true for many fields? Aren’t monkeys being trained to pilot airships?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
