<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>education on Yuvi Panda</title>
    <link>http://words.yuvi.in/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in education on Yuvi Panda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 09:37:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://words.yuvi.in/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Story of Average Indian ‘Techie’</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/story-average-indian-techie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 09:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/story-average-indian-techie/</guid>
      <description>Note: I am just reformatting + putting this in one piece rather than have it split across multiple comments on reddit. Am not the original author
Beautifully laid out by someone in the under-trafficked r/india:
 my state has 300+ engineering colleges and my parents decided that i am going to be an engineer. so, i wrote an exam and got into one institute (luckily i can make it into a good institute where there are campus interviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 reasons why people join ‘IT companies’</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/3-reasons-people-join-it-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 08:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/3-reasons-people-join-it-companies/</guid>
      <description>Source: Friend of mine who is sadly ‘training’ at a big ‘IT company’ now (He wishes to remain anonymous, and I could see why)
 Because everyone else did Because parents told Because it will be very sophisticated and relaxing there, with lots of recreational facilities  I’m just going to leave this here, and hope that when this boom does bust, it doesn’t leave too many dead bodies in its wake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“What is the best way to stop your child becoming an athiest?”</title>
      <link>http://words.yuvi.in/what-stop-child-athiest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 13:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://words.yuvi.in/what-stop-child-athiest/</guid>
      <description>From the usually boring Yahoo answers, we have this gem of a question:
 What is the best way to stop your child becoming an athiest?
I don’t want any of my children to be punished by God.
 However, it also had this gem of an answer:
 Do not educate them, or expose them to critical thinking, logic or science.
Lie to them constantly about how the world works.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>