<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on Yuvi Panda</title>
    <link>https://words.yuvi.in/categories/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on Yuvi Panda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 07:55:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://words.yuvi.in/categories/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DevLog for 2015 Dec 18</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-2015-dec-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 07:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/devlog-2015-dec-18/</guid>
      <description>Haven’t done these in a while, let’s see if I can get this back on the wagon!
 Discovered the WikiChatter library (thanks to @halfak!), and using that in my Teahouse analysis notebook. Far better than writing my own parser and fighting with that. Lets me get on with the actual fun stuff I wanted to do (which is the actual analysis) Learning about pandas, checking out matplotlib, bokeh and wordcloud libraries to use in the analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global merge of accounts at Wikimedia</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/global-merge-accounts-wikimedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2015 12:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/global-merge-accounts-wikimedia/</guid>
      <description>is now slowly happening, and I am the test subject!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terry Prachett on the word ‘synergistically’</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/terry-prachett-word-synergistically/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 15:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/terry-prachett-word-synergistically/</guid>
      <description> You had to admire the way perfectly innocent words were mugged, ravished, stripped of all true meaning and decency and then sent to walk the gutter for Reacher Gilt, although ‘synergistically’ had probably been a whore from the start Going Postal, Terry Prachett </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with Sriram Krishnan (5 years old)</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/interview-sriram-krishnan-5-years-old/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 15:50:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/interview-sriram-krishnan-5-years-old/</guid>
      <description>5 years ago, I was in my 10th and new on the Internet. I had been coding for about 5-6 years already, but mostly with TurboC and VB6/C# (thanks to MSDN CDs I steal from Sudar). And then this interview happened and pushed me farther out into geekland :)
Presenting a reprint from 2006, my interview with Sriram Krishnan, then Microsoftie. Note that the opinions here are of a Sriram 5 years ago, and do not necessarily represent what he thinks now :D And the questions are obviously the questions a younger, naiver (and stupider) Yuvi would’ve asked, so bear with that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“What is the best way to stop your child becoming an athiest?”</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/what-stop-child-athiest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 13:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/what-stop-child-athiest/</guid>
      <description>From the usually boring Yahoo answers, we have this gem of a question:
 What is the best way to stop your child becoming an athiest?
I don’t want any of my children to be punished by God.
 However, it also had this gem of an answer:
 Do not educate them, or expose them to critical thinking, logic or science.
Lie to them constantly about how the world works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belated Samsung Galaxy 3 Review</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/belated-samsung-galaxy-3-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 02:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/belated-samsung-galaxy-3-review/</guid>
      <description>Very late one. I’ve been using this since last September (as those of you on twitter and following me would know).
It was on 2.1 for a long, long time – and even after 2.2 came out (first unofficially and then officially) I didn’t upgrade for almost a month (thanks to a missing usb cable and some laziness). I then upgraded to official 2.2, then one of the ‘Stock’ bootloaderless ROMs, and then to InDroid 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving back to WordPress</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/moving-back-to-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 18:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/moving-back-to-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>A while back, I moved my blog (from a wordpress install whose data I lost) to my own platform (HiSlain).
After several close calls, I’m officially moving from HiSlain back to WordPress. I just don’t have enough time to maintain all the things I wanted in a blog platform in HiSlain, hence the move back. However, it satisfied it’s purpose – I learnt to write code I could use, others could use, and others could contribute to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Webfaction Review</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/webfaction-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 16:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/webfaction-review/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been running yuvi.in and busroutes.in on my [Webfaction][3] account for a while. I got the account for free – after Remi Delon from Webfaction noticed one of my tweets.
Review: I’m going to save that when my free one year plan expires, I can upgrade to one of their better plans. It is so good :)
Highly Reccomended!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samsung N210 Review</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/samsung-n210-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2010 20:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/samsung-n210-review/</guid>
      <description>I bought a brand new Samsung N210 Netbook about two weeks back – and have been using it almost non-stop since. I’ve been taking it to college every day, using it at every oportunity I get – on the college bus, on MTC buses, on the train, while waiting for the train, hell even during a rather very boring class!
The Great  The Screen! The matte screen is totally awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“We must take [India] as it is” – Jules Verne</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/we-must-take-india-as-it-is-jules-verne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 22:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/we-must-take-india-as-it-is-jules-verne/</guid>
      <description>I’ve gotten back to reading fiction ever since I got my netbook (review comin up!). Project Gutenberg has been very helpful. Jules Verne’s Adventures of a Special Correspondent was the first one I completed. It is a good book – but not phenomenal. It does have a few very good moments, and one of them hit extremely close to home.
Towards the end, when Claudius Bombarnac rumbles about how the Chinese do not make full use of the engine’s power – always keeping it running at 40 mph even though it could be pushed to do way more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICC Rules for Backyard Cricket</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/icc-rules-for-backyard-cricket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2009 18:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/icc-rules-for-backyard-cricket/</guid>
      <description>ICC’s Code of Conduct for Backyard Cricket. We followed every single one of them religiously :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABigger, binary heart</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/abigger-binary-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 23:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/abigger-binary-heart/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World, Again!</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/hello-world-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 10:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/hello-world-again/</guid>
      <description>I’m Yuvi. This is my second blog. My old one has been retired because, well, it’s old! It contained too much ranting. It has content from me since I was 14 – a lot of that is just plain stupid, and a few are even embarassingly inaccurate &amp;amp; naive. You can still possibly checkout the old blog – if I manage to get the content back :)
This new blog will be about me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
