<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>github on Yuvi</title>
    <link>https://words.yuvi.in/categories/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in github on Yuvi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 23:17:53 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://words.yuvi.in/categories/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Installing Python (and other packages) from conda-forge in GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/conda-forge-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 23:17:53 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/conda-forge-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>Alex Merose asked me on Mastodon how to best set up a conda environment on GitHub Actions. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a short blog post about it!&#xA;The short version is, use the conda-incubator/setup-miniconda GitHub action instead of the official setup-python action. Specifically, try out these options for size:&#xA;steps: - uses: conda-incubator/setup-miniconda@v2 with: # Specify python version your environment will have. Remember to quote this, or # YAML will think you want python 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Python (instead of bash) to write GitHub actions</title>
      <link>https://words.yuvi.in/post/python-in-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 23:04:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://words.yuvi.in/post/python-in-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>I am not smart enough to consistently write and debug shell scripts that use any conditional or looping constructs. So as soon as I&amp;rsquo;m writing something in bash that requires use of those, I switch to python. This works fine when writing scripts, but what to do when writing GitHub Actions workflows? You can only write bash in run: stanzas in your steps, right?&#xA;Not at all! You can set the shell parameter to anything you want, and the contents of run will be passed to the shell in the form of a file.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
